<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 Archive on Dunkelheit</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 Archive on Dunkelheit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Steak and Ale Stew</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/steak-and-ale-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/steak-and-ale-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Steak and Ale Stew, also known as Guinness Stew is traditional rustic stew from the British Isles, commonly served with mashed or roast potatoes or as part of a pie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⏲️  Prep time: 30 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🍳 Cooking Time: 2-3 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beef Stew Meat
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any roasting cut will do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beef Broth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ale
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your favourite Ale or Guinness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spices:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bay Leaf, Rosemary, Thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut beef into preferred size of chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut carrots into small chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dice onions and celery into tiny pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add butter to your Dutch oven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once butter is melted add the onions and fry until translucent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more butter if needed and &amp;ldquo;brown&amp;rdquo; your beef.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once beef is browned on all sides add carrots, celery and spices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix everything around and then add your ale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add beef broth until everything is covered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring to the boil, reduce heat to medium and stir and set oven to 160°&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once oven is up to heat place the lid on your Dutch oven and place it in your oven.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check after one hour, then every half hour until desired result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can forgo the use of beef broth and use more ale if you wish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like to add mustard with the onions and beef. Try it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can thicken the stew as desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausagemeat Stuffing</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sausagemeat-stuffing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sausagemeat-stuffing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sausagemeat Stuffing is a traditional Christmas / Yule stuffing tha can cooked inside of your turkey or on the side as it&amp;rsquo;s own dish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⏲️  Prep time: 10-30 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🍳 Cooking Time: 30 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple OR Cranberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Egg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pork Mince OR Pork Sausagemeat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breadcrumbs (Fresh recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spices
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sage, Mixed Spice (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 190°C.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finely chop onion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peel, core and finely chop apple.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, you can grate the Apple.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add breadcrumbs and onion to a mixing bowl and mix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the meat, apple, cranberry and spices to the bowl and mix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a beaten egg and mix further.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the mixture into the freezer for 20 minutes. (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mould into desired shape, loaf or meatballs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cover with foil and roast for 30 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After step 7 you may stuff it into your turkey instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ingredients can be proportioned how you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple or Cranberry can be used you do not need to use both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Notes Management</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/simple-notes-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/simple-notes-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to start organising my notes more thoroughly and introduced a schema to my notes directory (demonstrated below). I found that this made it more likely for me to utilise my notes, which in turn has saved me a lot of time. I tend to use my notes throughout the day so I found myself needing a means to access them quickly. This is when I made a script. Utilising &lt;code&gt;fd&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;fzf&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;xargs&lt;/code&gt; I can now search my notes directory and start taking notes at any given time. It is working really well so far and combined with Neovim I am able to swap between notes files without leaving the comfort of the Neovim editor. If I had to put a number to it I would say that this has saved me at least half an hour a week, which is pretty good for a single line shell command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the schema:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$HOME/Documents/Notes/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 1/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TODO.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 2/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TODO.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 3/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 3.1/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;todo.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjects can be related to a given category of things such as music, food, hobbies, etc or used as a means of categorising further sub-categories of related notes. A lot of these notes files are checklists. I love checklists and while I could use the markdown format of a checklist, that isn&amp;rsquo;t really needed as I tend to delete entries from checklists when they have been met so I don&amp;rsquo;t have a giant list of stuff I no longer need to take note of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These notes can be synced between devices using &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;syncthing&lt;/code&gt; but I have had no need to implement this due to maintaining a paper notebook as my main means of notetaking. Anything important enough to need to access it on the go is already on paper and I take it with me everywhere anyway. I maintain and use a paper notebook for most of my note taking. I transfer my written notes to this system to index them. The way that I take notes in my paper notebooks is different and will maybe get it&amp;rsquo;s own post at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-it-simple-stupid&#34;&gt;Keep It Simple, Stupid!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While talking to a friend about this subject they mentioned that they use software specifically designed for this purpose, which I found odd since notes are just text files. They told me about Obsidian, a graphical markdown text editor that connects notes together with links and has plugin support and all kinds of bloated features that you do not need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a monolithic solution to something as simple as note taking is rather funny to think about. Especially when it offers nothing useful on top of its main feature i.e. being a notebook on your computer. A lot of these software applications have popped up over the years and yet none of them have offered anything unique or useful. I remember my university pushing Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s OneNote as the perfect note taking solution as if a text file or document file wouldn&amp;rsquo;t suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the one argument in favour of these tools that I see repeated most often. That being that they support some form of sync between devices. This is not a unique feature either, syncing files between devices is easily done. Cloud storage exists already for people that don&amp;rsquo;t want a DIY solution, sync tools exist for those that do. Including a file sync that is proprietary to the notes editor is a clear case of inventing problems to sell a solution. It is fundamentally worse in all regards than utilising tools that already exist for this purpose. Monolithic design for the sake of self-justification in a note taking program is insanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest solutions are always the best, which is why I find this whole world of note taking software redundant. Any notes worth taking don&amp;rsquo;t need an entire suite of software to handle. Just write it down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working on a few project recently and thought I would give an update to what they are and how they are coming along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;migrating-from-vim-to-neovim&#34;&gt;Migrating from Vim to Neovim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty self explanatory, Vim has served me well over the years but having to maintain my config in vimscript and trying to manage packages and plugins for it is too much work for what I get out of it. As such I have chosen to move to Neovim and start using it. My progress with this can be tracked on my dotfiles repo if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-platform-dotfile-management&#34;&gt;Cross platform dotfile management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use multiple systems for my computing needs, GNU+Linux for my desktops, servers, ThinkPads and MacOS for my Mac. There are differences between these two that require micro-management and changes when deploying dotfiles as such I have chosen to start modelling a new way of managing my dotfiles. For now this is in the planning stages and will be rolled out as I see fit and implement my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-website-design&#34;&gt;New website design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is my little space on the internet where I scream into the void. It&amp;rsquo;s great being able to post and publish things and share them around and get feedback, etc. One of my favourite parts of being in control of this website is that I can post and publish what I would like. However the issue of organising the content on the site has come to my attention recently. The cookbook section should be it&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;website&amp;rdquo; within the same domain for example. Categories and tags should be more distinct, sorting things by year on the index pages doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me either. As such I plan to make a few design changes to the website over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently these are the changes I plan to make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categorise content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookbook migrated to it&amp;rsquo;s own website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New content types (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimise image usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social&amp;rdquo; links 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-content&#34;&gt;New content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to expand the content that I write on this site to include things I would like to write about but didn&amp;rsquo;t think would suit the site in its current design. Now that I will be changing the design that excuse is no longer valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New content may include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More guides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to reviews, I came to the conclusion that writing about the music I listen to or the video games I play or the books I read could be useful to some people. After all I do seem to be asked quite frequently about what I think about a given product or band, etc. I would also like to review some of the camping gear I have acquired recently as this information is useful in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bots-are-fun&#34;&gt;Bots are fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been developing a bot that I intend to use as a means to bridge various platforms together that I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or patience to manually keep up to date with. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be great, it is a personal project intended to teach me how to interact with APIs and other tool sets. But it is a fun little project so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brewing&#34;&gt;Brewing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making my own wine, beer and cider has been a great hobby so far and I having been gaining a lot more experience with it. Learning the various ways that different ingredients interact, which yeast to use, how long to do things for and why. It is a great hobby and doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of time to do. Although the learning curve can be somewhat of an issue depending on what you plan to do. I plan to write about my experiences with brewing alcohol at some point but for now I just wanted to update that is an ongoing hobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;power-lifting&#34;&gt;Power lifting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have returned to the gym and have taken up a power lifting programming again. I have always enjoyed this sport and intend to last a lot longer at it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about everything. Thanks for reading and if you are interested in anything I have mentioned feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running OpenMW Through Steam</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/running-openmw-through-steam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/running-openmw-through-steam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind is one of the finest video games ever made. It is one of my favourites and as such I like to have it installed on all of my computers. I prefer to play the game using the OpenMW source port but would still like to use Steam features like game time tracking, screenshot sharing and the overlay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow this guide, you should have the Steam version of Morrowind and OpenMW already installed on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your Steam library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right click on &amp;lsquo;The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind&amp;rsquo; in your games list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &amp;lsquo;Properties&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under Launch Options enter the path to OpenMW inside of single quotes followed by &lt;code&gt;-- %command%&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example &lt;code&gt;&#39;/usr/bin/openmw&#39; -- %command%&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your Steam library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right click on &amp;lsquo;The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind&amp;rsquo; in your games list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &amp;lsquo;Properties&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under Launch Options enter the path to OpenMW inside of double quotes followed by &lt;code&gt; %command%&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;C:\Games\OpenMW\openmw.exe %command%&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now launch OpenMW via Steam by clicking Play on your Morrowind entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trick will work for other games too. For example Daggerfall Unity, DOOM and DOOM 2 and your personal favourite source port(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I am aware you can&amp;rsquo;t do this to track game time for Morrowind on a Mac as Steam won&amp;rsquo;t let you launch the game even if you manage to get it to download the game files via a manifest file or console commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Starter</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sourdough bread requires a bit of maintenance unlike notmal white bread. You need to make a starter in advance and maintain it so that you can use it when needed. You can maintain these starters for years, once you have one going you can use it whenever you need. Just be sure not to deplete it or you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plain or bread flour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one teaspoon of sugar to a jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add three heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add enough water to cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix this together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loosely cover the jar with a towel, do not put the lid on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next day it should have a smell to it now and some bubbles, feed it with two heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar and enough water to cover. Mix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the next few days repeat the above feeding process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After five days your starter should be ready for use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now store and use as needed. Remember to feed it before use and to feed it occasionally (every dau is not required at this point) to keep it alive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to experiment with sourdough starters and see what works for you.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The recipe on &lt;a href=&#34;https://based.cooking/sourdough-starter/&#34;&gt;based.cooking&lt;/a&gt; has some good tips and advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure not to feed it with sugar and to only use sugar on the first day.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar is not a necessary step but I find it works for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blog Without Blogging</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this blog it was purely as an exercise in staking my e-claim on my e-land as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=3dIVesHEAzc&#34;&gt;meme at the time&lt;/a&gt; suggested. It was a fun exercise that let me refresh my knowledge of HTML and CSS and it led me to learn Hugo too and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting to this site whenever I feel like something I&amp;rsquo;ve written is worth posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much blogging, in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve done basically none at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to change that. The idea of writing a blog is appealing I&amp;rsquo;ve just never felt like I had anything interesting going on. I blame doing a CompSci degree for this though. Now that I am doing a degree that I actually want to do I have probably too much that I want to write down about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When last semester ended I planned to blog about my experience, what I thought of the various classes, the campus, the environment of the university in general but I never got around to it. So I will cover both semesters at the same time when this one is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact there is a bunch of stuff I would like to start writing about that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to. Such as book reviews, travel logs and personal updates. The idea of &amp;ldquo;building your own platform&amp;rdquo; was supposed to give the opportunity to do these things and I never took advantage of it when I wanted to. I will be doing so more often starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookbook Now Live</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is now live. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a separate RSS feed from the one for blog posts. You may need to adjust your existing RSS link as I made some changes to that on the back end. You can find the most up to date versions of the RSS links at the bottom of this page and on the cookbook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is a bit barren right now but I figured it was better have it public than not at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy cooking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against CDNs</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content Delivery Networks or CDNs for short are a common means for sourcing libraries and frameworks into a web page without having to provide a local copy on the server. It helps cut down on bandwidth and resource usage when serving web content. Which sounds like a great deal for the webmaster. To be fair, it pretty much is a great deal but only for the webmaster and the CDN provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When clients connect to a website and pull JQuery or Bootstrap or some other framework from a CDN instead of the web server serving the page contents they are being tracked. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a very good deal for the user. CDN data can be used to track users around the web without the use of cookies, just by requesting the library from a CDN you are providing an awful lot of metadata without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why it is important to minimize your exposure to sites and services that use these. Of course that means 90% of the web is probably no longer usable. It is important to be smart about it at the least. Should you use social media websites such as Facebook they already know who you are, the frameworks they use are served by them too. Your exposure to request tracking doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter in this scenario since you are already using Facebook. Which you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use if you value your privacy. Although it is possible to use Facebook without exposing your web usage to them, that is for another post, another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s say for example you like to read web blogs like mine. Hopefully they serve those frameworks, etc from their own server. You should check to be sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is served entirely in static HTML and CSS documents so there is no frameworks being loaded at all. However I encourage that you check right now anyway. After all I could be lying (I&amp;rsquo;m not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find that a blog you enjoy reading is using CDNs to serve frameworks, libraries, etc to your browser consider asking the admin to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun Is Trad</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has come to my attention that e-trads have been crusading against fun. Interestingly they do so on the Internet, which is a curious choice of battleground for such a subject. I have absolutely no idea why they are doing this or what they think they will achieve. The most confusing detail of this trend is that having fun is in fact trad so what&amp;rsquo;s with the intentional friendly fire?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days people either treat fun as a part of everyday life (which it is), as an excuse to waste their time (addiction cope) or as an evil to be conquered (the cringe take). It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly strange to see the latter take from people that call themselves &amp;rsquo;traditionalists&amp;rsquo; as these are the very same people that strive to return to some kind of societal normality. In normal societies people had fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History is full of examples of people having fun, be it feasting with friends and neighbors or dancing around a fire or in a ballroom. One could argue that these traditional forms of fun don&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore, they would be wrong of course. Quite commonly you will find if you try hard to look in the first place that there are plenty of opportunities to do these things already and if that somehow yields zero results for you then the problem is that you aren&amp;rsquo;t organising it yourself. However this doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain the aversion to fun that a lot of trads seem to have developed recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem that some of these people have isn&amp;rsquo;t people having fun, it&amp;rsquo;s the ways that people have fun. Particularly the habit forming excesses of it that lead to a loss of enjoyment but an addictive desire that compels participation when any joy to be found is already dead. So is the issue that fun is bad or that having fun is no longer fun? I&amp;rsquo;d wager it&amp;rsquo;s the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of habit forming fun is video games, they are formulaic in design, particularly to extract as much of your time as possible. Where is the fun to be found when these video games become a part time (or even a full time) job? If you have to commit yourself to something that used to be possible to just pick up and play you will find yourself drained of enjoyment very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major problem with people playing video games is excess. People play them way too much, they revolve their lives around them until they stop being fun and become a chore. They play these video games alone in their bedroom for hours or even days at a time in some cases and what do they get out of it? An ever decreasing dopamine rush when the shiny and sparkly effects flare off when you do the same chore (and that is what a lot of video game content is these days) for the thousandth time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with having some fun on your own of course, I find myself enjoying a book quite often. Books are trad right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just video games that masquerade as fun whilst in actual fact being nothing more than addictive distraction. Television, YouTube, TikTok, etc all fulfill this role as well. Since consumption of these is entirely passive the victims of addiction don&amp;rsquo;t even need to think about anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s make a distinction between fun and distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is when you enjoy yourself. A distraction is when you occupy your time. To quote anti-gambling PSAs &amp;ldquo;when the fun stops STOP!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t owe distractions any of your time, that time belong to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally when someone had free time they spent it with other people, or learning a new skill, reading a book or just getting in some extra rest. Fun was enjoyable in the moment and benefited you in some way as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is an ancient and primordial experience that has been twisted and turned into a control mechanism, you can reject it any time you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t have fun playing video games, or watching YouTube, etc but you have to be aware that they are built on algorithms and design standards to keep you engaged with them and not with something else. Time is money and they are draining you of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a bare minimum if you want to have fun find a hobby. Dedicate time to it every week, if after a while you don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it then find a new one. Repeat this until you are having fun. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for the trap of wasting time to pass time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your grandfathers went to the pub, the tavern and the mead hall on Thunorsday. You sit on a couch. Who do you think had more fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn&amp;rsquo;t fun, the problem is a lack of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain Name Change Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided against the use of the &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; TLD for the site and will be returning to tradition and using the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reasoning for choosing the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD over &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; is twofold. The &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD more accurately represents the end of the internet theme and it is much cheaper which fits with the minimalist theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The update will occur at some point in the coming days. The current domain will continue to work until it expires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS feeds should continue to work on the old domain once the domain change occurs. Once the old domain expires however it will no longer update. Please update your RSS feeds to reflect the new domain. The new feed can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/index.xml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email will change to the new domain at some point in the future too. I will make sure to update the site when this occurs. For now assume that the &lt;code&gt;w@dunkelheit.biz&lt;/code&gt; address is no longer functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please update your RSS, email contacts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
