<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 Archive on Dunkelheit</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 Archive on Dunkelheit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working on a few project recently and thought I would give an update to what they are and how they are coming along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;migrating-from-vim-to-neovim&#34;&gt;Migrating from Vim to Neovim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty self explanatory, Vim has served me well over the years but having to maintain my config in vimscript and trying to manage packages and plugins for it is too much work for what I get out of it. As such I have chosen to move to Neovim and start using it. My progress with this can be tracked on my dotfiles repo if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-platform-dotfile-management&#34;&gt;Cross platform dotfile management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use multiple systems for my computing needs, GNU+Linux for my desktops, servers, ThinkPads and MacOS for my Mac. There are differences between these two that require micro-management and changes when deploying dotfiles as such I have chosen to start modelling a new way of managing my dotfiles. For now this is in the planning stages and will be rolled out as I see fit and implement my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-website-design&#34;&gt;New website design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is my little space on the internet where I scream into the void. It&amp;rsquo;s great being able to post and publish things and share them around and get feedback, etc. One of my favourite parts of being in control of this website is that I can post and publish what I would like. However the issue of organising the content on the site has come to my attention recently. The cookbook section should be it&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;website&amp;rdquo; within the same domain for example. Categories and tags should be more distinct, sorting things by year on the index pages doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me either. As such I plan to make a few design changes to the website over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently these are the changes I plan to make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categorise content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookbook migrated to it&amp;rsquo;s own website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New content types (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimise image usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social&amp;rdquo; links 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-content&#34;&gt;New content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to expand the content that I write on this site to include things I would like to write about but didn&amp;rsquo;t think would suit the site in its current design. Now that I will be changing the design that excuse is no longer valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New content may include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More guides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to reviews, I came to the conclusion that writing about the music I listen to or the video games I play or the books I read could be useful to some people. After all I do seem to be asked quite frequently about what I think about a given product or band, etc. I would also like to review some of the camping gear I have acquired recently as this information is useful in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bots-are-fun&#34;&gt;Bots are fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been developing a bot that I intend to use as a means to bridge various platforms together that I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or patience to manually keep up to date with. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be great, it is a personal project intended to teach me how to interact with APIs and other tool sets. But it is a fun little project so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brewing&#34;&gt;Brewing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making my own wine, beer and cider has been a great hobby so far and I having been gaining a lot more experience with it. Learning the various ways that different ingredients interact, which yeast to use, how long to do things for and why. It is a great hobby and doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of time to do. Although the learning curve can be somewhat of an issue depending on what you plan to do. I plan to write about my experiences with brewing alcohol at some point but for now I just wanted to update that is an ongoing hobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;power-lifting&#34;&gt;Power lifting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have returned to the gym and have taken up a power lifting programming again. I have always enjoyed this sport and intend to last a lot longer at it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about everything. Thanks for reading and if you are interested in anything I have mentioned feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Update June 2023</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/site-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/site-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last updated the site so here&amp;rsquo;s a rundown on what&amp;rsquo;s new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-content&#34;&gt;New Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/about&#34;&gt;about me&lt;/a&gt; page has been updated with some hobby info for those interested. I will likely be completely redoing this page over the coming weeks as I find time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New &lt;code&gt;#tags&lt;/code&gt; in the CSS that may hint at future posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various new posts and minor changes to older ones. Out of date / scope posts have been removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;housekeeping&#34;&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some backend changes have been made to make maintenance of the site easier. Nothing complex or noteworthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;known-issues&#34;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None to report! :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Still Like Video Games</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-still-like-video-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-still-like-video-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have previously written about how video games aren&amp;rsquo;t fun any more. This is a bit of a follow up based on some recent thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been playing some video games on Linux via Steam&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Proton&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;gamescope&lt;/code&gt; tools and was amazed that somehow this made Windows games that are notorious for instability incredibly more stable. It has been fun to play Fallout: New Vegas again (unmodded) and it just works™️!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been fun to just play this game again, it is one of my favourites and playing it again after so long has been a nostalgia trip I was in need of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to my point, I still like video games! In particular I still like the video games I used to like. The various issues of modern gaming are still prolific and getting worse but my favourite games are from before this time. I can just run them, play them and enjoy myself without having to avoid, circumvent, grind out, etc the various chores and time/money gates found in almost all modern games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is fun to have fun and I have found myself having fun with video games again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running OpenMW Through Steam</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/running-openmw-through-steam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 12:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/running-openmw-through-steam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind is one of the finest video games ever made. It is one of my favourites and as such I like to have it installed on all of my computers. I prefer to play the game using the OpenMW source port but would still like to use Steam features like game time tracking, screenshot sharing and the overlay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow this guide, you should have the Steam version of Morrowind and OpenMW already installed on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your Steam library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right click on &amp;lsquo;The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind&amp;rsquo; in your games list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &amp;lsquo;Properties&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under Launch Options enter the path to OpenMW inside of single quotes followed by &lt;code&gt;-- %command%&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example &lt;code&gt;&#39;/usr/bin/openmw&#39; -- %command%&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your Steam library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right click on &amp;lsquo;The Elder Scrolls III: Morrowind&amp;rsquo; in your games list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click on &amp;lsquo;Properties&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under Launch Options enter the path to OpenMW inside of double quotes followed by &lt;code&gt; %command%&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;C:\Games\OpenMW\openmw.exe %command%&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now launch OpenMW via Steam by clicking Play on your Morrowind entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trick will work for other games too. For example DOOM and DOOM 2 and your personal favourite source port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I am aware you can&amp;rsquo;t do this to track game time for Morrowind on a Mac as Steam won&amp;rsquo;t let you launch the game even if you manage to get it to download the game files via a manifest file or console commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Still Sucks</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/twitter-still-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/twitter-still-sucks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently made a new Twitter account to follow some accounts while my usual manner of reading them via RSS feeds (thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://nitter.net&#34;&gt;Nitter&lt;/a&gt;) were unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprising no one, the website still sucks and has all the problems that it had before except now you can pay for a dunce cap on your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a waste of time that was!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Starter</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sourdough bread requires a bit of maintenance unlike notmal white bread. You need to make a starter in advance and maintain it so that you can use it when needed. You can maintain these starters for years, once you have one going you can use it whenever you need. Just be sure not to deplete it or you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plain or bread flour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one teaspoon of sugar to a jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add three heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add enough water to cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix this together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loosely cover the jar with a towel, do not put the lid on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next day it should have a smell to it now and some bubbles, feed it with two heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar and enough water to cover. Mix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the next few days repeat the above feeding process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After five days your starter should be ready for use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now store and use as needed. Remember to feed it before use and to feed it occasionally (every dau is not required at this point) to keep it alive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to experiment with sourdough starters and see what works for you.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The recipe on &lt;a href=&#34;https://based.cooking/sourdough-starter/&#34;&gt;based.cooking&lt;/a&gt; has some good tips and advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure not to feed it with sugar and to only use sugar on the first day.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar is not a necessary step but I find it works for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blog Without Blogging</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this blog it was purely as an exercise in staking my e-claim on my e-land as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=3dIVesHEAzc&#34;&gt;meme at the time&lt;/a&gt; suggested. It was a fun exercise that let me refresh my knowledge of HTML and CSS and it led me to learn Hugo too and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting to this site whenever I feel like something I&amp;rsquo;ve written is worth posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much blogging, in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve done basically none at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to change that. The idea of writing a blog is appealing I&amp;rsquo;ve just never felt like I had anything interesting going on. I blame doing a CompSci degree for this though. Now that I am doing a degree that I actually want to do I have probably too much that I want to write down about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When last semester ended I planned to blog about my experience, what I thought of the various classes, the campus, the environment of the university in general but I never got around to it. So I will cover both semesters at the same time when this one is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact there is a bunch of stuff I would like to start writing about that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to. Such as book reviews, travel logs and personal updates. The idea of &amp;ldquo;building your own platform&amp;rdquo; was supposed to give the opportunity to do these things and I never took advantage of it when I wanted to. I will be doing so more often starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookbook Now Live</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is now live. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a separate RSS feed from the one for blog posts. You may need to adjust your existing RSS link as I made some changes to that on the back end. You can find the most up to date versions of the RSS links at the bottom of this page and on the cookbook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is a bit barren right now but I figured it was better have it public than not at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy cooking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Day Carry and Equipment</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get asked for recommendations often regarding technology, clothing, boots, watches, etc and while these are topics I could talk about for hours on end, I simply don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to do so sometimes. As such I thought it would be useful to create an easy to navigate index of what I have, use and recommend that I can share with those interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; this list is likely incomplete and poorly formatted. It will get better over time (hopefully) unless I forget (perhaps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;Equipment:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my currently equipped items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;luggage&#34;&gt;Luggage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backpack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mil-Tec Molle Tactical Assault Pack
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A high quality reproduction / knock-off of some military design backpack. It is waterproof enough for my needs and can carry a significant amount of cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The listings for these online will say it is 20l or 25l I&amp;rsquo;m not sure which is accurate or if some are only listing the main compartment. Regardless this bag is excellent for my needs. I bought a second one for this reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid £35 for each of them, I would recommend them at this price. However if you can get something with equal features without a tactical / military look to it that may be the more practical option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gym Bag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adidas Essentials Linear Duffel Bag Medium
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This 40 liter duffel bag is huge, it can hold all of my gym equipment and then some and it weighs basically nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about its durability but I have had no issues with it so far. It has held up better than more expensive bags I have used in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid £15 for it. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it at this price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;computers&#34;&gt;Computers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listed in order of most frequent use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macbook Air M1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First generation base model Macbook Air running Apple silicon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideal University computer due to battery life and compatibility with required software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See my current and recommend &lt;a href=&#34;#peripherals&#34;&gt;accessories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom Desktop PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specs:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R5 2600 CPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RX 580&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32GB DDR4 RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artix Linux System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming capable, not that I really bother these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThinkPad T440p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Linux computer. Fairly well upgraded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For when I need penguin mode on the go. Which I haven&amp;rsquo;t recently hence it&amp;rsquo;s location on the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThinkPad X230&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup for the T440p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;portable-electronics&#34;&gt;Portable Electronics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headphones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sennheiser HD450SE Wireless Headphones
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect headphones for traveling. Not too powerful, they don&amp;rsquo;t need to be. Comfortable enough, may need slackened (at your own risk) depending on your head shape / size. I paid £70 for them. I would recommend them at this price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile Phone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Pixel 7
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charcoal Black model of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;peripherals&#34;&gt;Peripherals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macbook Dock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABIWAZY USB C Docking Station
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic Thunderbolt docking station for laptops that support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can convert my Macbook to a desktop at home, small enough to travel with in case I need an Ethernet connection or HDMI output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can likely find a similar or better solution for the price. I paid £52 and don&amp;rsquo;t regret the purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB-A to USB-C Adapters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Google Pixel OEM USB-C adapters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use these for the Google Pixel, they work in the Macbook but are a bit bulky for it in my use case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Syntech USB-A to USB-C adapters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleeker and less bulky option for use with the Macbook, can&amp;rsquo;t use both at the same time due to size. I carry two anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Storage
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crucial 500GB MX500 SATA SSD
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With USB enclosure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;stationary&#34;&gt;Stationary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A4 Refill Pad
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-explanatory. I need to take notes and do classwork. These are cheap and seemingly infinitely available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Colour Pens
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pen enclosure with 4 different coloured pens inside. Incredibly useful for language study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides red (corrections), black (writing), blue (translation) and green (inline note taking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic branded Post-Its
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For page marking and note taking in my textbooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am aware that these deteriorate books over time, I am looking for a better alternative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clothing&#34;&gt;Clothing:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon! / In Progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;footwear&#34;&gt;Footwear&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austrian Fallschrimjager Boots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfectly comfortable, keeps my feet warm and dry, slip on and off no issue when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dutch Army Surplus Wool Socks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incredible fit and feel. 80:20 blend woolen socks. Perfect for boots and high top trainers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converse Chuck Taylor All Star Hi Top&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect flat shoe for the gym.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheap, durable, flat, available in large sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;watch&#34;&gt;Watch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casio G-Shock GA-110
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indestructible digital timepiece.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against CDNs</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content Delivery Networks or CDNs for short are a common means for sourcing libraries and frameworks into a web page without having to provide a local copy on the server. It helps cut down on bandwidth and resource usage when serving web content. Which sounds like a great deal for the webmaster. To be fair, it pretty much is a great deal but only for the webmaster and the CDN provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When clients connect to a website and pull JQuery or Bootstrap or some other framework from a CDN instead of the web server serving the page contents they are being tracked. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a very good deal for the user. CDN data can be used to track users around the web without the use of cookies, just by requesting the library from a CDN you are providing an awful lot of metadata without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why it is important to minimize your exposure to sites and services that use these. Of course that means 90% of the web is probably no longer usable. It is important to be smart about it at the least. Should you use social media websites such as Facebook they already know who you are, the frameworks they use are served by them too. Your exposure to request tracking doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter in this scenario since you are already using Facebook. Which you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use if you value your privacy. Although it is possible to use Facebook without exposing your web usage to them, that is for another post, another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s say for example you like to read web blogs like mine. Hopefully they serve those frameworks, etc from their own server. You should check to be sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is served entirely in static HTML and CSS documents so there is no frameworks being loaded at all. However I encourage that you check right now anyway. After all I could be lying (I&amp;rsquo;m not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find that a blog you enjoy reading is using CDNs to serve frameworks, libraries, etc to your browser consider asking the admin to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun Is Trad</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has come to my attention that e-trads have been crusading against fun. Interestingly they do so on the Internet, which is a curious choice of battleground for such a subject. I have absolutely no idea why they are doing this or what they think they will achieve. The most confusing detail of this trend is that having fun is in fact trad so what&amp;rsquo;s with the intentional friendly fire?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days people either treat fun as a part of everyday life (which it is), as an excuse to waste their time (addiction cope) or as an evil to be conquered (the cringe take). It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly strange to see the latter take from people that call themselves &amp;rsquo;traditionalists&amp;rsquo; as these are the very same people that strive to return to some kind of societal normality. In normal societies people had fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History is full of examples of people having fun, be it feasting with friends and neighbors or dancing around a fire or in a ballroom. One could argue that these traditional forms of fun don&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore, they would be wrong of course. Quite commonly you will find if you try hard to look in the first place that there are plenty of opportunities to do these things already and if that somehow yields zero results for you then the problem is that you aren&amp;rsquo;t organising it yourself. However this doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain the aversion to fun that a lot of trads seem to have developed recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem that some of these people have isn&amp;rsquo;t people having fun, it&amp;rsquo;s the ways that people have fun. Particularly the habit forming excesses of it that lead to a loss of enjoyment but an addictive desire that compels participation when any joy to be found is already dead. So is the issue that fun is bad or that having fun is no longer fun? I&amp;rsquo;d wager it&amp;rsquo;s the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of habit forming fun is video games, they are formulaic in design, particularly to extract as much of your time as possible. Where is the fun to be found when these video games become a part time (or even a full time) job? If you have to commit yourself to something that used to be possible to just pick up and play you will find yourself drained of enjoyment very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major problem with people playing video games is excess. People play them way too much, they revolve their lives around them until they stop being fun and become a chore. They play these video games alone in their bedroom for hours or even days at a time in some cases and what do they get out of it? An ever decreasing dopamine rush when the shiny and sparkly effects flare off when you do the same chore (and that is what a lot of video game content is these days) for the thousandth time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with having some fun on your own of course, I find myself enjoying a book quite often. Books are trad right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just video games that masquerade as fun whilst in actual fact being nothing more than addictive distraction. Television, YouTube, TikTok, etc all fulfill this role as well. Since consumption of these is entirely passive the victims of addiction don&amp;rsquo;t even need to think about anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s make a distinction between fun and distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is when you enjoy yourself. A distraction is when you occupy your time. To quote anti-gambling PSAs &amp;ldquo;when the fun stops STOP!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t owe distractions any of your time, that time belong to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally when someone had free time they spent it with other people, or learning a new skill, reading a book or just getting in some extra rest. Fun was enjoyable in the moment and benefited you in some way as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is an ancient and primordial experience that has been twisted and turned into a control mechanism, you can reject it any time you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t have fun playing video games, or watching YouTube, etc but you have to be aware that they are built on algorithms and design standards to keep you engaged with them and not with something else. Time is money and they are draining you of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a bare minimum if you want to have fun find a hobby. Dedicate time to it every week, if after a while you don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it then find a new one. Repeat this until you are having fun. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for the trap of wasting time to pass time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your grandfathers went to the pub, the tavern and the mead hall on Thunorsday. You sit on a couch. Who do you think had more fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn&amp;rsquo;t fun, the problem is a lack of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain Name Change Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided against the use of the &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; TLD for the site and will be returning to tradition and using the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reasoning for choosing the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD over &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; is twofold. The &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD more accurately represents the end of the internet theme and it is much cheaper which fits with the minimalist theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The update will occur at some point in the coming days. The current domain will continue to work until it expires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS feeds should continue to work on the old domain once the domain change occurs. Once the old domain expires however it will no longer update. Please update your RSS feeds to reflect the new domain. The new feed can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/index.xml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email will change to the new domain at some point in the future too. I will make sure to update the site when this occurs. For now assume that the &lt;code&gt;w@dunkelheit.biz&lt;/code&gt; address is no longer functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please update your RSS, email contacts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/library-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/library-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to cataloging (some of) my personal library and have made a page dedicated to the books of my library for those interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to use this as a means of keeping track of what books I have, which of them I have read and whether there is any content I have relating to it. As well as keeping a list I can access when out and about in case I need a reminder of which books I own. It is also a useful way to share my library with friends that may wish to borrow something from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on a system of sorting the page yet. I checked &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/library&#34;&gt;Luke Smith&amp;rsquo;s library&lt;/a&gt; page and saw that he uses the Library of Congress system. Which doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem appropriate for my uses. For now I have opted for categorising books based on which genre I believe is most appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the question of whether to include the likes of manga or mass market paperback fiction titles as these aren&amp;rsquo;t as meaningful as other texts although most of the ones I find myself owning are of a higher quality than one would find on the best sellers list or the advertising shelves at a chain book shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason not to include manga is simply that I have no idea how to do include them elegantly. Do I list them by author or illustrator? Many of them have multiple. For now I have settled on including them by name only until I can determine a better way to include them that is more consistent with the rest of the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to check out the library, it can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
