<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 Archive on Dunkelheit Citizen</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 Archive on Dunkelheit Citizen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Hunt Challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/wild-hunt-challenge-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/wild-hunt-challenge-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Golden One issued his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e53MzSk3Jlc&#34;&gt;Wild Hunt challenge for 2023&lt;/a&gt; a while back and I intend to take part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge(s) for this year (like all years) are to make positive changes in your life by getting more organised, being more well read and improving your health. Of course the Glorious Lion&amp;rsquo;s challenge includes going to the gym. I will go over each challenge, my thoughts on them and how I intended to approach them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-one---notebook&#34;&gt;Challenge One - Notebook&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the challenge is probably the most important as it will assist with the remainder of the challenges as well as being immensely useful for everyday organisiation in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is simple, get a notebook and use it. Particular instruction on how to use it was given which is pretty straightforward. Write down what you plan to day on each given day and tick them off as you go. You get a feeling of accomplishment as you do this and get to see how you progress, where improvements can be made and you can keep on top of things such that you don&amp;rsquo;t forget anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great start to the challenge, a fairly reasonable introductory step that prepares you for the rest. Not much to say about it other than it being useful for the rest of the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-two---read-a-book&#34;&gt;Challenge Two - Read A Book&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part two of the challenge is to read a book, the recommended text is The Golden One&amp;rsquo;s own book Dauntless: Wild Hunt Edition, which I intend to read for this challenge as I have been meaning to get around to reading it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When presenting this part of the challenge the suggestion of reading a classic is also given and this is used to explain the purpose of the challenge. Reading a book doesn&amp;rsquo;t just teach you what its contents are, it also teaches you the world view of the author, the writing style used, why the book was written and you may even develop an idea as to why someone would want to read the book. A great intellectual exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned I plan to read Dauntless for this challenge. I already own a copy, as an additional challenge I plan to review the book and give my thoughts on it. I will consider this part of the challenge complete when I do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-three---the-temple-of-iron&#34;&gt;Challenge Three - The Temple of Iron&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we have a challenge relating to The Temple of Iron, which if you are unfamiliar is a term that Gigachads use to refer to the gym. In particular the challenge is to adopt a schedule for the gym and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty straightforward, the purpose of this challenge is to instill discipline as well as to get you in the gym and lifting. Which is glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Golden One gives Smolov Jr. as an example of a schedule / routine but I plan to use Starting Strength as it is what I prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-four---meditation&#34;&gt;Challenge Four - Meditation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth part of the challenge is to start meditating, every day. Starting at ten minutes with a guided meditation method. The recommended routine is the Wim Hof routine. I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about it yet but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to take the advice and at least look into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much else to say here, I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about meditation to really comment on it at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-five---fasting&#34;&gt;Challenge Five - Fasting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final challenge is to do a twenty four hour fast. There are many advantages to fasting, from appetite control, developing your discipline, autophagy and weight loss. There are many others but these are the four most common and most directly useful to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is likely to be the easiest part of the challenge for me as I already practice rolling fasting as a means of weight loss. I will say that it is very effective and if there are other benefits (there most certainly is) they will creep their way in. You aren&amp;rsquo;t going to wake up after your first fast to find all the benefits occurred overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend fasting alongside a ketogenic diet. Or at the very least a ketogenic protocol prior to the fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-approach&#34;&gt;My Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is my appraoch or how I intend to approach each challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchases a nice Oxford Touch notebook featuring 90gsm paper. Perfect for writing on both sides of.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is nothing fancy about it really, it&amp;rsquo;s a normal notebook with no thrills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t see much point in getting anything nicer than this for keeping checklists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As mentioned above I will be reading Dauntless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting Strength is a great routine for building strength, I switch between it and StrongLifts every so often.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also add in significant cardio work as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will start off with the recommended Wim Hof routine and see how it goes.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only challenge I see being somewhat of a change of pace / new experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I already have at least a twenty four hour fast every week.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes I throw in a forty eight or seventy two hour fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not consent to calories!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have given a breakdown of the challenge and my thoughts on each part I have a few comments on the overall challenge to make. First and foremost, the combination of these challenges will have obvious benefits to most people. I highly recommend taking part. Additionally you can modify it or add your own challenges if you&amp;rsquo;d like. The idea behind this is to make your New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution more meaningful without calling it a New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution. That&amp;rsquo;s a cringe name, we aren&amp;rsquo;t making &amp;ldquo;resolutions&amp;rdquo; we are COMPETING in the WILD HUNT with our leader THE GLORIOUS LION!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will update this post occasionally with my thoughts on the challenges so far. Glory to those competing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Starter</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sourdough bread requires a bit of maintenance unlike notmal white bread. You need to make a starter in advance and maintain it so that you can use it when needed. You can maintain these starters for years, once you have one going you can use it whenever you need. Just be sure not to deplete it or you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plain or bread flour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one teaspoon of sugar to a jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add three heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add enough water to cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix this together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loosely cover the jar with a towel, do not put the lid on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next day it should have a smell to it now and some bubbles, feed it with two heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar and enough water to cover. Mix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the next few days repeat the above feeding process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After five days your starter should be ready for use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now store and use as needed. Remember to feed it before use and to feed it occasionally (every dau is not required at this point) to keep it alive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to experiment with sourdough starters and see what works for you.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The recipe on &lt;a href=&#34;https://based.cooking/sourdough-starter/&#34;&gt;based.cooking&lt;/a&gt; has some good tips and advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure not to feed it with sugar and to only use sugar on the first day.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar is not a necessary step but I find it works for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blog Without Blogging</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this blog it was purely as an exercise in staking my e-claim on my e-land as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=3dIVesHEAzc&#34;&gt;meme at the time&lt;/a&gt; suggested. It was a fun exercise that let me refresh my knowledge of HTML and CSS and it led me to learn Hugo too and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting to this site whenever I feel like something I&amp;rsquo;ve written is worth posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much blogging, in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve done basically none at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to change that. The idea of writing a blog is appealing I&amp;rsquo;ve just never felt like I had anything interesting going on. I blame doing a CompSci degree for this though. Now that I am doing a degree that I actually want to do I have probably too much that I want to write down about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When last semester ended I planned to blog about my experience, what I thought of the various classes, the campus, the environment of the university in general but I never got around to it. So I will cover both semesters at the same time when this one is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact there is a bunch of stuff I would like to start writing about that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to. Such as book reviews, travel logs and personal updates. The idea of &amp;ldquo;building your own platform&amp;rdquo; was supposed to give the opportunity to do these things and I never took advantage of it when I wanted to. I will be doing so more often starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Update February 2023</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/site-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/site-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last updated the site so here&amp;rsquo;s a rundown on what&amp;rsquo;s new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-content&#34;&gt;New Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is now a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; page where you can see all the books I own. It is an ongoing project and there are a lot of books missing from it that I have yet to catalogue. However if you find anything of interest on it and would like to contact me, please do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now find the long awaited Cookbook project at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; page. It is a long awaited feature I am sure. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit empty at the moment but I will be filling it out from time to time. Read the Cookbook Now Live article linked below to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain name has now changed from &lt;code&gt;dunkelheit.biz&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;dunkelheit.xyz&lt;/code&gt; and the old domain will expire within a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-articles&#34;&gt;New Articles:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad&#34;&gt;Having Fun Is Trad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns&#34;&gt;Against CDNs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/necessary-evils-internet/&#34;&gt;Necessary Evils on the Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/&#34;&gt;Every Day Carry and Equipment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/&#34;&gt;Cookbook Now Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;housekeeping&#34;&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The home page and about me pages have been updated to include more accurate information and restructured a bit to ensure clarity. Please keep in mind that the YouTube and Odysee links are placeholders while I set those up. I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post when it has been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;known-issues&#34;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email is down, I will attempt to fix it at some point when I am less busy. For now you can contact me via twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunkelheitxyz&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Dunkelheitxyz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you are familiar with my content you will know that I am against social media and twitter in particular is my usual go to example of why. Check the Necessary Evils on the Internet article linked above to see some of my more recent thinking on the matter. I am still not convinced it is worth keeping a twitter account long term, for now it is a stopgap fix for a problem I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to find a better solution to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The YouTube and Odysee links don&amp;rsquo;t work. This is on purpose, they are placeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookbook Now Live</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is now live. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a separate RSS feed from the one for blog posts. You may need to adjust your existing RSS link as I made some changes to that on the back end. You can find the most up to date versions of the RSS links at the bottom of this page and on the cookbook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is a bit barren right now but I figured it was better have it public than not at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy cooking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Day Carry and Equipment</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get asked for recommendations often regarding technology, clothing, boots, watches, etc and while these are topics I could talk about for hours on end, I simply don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to do so sometimes. As such I thought it would be useful to create an easy to navigate index of what I have, use and recommend that I can share with those interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; this list is likely incomplete and poorly formatted. It will get better over time (hopefully) unless I forget (perhaps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;Equipment:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my currently equipped items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;luggage&#34;&gt;Luggage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backpack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mil-Tec Molle Tactical Assault Pack
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A high quality reproduction / knock-off of some military design backpack. It is waterproof enough for my needs and can carry a significant amount of cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The listings for these online will say it is 20l or 25l I&amp;rsquo;m not sure which is accurate or if some are only listing the main compartment. Regardless this bag is excellent for my needs. I bought a second one for this reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid £35 for each of them, I would recommend them at this price. However if you can get something with equal features without a tactical / military look to it that may be the more practical option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gym Bag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adidas Essentials Linear Duffel Bag Medium
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This 40 liter duffel bag is huge, it can hold all of my gym equipment and then some and it weighs basically nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about its durability but I have had no issues with it so far. It has held up better than more expensive bags I have used in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid £15 for it. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it at this price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;computers&#34;&gt;Computers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listed in order of most frequent use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macbook Air M1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First generation base model Macbook Air running Apple silicon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideal University computer due to battery life and compatibility with required software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See my current and recommend &lt;a href=&#34;#peripherals&#34;&gt;accessories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom Desktop PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specs:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R5 2600 CPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RX 580&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32GB DDR4 RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artix Linux System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming capable, not that I really bother these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThinkPad T440p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Linux computer. Fairly well upgraded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For when I need penguin mode on the go. Which I haven&amp;rsquo;t recently hence it&amp;rsquo;s location on the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThinkPad X230&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup for the T440p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;portable-electronics&#34;&gt;Portable Electronics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headphones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sennheiser HD450SE Wireless Headphones
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect headphones for traveling. Not too powerful, they don&amp;rsquo;t need to be. Comfortable enough, may need slackened (at your own risk) depending on your head shape / size. I paid £70 for them. I would recommend them at this price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile Phone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Pixel 7
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charcoal Black model of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;peripherals&#34;&gt;Peripherals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macbook Dock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABIWAZY USB C Docking Station
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic Thunderbolt docking station for laptops that support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can convert my Macbook to a desktop at home, small enough to travel with in case I need an Ethernet connection or HDMI output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can likely find a similar or better solution for the price. I paid £52 and don&amp;rsquo;t regret the purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB-A to USB-C Adapters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Google Pixel OEM USB-C adapters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use these for the Google Pixel, they work in the Macbook but are a bit bulky for it in my use case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Syntech USB-A to USB-C adapters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleeker and less bulky option for use with the Macbook, can&amp;rsquo;t use both at the same time due to size. I carry two anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Storage
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crucial 500GB MX500 SATA SSD
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With USB enclosure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;stationary&#34;&gt;Stationary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A4 Refill Pad
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-explanatory. I need to take notes and do classwork. These are cheap and seemingly infinitely available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Colour Pens
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pen enclosure with 4 different coloured pens inside. Incredibly useful for language study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides red (corrections), black (writing), blue (translation) and green (inline note taking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic branded Post-Its
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For page marking and note taking in my textbooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am aware that these deteriorate books over time, I am looking for a better alternative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clothing&#34;&gt;Clothing:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon! / In Progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;footwear&#34;&gt;Footwear&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bundeswehr Fallschrimjager Boots Mk4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finest combat boots ever made. Perfectly comfortable, keeps my feet warm and dry, slip on and off no issue when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resoled with Vibram soles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converse Chuck Taylor All Star Hi Top&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect flat shoe for the gym.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheap, durable, flat, available in large sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;watch&#34;&gt;Watch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casio G-Shock GA-110
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indestructible digital timepiece.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessary Evils on the Internet?</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/necessary-evils-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/necessary-evils-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The modern Internet experience for the average Internet user is a strange thing indeed. The compulsive desire to &amp;ldquo;check notis&amp;rdquo; is truly a technological horror and an expression of addictive behavior. Yet many find it to not only be &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; but completely acceptable. How bizarre!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger and I wanted to talk to my friends online I had to open various chat applications to be able to communicate with them all because everyone had just one application that they were comfortable with (or their parents allowed to be installed on the family computer) and it was normal for people to take days or weeks to reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it seems that is no longer the case, everyone feels some kind of need to be on every platform and expects instantaneous replies regardless of time zones or whether the recipient is awake or busy. It&amp;rsquo;s a very artificial way of interacting with people and it is quite disturbing to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the topic of being &amp;ldquo;on every platform&amp;rdquo;, I have come to resent the fact that I have started to rely on some of these same platforms myself recently. Although I have been doing this so far without accounts on them (shout out to &lt;a href=&#34;https://nitter.net/&#34;&gt;nitter&lt;/a&gt;!). This makes it very time consuming and exhausting to keep up to date with people that use these platforms exclusively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is no realistic solution to this problem when you want to follow more than five or so accounts. Which is why I have recently started to think that it may be a necessary evil to create an account on these platforms for the purpose of following and keeping up to date with certain people, topics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which goes against the spirit of what I am trying to do with this blog: being my own platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it a necessary evil or am I just unaware of a better solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried to use fediverse in the past, and while technologically it is a neat technological solution to problems and some cool people are on there that I would like to keep up to date with it falls into the same category of click-chasing habit forming behavior that twitter, etc all infect their users with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now I haven&amp;rsquo;t made accounts on these platforms however it is something that I am starting to think about. 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to try it out and see for myself if it is worth the hassle. You can follow me &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunkelheitxyz&#34;&gt;@Dunkelheitxyz&lt;/a&gt; if you want to. As I mentioned above I intend to just use it to keep up to date with some accounts that don&amp;rsquo;t have or use alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update-2&#34;&gt;Update 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not impressed with the twitter experience at all. It seems like it has gotten worse over the years. Which would surprise me if I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect this. The issues I pointed out in past posts about the issues being what twitter is as well as how they do it are still present. Ultimately it is designed to suck your time away and keep you engaged in meaningless nonsense. I will keep the account active for a while longer but I likely won&amp;rsquo;t log in to it. Really I just can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to use it at all, even to delete it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against CDNs</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content Delivery Networks or CDNs for short are a common means for sourcing libraries and frameworks into a web page without having to provide a local copy on the server. It helps cut down on bandwidth and resource usage when serving web content. Which sounds like a great deal for the webmaster. To be fair, it pretty much is a great deal but only for the webmaster and the CDN provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When clients connect to a website and pull JQuery or Bootstrap or some other framework from a CDN instead of the web server serving the page contents they are being tracked. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a very good deal for the user. CDN data can be used to track users around the web without the use of cookies, just by requesting the library from a CDN you are providing an awful lot of metadata without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why it is important to minimize your exposure to sites and services that use these. Of course that means 90% of the web is probably no longer usable. It is important to be smart about it at the least. Should you use social media websites such as Facebook they already know who you are, the frameworks they use are served by them too. Your exposure to request tracking doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter in this scenario since you are already using Facebook. Which you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use if you value your privacy. Although it is possible to use Facebook without exposing your web usage to them, that is for another post, another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s say for example you like to read web blogs like mine. Hopefully they serve those frameworks, etc from their own server. You should check to be sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is served entirely in static HTML and CSS documents so there is no frameworks being loaded at all. However I encourage that you check right now anyway. After all I could be lying (I&amp;rsquo;m not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find that a blog you enjoy reading is using CDNs to serve frameworks, libraries, etc to your browser consider asking the admin to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun Is Trad</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has come to my attention that e-trads have been crusading against fun. Interestingly they do so on the Internet, which is a curious choice of battleground for such a subject. I have absolutely no idea why they are doing this or what they think they will achieve. The most confusing detail of this trend is that having fun is in fact trad so what&amp;rsquo;s with the intentional friendly fire?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days people either treat fun as a part of everyday life (which it is), as an excuse to waste their time (addiction cope) or as an evil to be conquered (the cringe take). It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly strange to see the latter take from people that call themselves &amp;rsquo;traditionalists&amp;rsquo; as these are the very same people that strive to return to some kind of societal normality. In normal societies people had fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History is full of examples of people having fun, be it feasting with friends and neighbors or dancing around a fire or in a ballroom. One could argue that these traditional forms of fun don&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore, they would be wrong of course. Quite commonly you will find if you try hard to look in the first place that there are plenty of opportunities to do these things already and if that somehow yields zero results for you then the problem is that you aren&amp;rsquo;t organising it yourself. However this doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain the aversion to fun that a lot of trads seem to have developed recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem that some of these people have isn&amp;rsquo;t people having fun, it&amp;rsquo;s the ways that people have fun. Particularly the habit forming excesses of it that lead to a loss of enjoyment but an addictive desire that compels participation when any joy to be found is already dead. So is the issue that fun is bad or that having fun is no longer fun? I&amp;rsquo;d wager it&amp;rsquo;s the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of habit forming fun is video games, they are formulaic in design, particularly to extract as much of your time as possible. Where is the fun to be found when these video games become a part time (or even a full time) job? If you have to commit yourself to something that used to be possible to just pick up and play you will find yourself drained of enjoyment very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major problem with people playing video games is excess. People play them way too much, they revolve their lives around them until they stop being fun and become a chore. They play these video games alone in their bedroom for hours or even days at a time in some cases and what do they get out of it? An ever decreasing dopamine rush when the shiny and sparkly effects flare off when you do the same chore (and that is what a lot of video game content is these days) for the thousandth time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with having some fun on your own of course, I find myself enjoying a book quite often. Books are trad right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just video games that masquerade as fun whilst in actual fact being nothing more than addictive distraction. Television, YouTube, TikTok, etc all fulfill this role as well. Since consumption of these is entirely passive the victims of addiction don&amp;rsquo;t even need to think about anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s make a distinction between fun and distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is when you enjoy yourself. A distraction is when you occupy your time. To quote anti-gambling PSAs &amp;ldquo;when the fun stops STOP!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t owe distractions any of your time, that time belong to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally when someone had free time they spent it with other people, or learning a new skill, reading a book or just getting in some extra rest. Fun was enjoyable in the moment and benefited you in some way as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is an ancient and primordial experience that has been twisted and turned into a control mechanism, you can reject it any time you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t have fun playing video games, or watching YouTube, etc but you have to be aware that they are built on algorithms and design standards to keep you engaged with them and not with something else. Time is money and they are draining you of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a bare minimum if you want to have fun find a hobby. Dedicate time to it every week, if after a while you don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it then find a new one. Repeat this until you are having fun. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for the trap of wasting time to pass time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your grandfathers went to the pub, the tavern and the mead hall on Thunorsday. You sit on a couch. Who do you think had more fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn&amp;rsquo;t fun, the problem is a lack of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain Name Change Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided against the use of the &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; TLD for the site and will be returning to tradition and using the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reasoning for choosing the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD over &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; is twofold. The &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD more accurately represents the end of the internet theme and it is much cheaper which fits with the minimalist theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The update will occur at some point in the coming days. The current domain will continue to work until it expires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS feeds should continue to work on the old domain once the domain change occurs. Once the old domain expires however it will no longer update. Please update your RSS feeds to reflect the new domain. The new feed can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/index.xml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email will change to the new domain at some point in the future too. I will make sure to update the site when this occurs. For now assume that the &lt;code&gt;w@dunkelheit.biz&lt;/code&gt; address is no longer functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please update your RSS, email contacts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/library-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/library-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to cataloging (some of) my personal library and have made a page dedicated to the books of my library for those interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to use this as a means of keeping track of what books I have, which of them I have read and whether there is any content I have relating to it. As well as keeping a list I can access when out and about in case I need a reminder of which books I own. It is also a useful way to share my library with friends that may wish to borrow something from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on a system of sorting the page yet. I checked &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/library&#34;&gt;Luke Smith&amp;rsquo;s library&lt;/a&gt; page and saw that he uses the Library of Congress system. Which doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem appropriate for my uses. For now I have opted for categorising books based on which genre I believe is most appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the question of whether to include the likes of manga or mass market paperback fiction titles as these aren&amp;rsquo;t as meaningful as other texts although most of the ones I find myself owning are of a higher quality than one would find on the best sellers list or the advertising shelves at a chain book shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason not to include manga is simply that I have no idea how to do include them elegantly. Do I list them by author or illustrator? Many of them have multiple. For now I have settled on including them by name only until I can determine a better way to include them that is more consistent with the rest of the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to check out the library, it can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
