<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dunkelheit Citizen</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dunkelheit Citizen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Hunt Challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/wild-hunt-challenge-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/wild-hunt-challenge-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Golden One issued his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e53MzSk3Jlc&#34;&gt;Wild Hunt challenge for 2023&lt;/a&gt; a while back and I intend to take part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge(s) for this year (like all years) are to make positive changes in your life by getting more organised, being more well read and improving your health. Of course the Glorious Lion&amp;rsquo;s challenge includes going to the gym. I will go over each challenge, my thoughts on them and how I intended to approach them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-one---notebook&#34;&gt;Challenge One - Notebook&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the challenge is probably the most important as it will assist with the remainder of the challenges as well as being immensely useful for everyday organisiation in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is simple, get a notebook and use it. Particular instruction on how to use it was given which is pretty straightforward. Write down what you plan to day on each given day and tick them off as you go. You get a feeling of accomplishment as you do this and get to see how you progress, where improvements can be made and you can keep on top of things such that you don&amp;rsquo;t forget anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great start to the challenge, a fairly reasonable introductory step that prepares you for the rest. Not much to say about it other than it being useful for the rest of the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-two---read-a-book&#34;&gt;Challenge Two - Read A Book&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part two of the challenge is to read a book, the recommended text is The Golden One&amp;rsquo;s own book Dauntless: Wild Hunt Edition, which I intend to read for this challenge as I have been meaning to get around to reading it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When presenting this part of the challenge the suggestion of reading a classic is also given and this is used to explain the purpose of the challenge. Reading a book doesn&amp;rsquo;t just teach you what its contents are, it also teaches you the world view of the author, the writing style used, why the book was written and you may even develop an idea as to why someone would want to read the book. A great intellectual exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned I plan to read Dauntless for this challenge. I already own a copy, as an additional challenge I plan to review the book and give my thoughts on it. I will consider this part of the challenge complete when I do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-three---the-temple-of-iron&#34;&gt;Challenge Three - The Temple of Iron&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we have a challenge relating to The Temple of Iron, which if you are unfamiliar is a term that Gigachads use to refer to the gym. In particular the challenge is to adopt a schedule for the gym and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty straightforward, the purpose of this challenge is to instill discipline as well as to get you in the gym and lifting. Which is glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Golden One gives Smolov Jr. as an example of a schedule / routine but I plan to use Starting Strength as it is what I prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-four---meditation&#34;&gt;Challenge Four - Meditation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth part of the challenge is to start meditating, every day. Starting at ten minutes with a guided meditation method. The recommended routine is the Wim Hof routine. I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about it yet but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to take the advice and at least look into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much else to say here, I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about meditation to really comment on it at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-five---fasting&#34;&gt;Challenge Five - Fasting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final challenge is to do a twenty four hour fast. There are many advantages to fasting, from appetite control, developing your discipline, autophagy and weight loss. There are many others but these are the four most common and most directly useful to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is likely to be the easiest part of the challenge for me as I already practice rolling fasting as a means of weight loss. I will say that it is very effective and if there are other benefits (there most certainly is) they will creep their way in. You aren&amp;rsquo;t going to wake up after your first fast to find all the benefits occurred overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend fasting alongside a ketogenic diet. Or at the very least a ketogenic protocol prior to the fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-approach&#34;&gt;My Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is my appraoch or how I intend to approach each challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchases a nice Oxford Touch notebook featuring 90gsm paper. Perfect for writing on both sides of.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is nothing fancy about it really, it&amp;rsquo;s a normal notebook with no thrills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t see much point in getting anything nicer than this for keeping checklists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As mentioned above I will be reading Dauntless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting Strength is a great routine for building strength, I switch between it and StrongLifts every so often.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also add in significant cardio work as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will start off with the recommended Wim Hof routine and see how it goes.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only challenge I see being somewhat of a change of pace / new experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I already have at least a twenty four hour fast every week.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes I throw in a forty eight or seventy two hour fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not consent to calories!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have given a breakdown of the challenge and my thoughts on each part I have a few comments on the overall challenge to make. First and foremost, the combination of these challenges will have obvious benefits to most people. I highly recommend taking part. Additionally you can modify it or add your own challenges if you&amp;rsquo;d like. The idea behind this is to make your New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution more meaningful without calling it a New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution. That&amp;rsquo;s a cringe name, we aren&amp;rsquo;t making &amp;ldquo;resolutions&amp;rdquo; we are COMPETING in the WILD HUNT with our leader THE GLORIOUS LION!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will update this post occasionally with my thoughts on the challenges so far. Glory to those competing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Starter</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/sourdough-starter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sourdough bread requires a bit of maintenance unlike notmal white bread. You need to make a starter in advance and maintain it so that you can use it when needed. You can maintain these starters for years, once you have one going you can use it whenever you need. Just be sure not to deplete it or you&amp;rsquo;ll have to start again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plain or bread flour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one teaspoon of sugar to a jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add three heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add enough water to cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix this together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loosely cover the jar with a towel, do not put the lid on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The next day it should have a smell to it now and some bubbles, feed it with two heaped tablespoons of flour to the jar and enough water to cover. Mix it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the next few days repeat the above feeding process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After five days your starter should be ready for use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now store and use as needed. Remember to feed it before use and to feed it occasionally (every dau is not required at this point) to keep it alive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to experiment with sourdough starters and see what works for you.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The recipe on &lt;a href=&#34;https://based.cooking/sourdough-starter/&#34;&gt;based.cooking&lt;/a&gt; has some good tips and advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure not to feed it with sugar and to only use sugar on the first day.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar is not a necessary step but I find it works for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blog Without Blogging</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this blog it was purely as an exercise in staking my e-claim on my e-land as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=3dIVesHEAzc&#34;&gt;meme at the time&lt;/a&gt; suggested. It was a fun exercise that let me refresh my knowledge of HTML and CSS and it led me to learn Hugo too and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting to this site whenever I feel like something I&amp;rsquo;ve written is worth posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much blogging, in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve done basically none at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to change that. The idea of writing a blog is appealing I&amp;rsquo;ve just never felt like I had anything interesting going on. I blame doing a CompSci degree for this though. Now that I am doing a degree that I actually want to do I have probably too much that I want to write down about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When last semester ended I planned to blog about my experience, what I thought of the various classes, the campus, the environment of the university in general but I never got around to it. So I will cover both semesters at the same time when this one is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact there is a bunch of stuff I would like to start writing about that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to. Such as book reviews, travel logs and personal updates. The idea of &amp;ldquo;building your own platform&amp;rdquo; was supposed to give the opportunity to do these things and I never took advantage of it when I wanted to. I will be doing so more often starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minute Mead</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/minute-mead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/minute-mead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe for making &amp;ldquo;minute&amp;rdquo; mead. Meaning that it can be made quickly and cheaply. This is not a traditional mead recipe but it is a cheaper and easier alternative that is great for beginners to try out before buying expensive ingredients to try for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 litres of Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Lemons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500g Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500g honey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raisins (Optional) (Recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Activate your yeast in warm water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash and zest and juice lemons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add lemon zest, sugar and honey to a 10 litre pot or bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boil 4 litres of water and add to the sugar mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix the sugar mixture and boiling water until it is one fluid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the remainder of the water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the lemon juice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue mixing and wait for the fluid to reach blood temperature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add yeast. Observe for bubbles. Once bubbling starts, add a lid to the pot and cover with a towel or old t-shirt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now begin bottling the mead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once bottled, add some raisins to the fluid with one teaspoon of sugar per litre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store in your fridge for 3-5 days, release gas from the bottles in the morning and at night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This recipe is proportional, if you want a smaller batch, adjust each ingredient by the same fraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For this recipe I use two 5 litre pots instead of a single pot or bucket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The raisins are used for measuring the state of the mead. The more of them that float the closer it is to being done.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that it is possible that not all of them will float by the time the mead is finished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try experimenting with adding fruits or heather.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjust sugar levels for sweetness / sourness, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Update February 2023</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/site-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/site-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last updated the site so here&amp;rsquo;s a rundown on what&amp;rsquo;s new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-content&#34;&gt;New Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is now a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; page where you can see all the books I own. It is an ongoing project and there are a lot of books missing from it that I have yet to catalogue. However if you find anything of interest on it and would like to contact me, please do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now find the long awaited Cookbook project at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; page. It is a long awaited feature I am sure. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit empty at the moment but I will be filling it out from time to time. Read the Cookbook Now Live article linked below to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain name has now changed from &lt;code&gt;dunkelheit.biz&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;dunkelheit.xyz&lt;/code&gt; and the old domain will expire within a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-articles&#34;&gt;New Articles:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad&#34;&gt;Having Fun Is Trad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns&#34;&gt;Against CDNs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/necessary-evils-internet/&#34;&gt;Necessary Evils on the Internet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/&#34;&gt;Every Day Carry and Equipment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/&#34;&gt;Cookbook Now Live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;housekeeping&#34;&gt;Housekeeping&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The home page and about me pages have been updated to include more accurate information and restructured a bit to ensure clarity. Please keep in mind that the YouTube and Odysee links are placeholders while I set those up. I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post when it has been fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;known-issues&#34;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email is down, I will attempt to fix it at some point when I am less busy. For now you can contact me via twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunkelheitxyz&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@Dunkelheitxyz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. If you are familiar with my content you will know that I am against social media and twitter in particular is my usual go to example of why. Check the Necessary Evils on the Internet article linked above to see some of my more recent thinking on the matter. I am still not convinced it is worth keeping a twitter account long term, for now it is a stopgap fix for a problem I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to find a better solution to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The YouTube and Odysee links don&amp;rsquo;t work. This is on purpose, they are placeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookbook Now Live</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is now live. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a separate RSS feed from the one for blog posts. You may need to adjust your existing RSS link as I made some changes to that on the back end. You can find the most up to date versions of the RSS links at the bottom of this page and on the cookbook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is a bit barren right now but I figured it was better have it public than not at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy cooking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Day Carry and Equipment</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/every-day-carry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get asked for recommendations often regarding technology, clothing, boots, watches, etc and while these are topics I could talk about for hours on end, I simply don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to do so sometimes. As such I thought it would be useful to create an easy to navigate index of what I have, use and recommend that I can share with those interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; this list is likely incomplete and poorly formatted. It will get better over time (hopefully) unless I forget (perhaps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;equipment&#34;&gt;Equipment:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my currently equipped items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;luggage&#34;&gt;Luggage&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backpack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mil-Tec Molle Tactical Assault Pack
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A high quality reproduction / knock-off of some military design backpack. It is waterproof enough for my needs and can carry a significant amount of cargo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The listings for these online will say it is 20l or 25l I&amp;rsquo;m not sure which is accurate or if some are only listing the main compartment. Regardless this bag is excellent for my needs. I bought a second one for this reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid £35 for each of them, I would recommend them at this price. However if you can get something with equal features without a tactical / military look to it that may be the more practical option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gym Bag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adidas Essentials Linear Duffel Bag Medium
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This 40 liter duffel bag is huge, it can hold all of my gym equipment and then some and it weighs basically nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about its durability but I have had no issues with it so far. It has held up better than more expensive bags I have used in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I paid £15 for it. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it at this price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;computers&#34;&gt;Computers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listed in order of most frequent use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macbook Air M1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First generation base model Macbook Air running Apple silicon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideal University computer due to battery life and compatibility with required software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See my current and recommend &lt;a href=&#34;#peripherals&#34;&gt;accessories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom Desktop PC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specs:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R5 2600 CPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RX 580&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32GB DDR4 RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artix Linux System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming capable, not that I really bother these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThinkPad T440p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Linux computer. Fairly well upgraded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For when I need penguin mode on the go. Which I haven&amp;rsquo;t recently hence it&amp;rsquo;s location on the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThinkPad X230&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup for the T440p&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;portable-electronics&#34;&gt;Portable Electronics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Headphones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sennheiser HD450SE Wireless Headphones
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect headphones for traveling. Not too powerful, they don&amp;rsquo;t need to be. Comfortable enough, may need slackened (at your own risk) depending on your head shape / size. I paid £70 for them. I would recommend them at this price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile Phone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Pixel 7
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charcoal Black model of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;peripherals&#34;&gt;Peripherals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macbook Dock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABIWAZY USB C Docking Station
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic Thunderbolt docking station for laptops that support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can convert my Macbook to a desktop at home, small enough to travel with in case I need an Ethernet connection or HDMI output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can likely find a similar or better solution for the price. I paid £52 and don&amp;rsquo;t regret the purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB-A to USB-C Adapters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Google Pixel OEM USB-C adapters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use these for the Google Pixel, they work in the Macbook but are a bit bulky for it in my use case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Syntech USB-A to USB-C adapters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleeker and less bulky option for use with the Macbook, can&amp;rsquo;t use both at the same time due to size. I carry two anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable Storage
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crucial 500GB MX500 SATA SSD
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With USB enclosure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;stationary&#34;&gt;Stationary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A4 Refill Pad
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-explanatory. I need to take notes and do classwork. These are cheap and seemingly infinitely available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Colour Pens
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A pen enclosure with 4 different coloured pens inside. Incredibly useful for language study.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides red (corrections), black (writing), blue (translation) and green (inline note taking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generic branded Post-Its
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For page marking and note taking in my textbooks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am aware that these deteriorate books over time, I am looking for a better alternative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clothing&#34;&gt;Clothing:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming soon! / In Progress!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;footwear&#34;&gt;Footwear&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bundeswehr Fallschrimjager Boots Mk4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finest combat boots ever made. Perfectly comfortable, keeps my feet warm and dry, slip on and off no issue when needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resoled with Vibram soles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converse Chuck Taylor All Star Hi Top&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect flat shoe for the gym.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheap, durable, flat, available in large sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;watch&#34;&gt;Watch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casio G-Shock GA-110
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indestructible digital timepiece.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overnight Oats</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/overnight-oats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/overnight-oats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Overnight oats is a nice easy alternative to porridge that you eat cold instead. A very simple dish to make and can be supplemented with various additions to increase taste, macros and texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my personal way of making it, you will find hundreds of ways of doing it online though, experiment until you find what you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⏲️ Prep time: 5 min&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🍽️ Servings: 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rolled Oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whole Milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whey Protein Powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greek Yoghurt (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fruit of choice (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure out your preferred serving of oats. Add to a glass or cup.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like to go for a good couple of handfuls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one serving of whey protein powder to the oats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this stage you can add other things you like to it. I sometimes add cinnamon or nutmeg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour milk until oats and whey are covered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix together until whey powder is evenly distributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add more milk as needed, you want to cover the dry ingredients entirely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cover the glass or cup with cling film and place in the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the morning you will now have overnight oats.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on how much milk you used you will now find either:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A peanut butter like consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A milkshake like consistency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something in between.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experimenting is key until you find the right consistency for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may now add Yoghurt to the top. (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may now add your fruit of choice to the yoghurt. (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use many different kinds of ingredients when making this. I plan to update this recipe when I find interesting additions and alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use a 100% whey protein powder, absent of soy, pea and other &amp;ldquo;proteins&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can add whatever you like to this, the key with this is experimenting and finding what you like.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like to switch whey flavours around, sometimes I add some chocolate, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessary Evils on the Internet?</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/necessary-evils-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/necessary-evils-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The modern Internet experience for the average Internet user is a strange thing indeed. The compulsive desire to &amp;ldquo;check notis&amp;rdquo; is truly a technological horror and an expression of addictive behavior. Yet many find it to not only be &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; but completely acceptable. How bizarre!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger and I wanted to talk to my friends online I had to open various chat applications to be able to communicate with them all because everyone had just one application that they were comfortable with (or their parents allowed to be installed on the family computer) and it was normal for people to take days or weeks to reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it seems that is no longer the case, everyone feels some kind of need to be on every platform and expects instantaneous replies regardless of time zones or whether the recipient is awake or busy. It&amp;rsquo;s a very artificial way of interacting with people and it is quite disturbing to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the topic of being &amp;ldquo;on every platform&amp;rdquo;, I have come to resent the fact that I have started to rely on some of these same platforms myself recently. Although I have been doing this so far without accounts on them (shout out to &lt;a href=&#34;https://nitter.net/&#34;&gt;nitter&lt;/a&gt;!). This makes it very time consuming and exhausting to keep up to date with people that use these platforms exclusively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there is no realistic solution to this problem when you want to follow more than five or so accounts. Which is why I have recently started to think that it may be a necessary evil to create an account on these platforms for the purpose of following and keeping up to date with certain people, topics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which goes against the spirit of what I am trying to do with this blog: being my own platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it a necessary evil or am I just unaware of a better solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried to use fediverse in the past, and while technologically it is a neat technological solution to problems and some cool people are on there that I would like to keep up to date with it falls into the same category of click-chasing habit forming behavior that twitter, etc all infect their users with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now I haven&amp;rsquo;t made accounts on these platforms however it is something that I am starting to think about. 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to try it out and see for myself if it is worth the hassle. You can follow me &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dunkelheitxyz&#34;&gt;@Dunkelheitxyz&lt;/a&gt; if you want to. As I mentioned above I intend to just use it to keep up to date with some accounts that don&amp;rsquo;t have or use alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update-2&#34;&gt;Update 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not impressed with the twitter experience at all. It seems like it has gotten worse over the years. Which would surprise me if I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect this. The issues I pointed out in past posts about the issues being what twitter is as well as how they do it are still present. Ultimately it is designed to suck your time away and keep you engaged in meaningless nonsense. I will keep the account active for a while longer but I likely won&amp;rsquo;t log in to it. Really I just can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to use it at all, even to delete it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against CDNs</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content Delivery Networks or CDNs for short are a common means for sourcing libraries and frameworks into a web page without having to provide a local copy on the server. It helps cut down on bandwidth and resource usage when serving web content. Which sounds like a great deal for the webmaster. To be fair, it pretty much is a great deal but only for the webmaster and the CDN provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When clients connect to a website and pull JQuery or Bootstrap or some other framework from a CDN instead of the web server serving the page contents they are being tracked. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a very good deal for the user. CDN data can be used to track users around the web without the use of cookies, just by requesting the library from a CDN you are providing an awful lot of metadata without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why it is important to minimize your exposure to sites and services that use these. Of course that means 90% of the web is probably no longer usable. It is important to be smart about it at the least. Should you use social media websites such as Facebook they already know who you are, the frameworks they use are served by them too. Your exposure to request tracking doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter in this scenario since you are already using Facebook. Which you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use if you value your privacy. Although it is possible to use Facebook without exposing your web usage to them, that is for another post, another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s say for example you like to read web blogs like mine. Hopefully they serve those frameworks, etc from their own server. You should check to be sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is served entirely in static HTML and CSS documents so there is no frameworks being loaded at all. However I encourage that you check right now anyway. After all I could be lying (I&amp;rsquo;m not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find that a blog you enjoy reading is using CDNs to serve frameworks, libraries, etc to your browser consider asking the admin to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun Is Trad</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has come to my attention that e-trads have been crusading against fun. Interestingly they do so on the Internet, which is a curious choice of battleground for such a subject. I have absolutely no idea why they are doing this or what they think they will achieve. The most confusing detail of this trend is that having fun is in fact trad so what&amp;rsquo;s with the intentional friendly fire?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days people either treat fun as a part of everyday life (which it is), as an excuse to waste their time (addiction cope) or as an evil to be conquered (the cringe take). It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly strange to see the latter take from people that call themselves &amp;rsquo;traditionalists&amp;rsquo; as these are the very same people that strive to return to some kind of societal normality. In normal societies people had fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History is full of examples of people having fun, be it feasting with friends and neighbors or dancing around a fire or in a ballroom. One could argue that these traditional forms of fun don&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore, they would be wrong of course. Quite commonly you will find if you try hard to look in the first place that there are plenty of opportunities to do these things already and if that somehow yields zero results for you then the problem is that you aren&amp;rsquo;t organising it yourself. However this doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain the aversion to fun that a lot of trads seem to have developed recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem that some of these people have isn&amp;rsquo;t people having fun, it&amp;rsquo;s the ways that people have fun. Particularly the habit forming excesses of it that lead to a loss of enjoyment but an addictive desire that compels participation when any joy to be found is already dead. So is the issue that fun is bad or that having fun is no longer fun? I&amp;rsquo;d wager it&amp;rsquo;s the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of habit forming fun is video games, they are formulaic in design, particularly to extract as much of your time as possible. Where is the fun to be found when these video games become a part time (or even a full time) job? If you have to commit yourself to something that used to be possible to just pick up and play you will find yourself drained of enjoyment very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major problem with people playing video games is excess. People play them way too much, they revolve their lives around them until they stop being fun and become a chore. They play these video games alone in their bedroom for hours or even days at a time in some cases and what do they get out of it? An ever decreasing dopamine rush when the shiny and sparkly effects flare off when you do the same chore (and that is what a lot of video game content is these days) for the thousandth time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with having some fun on your own of course, I find myself enjoying a book quite often. Books are trad right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just video games that masquerade as fun whilst in actual fact being nothing more than addictive distraction. Television, YouTube, TikTok, etc all fulfill this role as well. Since consumption of these is entirely passive the victims of addiction don&amp;rsquo;t even need to think about anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s make a distinction between fun and distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is when you enjoy yourself. A distraction is when you occupy your time. To quote anti-gambling PSAs &amp;ldquo;when the fun stops STOP!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t owe distractions any of your time, that time belong to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally when someone had free time they spent it with other people, or learning a new skill, reading a book or just getting in some extra rest. Fun was enjoyable in the moment and benefited you in some way as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is an ancient and primordial experience that has been twisted and turned into a control mechanism, you can reject it any time you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t have fun playing video games, or watching YouTube, etc but you have to be aware that they are built on algorithms and design standards to keep you engaged with them and not with something else. Time is money and they are draining you of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a bare minimum if you want to have fun find a hobby. Dedicate time to it every week, if after a while you don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it then find a new one. Repeat this until you are having fun. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for the trap of wasting time to pass time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your grandfathers went to the pub, the tavern and the mead hall on Thunorsday. You sit on a couch. Who do you think had more fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn&amp;rsquo;t fun, the problem is a lack of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain Name Change Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/domain-name-change-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided against the use of the &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; TLD for the site and will be returning to tradition and using the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reasoning for choosing the &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD over &lt;code&gt;city&lt;/code&gt; is twofold. The &lt;code&gt;xyz&lt;/code&gt; TLD more accurately represents the end of the internet theme and it is much cheaper which fits with the minimalist theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The update will occur at some point in the coming days. The current domain will continue to work until it expires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS feeds should continue to work on the old domain once the domain change occurs. Once the old domain expires however it will no longer update. Please update your RSS feeds to reflect the new domain. The new feed can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/index.xml&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email will change to the new domain at some point in the future too. I will make sure to update the site when this occurs. For now assume that the &lt;code&gt;w@dunkelheit.biz&lt;/code&gt; address is no longer functional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please update your RSS, email contacts, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Library Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/library-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/library-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got around to cataloging (some of) my personal library and have made a page dedicated to the books of my library for those interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is to use this as a means of keeping track of what books I have, which of them I have read and whether there is any content I have relating to it. As well as keeping a list I can access when out and about in case I need a reminder of which books I own. It is also a useful way to share my library with friends that may wish to borrow something from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided on a system of sorting the page yet. I checked &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/library&#34;&gt;Luke Smith&amp;rsquo;s library&lt;/a&gt; page and saw that he uses the Library of Congress system. Which doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem appropriate for my uses. For now I have opted for categorising books based on which genre I believe is most appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the question of whether to include the likes of manga or mass market paperback fiction titles as these aren&amp;rsquo;t as meaningful as other texts although most of the ones I find myself owning are of a higher quality than one would find on the best sellers list or the advertising shelves at a chain book shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason not to include manga is simply that I have no idea how to do include them elegantly. Do I list them by author or illustrator? Many of them have multiple. For now I have settled on including them by name only until I can determine a better way to include them that is more consistent with the rest of the catalog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to check out the library, it can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/library&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Path in Life</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from my Computer Science degree program. I did not enjoy my time on this degree as much as I had hoped when I started. Computers were my passion at one point in the past, but not so much any more. I still enjoy using the skills I developed and researching the industry out of curiousity. Ultimately though I pushed through to finish what I started and was glad when it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am a free man and I am going back into academia to study a completely different field that I am actually passionate for: Archaeology and History. Specifically Celtic and Anglo-Saxon history. Which is the field that I have always wanted to study but was misled by well-meaning and sincere concern over &amp;ldquo;employability&amp;rdquo; regarding such a subject. Personally I am not too concerned with the employability of such a degree. Afterall I was led to believe that CompSci would make me a millionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to write about my time on this degree as the subjects themselves are very fascinating but the way that they flow between each other by coincidence is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About My Meme Diet</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/all-about-my-meme-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 17:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/all-about-my-meme-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been rereading the Unaboomer archives again and came across this &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/my-diet-following-the-memes/&#34;&gt;interesting post&lt;/a&gt; titled &amp;ldquo;My diet following the memes&amp;rdquo; and thought it was an interesting read. I recommend reading it if you get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading that post I wanted to make my own post in the same vein, which is this one you are reading now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diet-or-dogma&#34;&gt;Diet or Dogma?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In industrial societies people tend to find themselves identifying with meaningless labels and manmade dogmatic practices to feel unique. You will even find people identifying with silly things like soap brands, whichever soy beverage they consume and even what video game they play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of dogmatic diets out there, some like Paleo are closer to the mark than others. There are other similar meme diets such as Keto too which get the fundamentals right by rejecting the ridiculous food pyramid standard but then fall for the direct consequences of the food pyramid such as so called &amp;ldquo;nutrition facts&amp;rdquo; labels and the promotion of factory farmed imported foodstuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of this is many people that have just been introduced to the Keto diet and lazy adherents to it will consider seed oils a perfectly healthy &amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo; to consume as it has the right macros according to the label. That label is lying of course there are no fats in there, only plant oils. These oils are produced using a highly industrialised and mechanical process involving petroleum byproducts and acetone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, at least they get the premise right and if they are coming from the standard Euro-American diet then they are still likely improving their health despite these mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for Keto adherents they do reject the food pyramid and are generally more willing to listen when you have advice to give and generally willing to do at least some research of their own, even if it is second hand research like watching a YouTube video explaining these concepts in normie friendly terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are &amp;ldquo;diets&amp;rdquo; that are more or less a suicidal death cult. You know which one it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-diet&#34;&gt;My Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried most of these meme diets: Keto, Paleo, Carnivore, etc. They all get the fundamentals right: high fat, high protein. But it isn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as that. Protein from a plant is not the same and is not comparable at all to protein from an animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the memes, what do I do now? I eat the natural human diet of course. Animal products, nose to tail, dairy, eggs. Raw, rare, cooked, stewed, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t eat bread or other slave foods unless I am eating out with friends or family and I really want to have a burger or something, which is still a meal that contains a lot of animal products. I enjoy fruits that are in season and native to the local soil, I avoid green vegetables and use carrots, potatoes, etc instead but in limited amounts as they are not sustainable for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-natural-human-diet&#34;&gt;On The Natural Human Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural human diet consisted of raw meat, fish, perennial fruits and mushrooms. If I was raised in an environment where this wasn&amp;rsquo;t presented as &amp;ldquo;disgusting&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;savage&amp;rdquo; then I would likely be able to adapt to doing it for the entirety of my diet. I would probably enjoy this kind of diet if I was able to break the mental barrier, which is why I include raw meats and organs, dairy and eggs in my diet where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I like my steak? Rare with butter and sauteed mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Git Etiquette</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/an-introduction-to-git-etiquette/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/an-introduction-to-git-etiquette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git Etiquette is an interesting subject and one that I found myself having to teach my classmates often. Which I enjoyed because teaching is the greatest way to learn. (Apparently)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply it is the practice of standardising the way you manage your repo and how you communicate regarding things inside of the repo and generally for the purpose of making sure you don&amp;rsquo;t get conflicts, errors and other disasters that lead to development down time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I like to teach Git Etiquette is to introduce a schema and then give examples of how to operate within this schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;schema&#34;&gt;Schema&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical schema that was used on team projects at University was the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-diagram&#34; data-lang=&#34;diagram&#34;&gt;b-bug-name          |   Bug branches
doc-document-name   |   Documentation branches
f-feature-name      |   Feature branches
master              |   Master branch
t-test-name         |   Testing branches
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This allowed us to see at a glance what was going on in a branch without having to ask someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would then give examples of how to create branches, switch to them and back, give proper commit messages and other basic Git usage. The hour or so it takes to teach all of this at the start saves you immeasurable time later and keeps everyone happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;semi-automated-project-management&#34;&gt;Semi-Automated Project Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we made sure to use the GitHub issues tracker, personally I am not a fan of this but it was a reasonable compromise to make for the sake of the team&amp;rsquo;s comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merge and pull requests went through a two person verification stage to make sure we caught any issues before pulling them into the master branch. This was very effective. One developer would verify the contents of the commit and then escalate to the leader of his team or the project so that the users that could push to master was limited to those that were responsible for the project going smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an extremely effective means for us to keep everything flowing and smooth. With minor hiccups along the way when someone needed help with using Git as there are many people with zero experience of Git or similar software at University and not all Universities have classes on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-etiquette-and-you&#34;&gt;Git Etiquette and You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a good chance that only some, perhaps none of the above will be perfectly applicable to your project(s). That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, your schema and management rules must apply to the scope of your project after all. You may need more branch naming schemes than this, you may need more layers of verification. The important thing is to have a set of rules set out when you start so that events can flow into the desired workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steak Tartare</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/steak-tartare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/steak-tartare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an exact copy of my Steak Tartare recipe from &lt;a href=&#34;https://based.cooking/&#34;&gt;based.cooking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steak Tartare is a dish prepared using raw ground / minced beef and egg yolk. A popular dish in Europe, this recipe is a good stepping stone into the world of raw meats, organs and pates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⏲️ Prep time: 10 min&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🍽️ Servings: 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ground Beef (Lean as possible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onion or Shallots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gherkin / Cornichons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsley (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ketchup (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mustard (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worcestershire Sauce (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dice your onions or shallots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finely slice your cornichons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rinse, drain and chop your capers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop parsley. (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop ground beef into smaller pieces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the above to a mixing bowl and mix with hands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ketchup, mustard or Worcestershire sauce as needed and mix further. (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate an egg yolk from the whites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loosely roll some of the mixture into a ball in your hand and place onto a plate and press softly to form a bowl shape, add egg yolk to indentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve, you may now add salt and pepper as desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPNs Are Not Private</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/vpns-are-not-private/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 07:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/vpns-are-not-private/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common misconception you will see repeated online is that VPNs make everything you do online &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo;. The people repeating this myth are unfortunate victims of advertising psyops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to VPNs having active advertising campaigns on television, they make outright claims in said advertisements that are simply untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be obvious that any product that can advertise itself on television doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually offer &amp;ldquo;privacy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; which of course they vaguely define and redefine as needed to sell you on their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPN services effectively have two main features and that&amp;rsquo;s it, anything beyond them is marketing. These are packet / protocol obfuscation and bypassing region locks or ISP blocking. Any claims to &amp;ldquo;privacy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; are poorly defined and assume that the user in question is an expert on internet protocols, fingerprinting, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can VPNs be used for privacy? Yes. Do VPNs offer privacy out of the box? No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, using a VPN service as is for all of your web traffic makes you easier to track as it is another piece of metadata that can be used to identify you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a VPN out of the box but then using it for everything tells every service you connect to that you are on a VPN, which VPN it is and that you use it for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some valid uses of a VPN service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bypassing your ISP / University network rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiding your IP address when using Peer To Peer services.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Such as torrents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bypassing a region lock for web content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide where you are if you decide to go abroad but continue to &amp;ldquo;work from home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are still valid uses for VPNs but for anything privacy or security related you need to know what you are doing. Otherwise you just make yourself a bigger target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPNs are useful tools and have valid uses, they can be used for privacy if you know what you are doing. Just be careful which one you pick and how you use it. Many VPN companies are owned by companies or in territories that are hostile to a free internet. Always research what you are buying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Cares About Twitter?</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/who-cares-about-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/who-cares-about-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s a big deal that Elon Musk bought Twitter. Everyone seems to be competing for the worst take regarding it. Which means it must be the Current Thing™️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true based and red pilled position is as always &amp;ldquo;who cares?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter sucks, it always sucked, it will continue to suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk wants to &amp;ldquo;verify all humans&amp;rdquo;, this effectively means KYCAML for Twitter. Apparently his reasoning for buying Twitter is to secure free speech online or something. A laughable statement when combined with his proposed human verification efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a more free (as in freedom) alternative to Twitter then maybe look into Fediverse services such as Mastodon and Pleroma. Do your research before you join an instance of course. Many of them are more censorious than Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a truly free instance then run your own, create your own rules, block instances that you don&amp;rsquo;t like, etc. You can learn how to host your own Pleroma instance with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs-develop.pleroma.social/backend/installation/otp_en/&#34;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt; or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://landchad.net/pleroma.html&#34;&gt;LandChad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting an External Storage Device</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/encrypting-an-external-storage-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/encrypting-an-external-storage-device/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to keep backups of important data, it&amp;rsquo;s an even better idea to make sure only you can access them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a guide on how to encrypt an external storage device for use on a Linux system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-devices&#34;&gt;Storage Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide should be relatively universal for most external storage devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example I am assuming you know what kind of storage device is best for your use case and that you are using a NEW device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;color:red;&#34;&gt;Important Notice:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are using a device that you have used previously you may wish to securely wipe all data on it first. I do not have a guide for this at this time. I will update this post in the future if that changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need the following to follow this guide along:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer running a GNU/Linux operating system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An external storage device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;cryptsetup&lt;/code&gt; package installed.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name may vary based on distro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;encrypting-the-device&#34;&gt;Encrypting The Device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-find-your-devices-path&#34;&gt;1. Find your device&amp;rsquo;s path.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do so with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo fdisk -l
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The output of this command will list information about each storage device connected to your computer. Such as it&amp;rsquo;s total capacity in GiB units and the model number. You can use this information to determine which disk is the one you intend to write to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point forward I will be referring to this device as /dev/sdx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-set-up-partition-table&#34;&gt;2. Set up partition table.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most drives when purchased will come with the msdos partition table, you don&amp;rsquo;t need this for a Linux machine. The following command will change it to use the GPT partition table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo parted /dev/sdx mklabel gpt
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive now has the GPT partition table format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-creating-a-luks-device&#34;&gt;3. Creating a LUKS device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will now create the LUKS device. Using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksFormat /dev/sdx
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now it will ask you for a password and to confirm it. I assume you know how to choose a strong one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-mapping-the-device&#34;&gt;4. Mapping the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will now mount the device to the mapper. This allows us to use it like a normal storage device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will want to name the device at this stage, we will refer to your given name as DevName from here on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksOpen /dev/sdx DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The device is now available for usage as a normal storage device would be if it were unmounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-formatting-the-device&#34;&gt;5. Formatting the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage we will be formatting the device as the ext4 Linux format. To do that we run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo mkfs.ext4 /dev/mapper/DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The device now has the ext4 format and can be mounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mounting-the-device&#34;&gt;Mounting The Device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage you can mount the device the way you normally would an external device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your GUI file manager such as &lt;code&gt;pcmanfam&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;dolphin&lt;/code&gt; to open it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also do the following to open it using the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-repeat-step-4-above-mapping-the-device&#34;&gt;1. Repeat step 4 above. (Mapping the device)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can skip this if it is still mapped from earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-mount-the-drive&#34;&gt;2. Mount the drive.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now mount the device as you would normally do so for an external device via the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo mount /dev/mapper/DevName &amp;lt;/path/to/mount/point/&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;unmounting-the-device&#34;&gt;Unmounting the device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-unmounting-the-drive&#34;&gt;1. Unmounting the drive.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can unmount the drive using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo umount &amp;lt;/path/to/mount/point&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-unmapping-the-device&#34;&gt;2. Unmapping the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can unmap the device using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksClose DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now safely remove the device from the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you prefer to use a graphical file manager then you should use one.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact for external devices I recommend doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use other formats for the disk if you wish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin and Monero Extremism</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/bitcoin-monero-extremism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/bitcoin-monero-extremism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img class=&#34;postmeme&#34; style=&#34;max-height: 240px;&#34; src=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/bitcoin-monero-extremism/monero-pilled.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Monero Pilled&#34; title=&#34;Monero Pilled&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a Bitcoin maximalist but I am also a Monero extremist. These positions aren&amp;rsquo;t mutually exclusive. In fact these two technologies combined solve the problems of the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-cash-digital-gold&#34;&gt;Digital Cash, Digital Gold&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems almost inevitable at this point that Bitcoin will overtake Gold as the strongest (in terms of market cap) store of wealth. Bitcoin is the new gold standard 😉 for storing wealth but it&amp;rsquo;s not very good at being money any more (just like gold). Due to high transaction fees and currency speculation it is better to not use your Bitcoin and to just HODL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are emergent technologies trying to solve this problem like the lightning network there are some issues regarding anonymity and privacy that makes traditional cash superior for transacting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Monero comes in. Being the only cryptocurrency that allows for transactions to be both anonymous and private, Monero functions almost exactly like physical cash does, except digitally and without out of control money printing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monero can be swapped for Bitcoin using decentralised platforms too meaning you do not require the traditional finance system to acquire it. There is also the experimental technology of atomic swaps that allows private chain-to-chain transactions to swap one crypto for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For these reasons Bitcoin and Monero are the only cryptocurrencies that have legitimate use cases as currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;utility-tokens&#34;&gt;Utility Tokens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some other cryptocurrencies that aren&amp;rsquo;t shitcoins but these are mostly utility tokens such as the Brave foundation&amp;rsquo;s BAT (Basic Attention Token) and Namecoin. But as utility tokens these function as a means to an end and not as a form of savings or money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;proof-of-stake---proof-of-shitcoin&#34;&gt;Proof of stake - Proof of shitcoin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proof of stake is anti-crypto. It allows for the largest bag holders to control the network and takes the decentralisation of proof of work away. Making transactions censorable and the currency defacto non-fungible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;muh-power-usage&#34;&gt;Muh power usage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most energy alarmism this is a non-issue. If you understand how electric power is generated and how much of it goes to waste due to fluctuations in demand then you will see that Bitcoin actually incentivises energy innovation and prevents waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact this is demonstrated in real life Bitcoin mining practices. Countries with cheap electricity get more Bitcoin mining operations in them which brings more money into the local economy as well as incentivising said means of creating energy. El Salvador plans to mine Bitcoin using geothermal for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great way to explain how Bitcoin mining reduces waste is that miners seeking the highest return on their investment will go where the energy is cheapest and most abundant, leaving the places were it is more costly and limited. This effectively allows for excess energy production in one part of the world to be utilised elsewhere by proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-friends-into-crypto&#34;&gt;Getting friends into crypto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting friends and family into crypto can be difficult. A cool trick I found is to get them to install a wallet app, send them a small amount (about $5 worth) and show them how easy it is to use by sending it back to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s better to show and not tell, especially when trying to explain bleeding edge technologies. However you will want to make sure that person you are introducing cryptocurrencies to understands the importance of self custody, securing their devices, backing up their seed phrases, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone will be technically competent enough to do all of this which is fine. If this is the case then you will need to adjust as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is easiest to get people into as it has brand recognition and is the easiest to acquire. It also has a reputation of being &amp;ldquo;internet stocks&amp;rdquo; which attracts the wrong kind of attitude sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monero is harder to recommend to people as most people that get into crypto just want gains and don&amp;rsquo;t see the point in using it as money when they can use money. I understand this position and why it is held, which is why I generally only recommend Monero to people that are already internet present. That is not to say however that I won&amp;rsquo;t recommend it to people anyway, just that if they have no real use for it then they will be better off just buying some Bitcoin sats instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact one thing that Monero is excellent for is teaching someone the basics of how cryptocurrencies work with real life examples but without breaking the bank. It is also good at giving people an idea of how other cryptocurrencies aren&amp;rsquo;t private or anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating QR Codes for Crypto</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/generating-qr-codes-for-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/generating-qr-codes-for-crypto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you run a blog or a website or have any kind of online presence then you should be accepting crypto donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not explain why you should accept crypto here because &lt;a href=&#34;https://landchad.net/crypto&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; exists. Please read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crypto-addresses&#34;&gt;Crypto Addresses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to use third party platforms to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you need is your address and you are good to go. In this example I will be assuming that you have custody of your crypto wallet(s) and don&amp;rsquo;t use fiat-crypto™️ platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example I will be using a Monero address but the same method will work for all cryptocurrencies that use a single-string address. Which &lt;a href=&#34;#tips&#34;&gt;all two&lt;/a&gt; of the important ones do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all you are going to want to know your Crypto receive address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should look like this for Monero: &lt;code&gt;87ukrCxsbK79rQbGwutzTmE4RDPiayn3xK5JT63iiSks5Q9TMCsXzUibXEea1q6x6ij6u2UDxzXpNBU5bP4u8Wz34esoLRG&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly you are going to want to install the &lt;code&gt;python-qrcode&lt;/code&gt; package. It is available under this name on Arch and Debian based distros. It can also be &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/qrcode/&#34;&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have these two tools you are ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;generating-the-qr-code&#34;&gt;Generating the QR code.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Input the following into your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;qr &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;lt;your crypto address&amp;gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; xmr.png
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replacing &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;your crypto address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with your actual address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me this would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;qr &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;87ukrCxsbK79rQbGwutzTmE4RDPiayn3xK5JT63iiSks5Q9TMCsXzUibXEea1q6x6ij6u2UDxzXpNBU5bP4u8Wz34esoLRG&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; xmr.png
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will now have a png image file in your current directory. You can now use this on your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of it in use see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/donate&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-use-this-program&#34;&gt;Why Use This Program?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be considering using an online QR code generator. But any code running on someone else&amp;rsquo;s hardware cannot be trusted with something as sensitive as this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an advanced user you can use this tool with optimisation options or you can output your QR code to an SVG instead. You can use this in combination with other QR code optimisation tools to minimize the file size if that is a concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only two cryptocurrencies actually matter these are Bitcoin and Monero. All other cryptos are gambling or memes (or a dangerous combination of both). &lt;strong&gt;Not financial advice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should always give the user the option to donate with the address itself too. In fact its a good idea to provide the address with the QR code so that they can verify the QR resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be a good idea to create a minimalist solution to allow the user to expand the page with the given QR codes if you plan to include them on other pages on your site. This is only relevant if your site doesn&amp;rsquo;t accommodate for this in its design anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Bloating Your Shell</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/stop-bloating-your-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/stop-bloating-your-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably my favourite part of using Linux is that I can customise my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The customisation options for some of the fundamental tools I use are endless and they are customisable by design. I have probably spent more time customising, modifying and tweaking my shell configurations than any other piece of software on my system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this article I will be using &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; as the example shell unless stated otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-shell-is-a-tool-not-a-toy&#34;&gt;A shell is a tool, not a toy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put the shell is a tool. Whether you are using it interactively or you are scripting tasks, you must use your shell correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the shell is a tool you should be more concerned with what it is for than how it looks. You should also be aware of the dangers of using it incorrectly and the dangers of misunderstanding it while using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most shells support a form of regex which allows you to be as explicit or implicit as you need when creating a command to be run. The use of the &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; on its own in shell scripts should be avoided for this reason. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to accidentally delete your entire home folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-dont-need-plugin-managers&#34;&gt;You Don&amp;rsquo;t Need Plugin Managers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of plugin managers for a shell is peak soydev and a completely ridiculous concept, so why do so many people fall for it? The answer is simple, they are soydevs and do not understand the shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular plugin manager seems to be &lt;code&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/code&gt; for the &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; shell. It is nothing more than an obfuscated fronted for features that are built into &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt;. You do not need it to install anything. You can &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; these plugins manually in your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using these managers makes your shell take longer to load, adds unneeded complexity and causes problems if you want to do something outside of its scope. Not only that but it turns your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file into a complete and utter mess for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop using them, you don&amp;rsquo;t need them. It&amp;rsquo;s lazy and encourages bad practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-your-own-plugins&#34;&gt;Make your own plugins!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have a ridiculous number of aliases? Would you prefer not to scroll through them? You can make these into their own plugin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above with how to load a plugin you simply need to source the plugin file. Plugin files for &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; are actually just &lt;code&gt;.zsh&lt;/code&gt; files and you can make your own. All you need to do is place your aliases in a new file, place the file somewhere appropriate, ensure that the file&amp;rsquo;s shebang is correct: &lt;code&gt;#!/bin/zsh&lt;/code&gt; and then source that file in the .zshrc file like so:
&lt;code&gt;source /path/to/new/alias/plugin.zsh 2&amp;gt;/dev/null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally don&amp;rsquo;t do this with my aliases and would recommend not doing so but this is a good example of how plugins work, they are just &lt;code&gt;.zsh&lt;/code&gt; scripts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aliasing-correctly&#34;&gt;Aliasing correctly.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliases are probably my favourite part of using the shell for most of my needs. You can ensure that a command such as &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; always uses colours, you can create adjacently named commands such as &lt;code&gt;ll&lt;/code&gt; for example to run &lt;code&gt;ls -l&lt;/code&gt; when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally you can bind scripts and long and complicated single line commands to a single word for ease of use. For example I use &lt;code&gt;dotfiles&lt;/code&gt; for managing my dotfiles git repository, I have some scripts that I also like to invoke for things such as checking for updates from all programs on my system, checking crypto prices, etc that I can do with a single word instead of writing the full file path. Although I do I keep these scripts in my &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; I use a naming convention that makes it easier to tell what script it is but it is easier to just invoke them with an alias instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing you should not do with aliases however is use them to replace a program. It is bad practice to &amp;ldquo;rename&amp;rdquo; a core program such as &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; with an alternative you found online. You should instead be using this tool by its name so that you are aware of what you are doing. Using aliases to obfuscate what you are doing is dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shebang&#34;&gt;Shebang&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shebang (shell bang) is used to ensure that the correct shell language is used when a file is run. For example &lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh&lt;/code&gt; would be used if a script is POSIX compliant only and uses no Non-POSIX commands. For example if you write a script in &lt;code&gt;BASH&lt;/code&gt; and it uses bashisms, then your shebang should be &lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/code&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting the shebang in your scripts correctly means that when you invoke them from another shell the correct shell program is used to interpret the script. There are tools for testing your shell scripts so that you know what shebang to use, what adjustments to make to use, etc. I personally quite like &lt;code&gt;shellcheck&lt;/code&gt; but there are other options out there. However you should not rely on these tools and should be familiar with the commands you are using and how they work before committing them to a script. You can always check their man pages or other documentation before you commit to their use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally all scripts should be POSIX compliant only, bashisms are very tempting to use as they do give you more options for your script but there is a good chance you just do not need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;remote-shells&#34;&gt;Remote Shells&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you connect to other devices using a tool like &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; then you should ensure that the remote user&amp;rsquo;s shell config is configured correctly for this. A few examples of what not to do are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invocation of programs with &lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt; returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard declaring terminal (and emulator) compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting background processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-recommendations&#34;&gt;Additional recommendations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When declaring your &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; variable you should do so explicitly, it may seem fun to use a script to do this but that is additional startup logic that you do not need and a script that you now need to maintain. Additionally you should not be declaring the &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file it should be declared in your &lt;code&gt;.zprofile&lt;/code&gt; file so that your application launcher (assuming dmenu) is &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of using a script that iterates through all the sub-directories of your &lt;code&gt;.local/bin/&lt;/code&gt; directory just declare them like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;export PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;$HOME&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;/.local/bin/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;export PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;$HOME&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;/.local/bin/go&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;export PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;$HOME&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;/.local/bin/sh&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This example is from my &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file, which you can find here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/wdunkelheit/dotfiles/-/blob/master/.config/zsh/.zshrc&#34;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-process&#34;&gt;Learning process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, using the shell is a learning process. The more you use it and tinker with it they more you will learn. Feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; about this subject if you would like help or would like to correct anything I have said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emacs Rabbit Hole</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/the-emacs-rabbit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/the-emacs-rabbit-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Emacs as my text editor for about a year now. I still have no idea what I am doing but at least I know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosy-and-powerful&#34;&gt;Cosy and Powerful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Emacs client is very lightweight and it can be self-extended whilst running by using Elisp. I am not quite sure how it works as Elisp is too far down the rabbit hole and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been there yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emacs is very modular to the point that you can use it as an entire operating system if you so choose. It can be used as a windowing manager, a web browser, an email client. Not bad for a text editor right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some believe that this makes Emacs monolithic but that is due to a misconception that Emacs itself is doing all of these things and not the independent Elisp and C programs running within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few days ago I learned that you can run Emacs as a server, I don&amp;rsquo;t even know what purpose this would have but it sounds cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vim-gang&#34;&gt;Vim gang&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to using Emacs I used Vim as my editor of choice. I still do for single file editing. I love the Vim keybindings, macros, instruction language, etc. So when I heard that you can use these in Emacs with Evil mode I decided to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-year-later&#34;&gt;One Year Later&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I have found to be the most impressive about Emacs after a year of use is how it just &amp;ldquo;works&amp;rdquo; in a minimalist way. There&amp;rsquo;s no bells and whistles, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to use my mouse for anything. Once it has been launched it is ready to go, my way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Evil mode in Emacs and it is indistinguishable from using Vim in a terminal except I am no longer held back by any limitations built into a given terminal emulator. At first I missed being unable to use Alt key for quick normal mode instructions but I have since rebound my keyboard to be more Emacs compatible and find the Emacs way of doing things more intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to try Emacs tools such as &lt;code&gt;magit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;rmail&lt;/code&gt; but this is mostly due to wanting to wait until I learn Emacs properly. Speaking of which&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-off-the-training-wheels&#34;&gt;Taking off the training wheels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn Emacs from scratch, as it stands for the last year I have not been using Emacs &amp;ldquo;correctly&amp;rdquo; in the sense that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been using it in a way that allows me to learn how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using an Emacs &amp;ldquo;rice&amp;rdquo; named &lt;code&gt;Doom Emacs&lt;/code&gt;. Which is effectively a glorified interface for package management that handles all of the initial setup of the packages that come with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is to learn the intricacies of Emacs configuration, how to correctly use Org mode for documentation and organisation and create an Emacs build that only has what I need and want in it. My hope is that by doing so I will learn more of the intricacies of Emacs and will be able to use it more effectively and maybe start writing my own Elisp extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-know&#34;&gt;In The Know&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that my experience of learning Emacs from scratch will be interesting enough to some people that I may blog about it a bit. I am not sure whether I will do so by updating this post or by making new posts regarding a specific topic, etc I want to talk about. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Books Suck</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/modern-books-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 18:30:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/modern-books-suck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The commodification of books and its consequences have been a disaster for the human race. There is no legitimate reason for the continued printing of the modern paperback to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-abundance-of-nothing&#34;&gt;An Abundance of Nothing.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s state the obvious first. You walk into your local (or high street) book shop and what do you see promoted the most? Erotic fiction, books about why you should hate yourself, books promoting diets that will kill you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no reason for these to exist. They functionally have no contents, they do not contribute to any thing meaningful and serve only as a means to assist consumers in parting with their wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally these books are always printed in a low quality, disposable paperback format. Of course they are not deserving of a higher quality printing anyway, after all the contents of these books is nothing more than a mockery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books that have stood the test of time will of course have shelf space reserved for them in these shops and the quality difference between them and what surrounds them is night and day. But these books are hardly ever put on the display tables or promoted for sale. In fact most book shops seem to be content to not have these books in stock at all if they can get away with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-paperback-paradox&#34;&gt;The Paperback Paradox&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I enter a book shop there is always a &amp;ldquo;new from best sellers&amp;rdquo; as well as a &amp;ldquo;reprinted classics&amp;rdquo; display. The interesting thing is that these best selling authors apparently didn&amp;rsquo;t earn the right to a first edition hardback, something that used to be a given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally these so called &amp;ldquo;reprinted classics&amp;rdquo; are always &amp;ldquo;edited for modern sensibilities&amp;rdquo; which of course is just a fancy way of saying censored and modified, making them anything but a reprint and completely useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is rather ironic that the perception of the paperback bringing literature to the masses has resulted in the worst quality of writing in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally it is also ironic that the proliferation of paperbacks is for some reason a sacred cow to the very same groups of reactionary liberals that think banning plastic straws will stop the third world from dumping all their trash into the oceans and rivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;print-on-demand-and-self-publishing&#34;&gt;Print on Demand and Self-Publishing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting phenomena that has emerged in the last decade has been the ability for authors to self-publish their books using print on demand services like Lulu. This has resulted in some authors that would have been ignored otherwise being able to bring their books to market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a double edged sword however as most of these books are of an even worse quality that what is being pushed out by the larger publishing houses. Now if these books really are &amp;ldquo;print on demand&amp;rdquo; and I have no reason to believe otherwise based on my experience with them then the environmental issues are at least minimized if not completely mitigated by preventing the waste of excessive quantities of printing materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Print on demand has caused problems for legitimate authors in that they are now competing against algorithms for exposure on self-publishing services. Most book descriptions on Amazon for example look like old YouTube video descriptions with hundreds of unrelated words included for the sake of getting the attention of primitive search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;based-and-red-pilled-book-reviews&#34;&gt;Based and Red pilled Book Reviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a severe lack of high quality discussion regarding high quality books online. At least from what I can see. &amp;ldquo;BookTube&amp;rdquo; is full of people that recommend books on the cover art alone for example. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that some of them actually read the books but they don&amp;rsquo;t give this impression in their videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good books are undoubtedly being published, be it with publishers or via print on demand services but they are competing for attention with books written by algorithms, marketed by algorithms and sold by algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to look out for based and red pilled book reviewers, discussion, etc online of course but in the mean time I should put my keyboard where my mouth is and try to contribute to what I want to see. As such I will start publishing essays, reviews, etc on this very subject on this site. I even made a &lt;code&gt;📚 Books&lt;/code&gt; tag for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Dont Care If You Use Linux</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have seen my previous post about Free (as in freedom) software and came to the conclusion that I want to &amp;ldquo;convert&amp;rdquo; normies to using Linux. This is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not care if you use Linux or not, I do not care what distro you use either. Whatever works for you, works for you and that&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I recommend that you use a Linux based OS is not that I personally gain from you doing so but that you will gain from it. I have no attachment to what you use or how you use it. Linux fanboyism is a ridiculous concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-confusion&#34;&gt;Further Confusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the &amp;ldquo;What Does The Steam Deck mean?&amp;rdquo; post, someone read it and completely misunderstood it. They were under the impression that I wish to &amp;ldquo;convert&amp;rdquo; gamers to Linux. LOL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had intended to delete that post for being crap anyway, which I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point I was trying to make could be made in a sentence but I tried to give too much context. So I will make my point here and consider the issue resolved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Steam Deck will put more eyes on Linux as a gaming platform. It will not convert the masses to a new operating system that they have no apparent need for. This will not benefit me, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way let&amp;rsquo;s get to the main point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-dont-care-bro&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Care Bro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put if you don&amp;rsquo;t use Linux I don&amp;rsquo;t care and more importantly, if you do use Linux I don&amp;rsquo;t care either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have absolutely no need to know or care for what operating system you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-consumer-issue&#34;&gt;The Consumer Issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of Linux consumerism has reached its twilight, we now live in a world where people wear Tux t-shirts unironically and discuss their desktop environment of choice as if it is their favourite sportsball team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a Linux consumer? A Linux™️ consumer is someone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Linux because they want a Unix like free software operating system, they are just anti-Windows and use Linux as if it were Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I estimate that about 60-70% of people with a Linux based OS on their personal computer would fall under the category of a Linux consumer and as I stated above. I don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical example is someone that installs whatever meme distro they were shilled then goes on to use Google and Microsoft services, integrating them into every level of their workflow and consumption cycles. It really is an impressive example of cognitive dissonance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consuming Linux is a mindset that I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or patience to entertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put if you need to attach part of your identity to the operating system that you use, you need to get a life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;converting-normies&#34;&gt;Converting Normies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is simply not an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only benefit a normie will get from switching to Linux is that their 5 year old laptop won&amp;rsquo;t run to a halt and can still get security patches. The real normie operating system is Google Chrome after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t care about software, ethics, etc. They use their computer to write their homework, read their emails, watch cat videos and buy junk from Amazon. They are content and happy if they can do this, you won&amp;rsquo;t convince them to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youre-just-an-elitist&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re just an elitist!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/yeschad.webp&#34; style=&#34;height:120px; margin:auto; display:block&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; &#34;&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free As In Freedom</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Libre, not gratis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the specifics of Free Software in this article, if you would like to know more check the &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34;&gt;references&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;freedom-is-non-negotiable&#34;&gt;Freedom is non-negotiable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;memeright&#34; src=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/freedom.webp&#34; alt=&#34;GNU Pepe&#34; title=&#34;GNU Pepe&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your freedom as a user is the most important aspect of the software that you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common phrase found online regarding services such as search engines and email service providers goes something like &amp;ldquo;if it&amp;rsquo;s free then you are the product&amp;rdquo;. This is a fairly good summary as it implies (accurately) that these service providers see &lt;strong&gt;YOU&lt;/strong&gt; as an extension of their property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with this statement is the implication that software that is paid for will respect your rights. This is of course not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution to this problem is straightforward. Don&amp;rsquo;t use them. I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting a boycott (boycotts don&amp;rsquo;t work lol) I am actually just suggesting that you opt out and choose to use Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-a-change&#34;&gt;Make a change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant services you can change are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office Suite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also drop social media and streaming services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem daunting to have to switch all of your service providers but you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do it all at once. In fact if you do it slowly over time that is perfectly fine. You may find that you have to do so anyway if you keep on top of sanitising your email inbox, have ongoing projects or need access to a given social media platform to stay in contact with family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the latter case you may wish to get them onboard with switching to Free Software and Libre services too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every proprietary service you currently use likely has a Free Software equivalent. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t then you probably never needed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;regarding-video-games-and-drm&#34;&gt;Regarding Video Games and DRM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video games are almost always proprietary. If you want to play them there are ways to do so on Linux including native Linux binaries. However for those that don&amp;rsquo;t have native binaries you may experience issues with their &amp;ldquo;Anti-Cheat&amp;rdquo; or DRM. I recommend just not buying games that have intrusive layers like that in the first place, it is unacceptable for these companies to treat customers this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay away from streaming services like Netflix and Spotify. Buy an SD card instead, store your music on that and stick it in your phone. Streaming services take your money and give you nothing in return, you do not own what you &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo; they are ripping you off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-be-fooled&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Source and Free Software are not the same thing and whilst many Open Source programs would fit the definition of Free Software in practice this is not true of all Open Source programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the popular editing suite Visual Studio Code is not free software due to its inclusion of anti-features such as telemetry and centralisation of integrated services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is Telegram, the client software uses a modified GPL3 that makes it non-free and the server software is completely proprietary. Telegram is fundamentally no different from using WhatsApp in terms of user freedoms and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common misconception is that Android devices are &amp;ldquo;Free&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo; but this couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from the truth. Out of the box these devices do not run Free Software or Open Source software. They run proprietary builds of a semi-open source project but the closed source proprietary nature of the out of the box device makes it a non-free device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these devices can be modified with Free and Open Source Android forks such as LineageOS and GrapheneOS. With GrapheneOS being the superior choice if you own a Google Pixel device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;im-happy-to-help&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like advice or some pointers or if you would like to discuss the topics discussed here feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will likely publish articles on switching services in the future so make sure to subscribe to the RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html&#34;&gt;What is Free Software? | GNU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/why-i-use-the-gpl-and-not-cuck-licenses&#34;&gt;Why I Use the GPL and Not Cuck Licenses | Luke Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free As In Freedom: Richard Stallman&amp;rsquo;s Crusade For Free Software, Sam Williams - ISBN-13: 978-0-59-600287-4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS is Based!</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/rss-is-based/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 08:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/rss-is-based/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started using Newsboat for RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a proper RSS setup has been on my &amp;ldquo;cosy setup&amp;rdquo; checklist for a while. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take much time at all to get it working either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously just used browser plug-ins for this however this approach is terrible in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a proper setup using Newsboat I can truly appreciate RSS feeds and I would recommend using them to anyone that wants to keep up to date with things without engaging with social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-rss&#34;&gt;What is RSS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS is an abbreviation of Really Simple Syndication, although this isn&amp;rsquo;t it&amp;rsquo;s original name. Put simply it is a way for you to download a feed from a website and keep up to date with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that instead of using intrusive and manipulated social media feeds to keep up to date with your favourite web feeds you can have it all in one place on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may in fact already be using RSS without realising it. Did you know that most podcast apps are just RSS readers with a media player?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using RSS you can completely replace the need for a Google account to keep up to date with your favourite YouTube channels. Although adding YouTube channels to an RSS feed isn&amp;rsquo;t as straightforward as blogs or podcasts it is doable and once you have done it once the process is quickly repeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One small caveat to this is that YouTube can choose to eliminate RSS feeds at any time so it may be worth keeping a separate list of channels you subscribe to for the inevitable third party solution that pops up (or perhaps already exists? 👀 Let me know please) if this situation were to arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-rss&#34;&gt;Why use RSS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Censorship Resistant:&lt;/strong&gt; You get what you subscribed to, no manipulation by algorithms or loss of access based on social media account status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convenience:&lt;/strong&gt; Every feed you care for in one place, in whatever order you want, categorised, tagged, etc however you see fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalist:&lt;/strong&gt; No need for accounts or web services. Just a list, add or remove as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portable:&lt;/strong&gt; You can read the feeds using any client you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy:&lt;/strong&gt; RSS just loads an XML file from a web server, there is no tracking, JavaScript, middleman services, etc. You get the feed sent directly to you without the need to identify yourself (beyond IP requirements).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-get-started&#34;&gt;How do I get started?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get started by downloading an RSS client. I recommend the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;newsboat&lt;/code&gt; - CLI client, highly configurable and easy to configure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;liferea&lt;/code&gt; - GUI client, highly configurable graphical client, uses GTK+ theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These can be found in your distro&amp;rsquo;s package manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you have a client you can start adding your favourite feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add feeds as you go, doing it all at once can be an exhaustive exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a site doesn&amp;rsquo;t natively support RSS you will likely find a tool that can create a feed for you instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some sites provide feeds for specific topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the documentation for your chosen client if you need help configuring it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Markdown Format</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/switching-to-markdown-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/switching-to-markdown-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am starting to get comfortable with &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; as a static site generator, I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t made my theme the &amp;ldquo;correct way&amp;rdquo; but for now it works to an acceptable minimum and most importantly the pages it produces are formatted perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an issue in that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide if I wanted to use Markdown or HTML when writing blog posts. The issue may seem silly (it is) but my reasons for having it were pretty straight forward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just Works&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to read and write (important for blogging)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo&amp;rsquo;s intended language (kinda)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTML:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives me total control via element ids and tags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Markdown page elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows for very specific inputs into the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accurate and very flexible control of media inputs (important)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; (currently) supports the use of both at the same time but with some minor issues. Ideally I would prefer to use one standard for blog posts and stick with it. For the sake of uniformity and simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I was previously doing when drafting a post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write it in Markdown for ease of writing and proofreading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start &lt;code&gt;hugo server -D&lt;/code&gt; so that I can preview the page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert everything to HTML in the document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check preview again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s all good then publish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the issue here should be obvious, I was effectively putting in twice the work for the same result. But this did mean that I had absolute control of the page contents and could ensure certain elements are displayed correctly if I wanted them to have a unique style or position that Markdown itself wouldn&amp;rsquo;t produce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also realised after the &lt;a href=&#34;learning-german&#34;&gt;Learning German&lt;/a&gt; entry that I could just take the HTML output from the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; output. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was to eliminate steps 3 and 4 above. The easiest way to do this is to just eliminate HTML conversion of the entire document and use &lt;code&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt; when needed instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This eliminates steps 3 and 4 as well as allowing me to control elements very specifically when needed and keeps the document readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So going forward all posts will be created this way unless it isn&amp;rsquo;t viable for the post type. All previous posts will be converted too. Top level pages AKA &amp;ldquo;base&amp;rdquo; pages will still be written in HTML for functional reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally the site will now be rendered using the &lt;code&gt;uglyURLs = true&lt;/code&gt; option as I don&amp;rsquo;t like the look of &lt;code&gt;/blog/post-name/index.html&lt;/code&gt; in the file tree.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning German</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/learning-german/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/learning-german/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to learn German. I have always had an interest in learning another language but due to the terrible methodology used by the education system and cringe meme apps like DuoLingo I was never motivated enough to stick them out. However I recently came to discover the Michel Thomas method after reading these articles by Luke Smith: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/notes-on-learning-languages&#34;&gt;Notes on Learning Languages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/learning-european-languages-michel-thomas&#34;&gt;Learning European Languages (Michel Thomas)&lt;/a&gt;. I won&amp;rsquo;t bother to summarize them here but you should definitely read them if you are interested in learning a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading these articles I was convinced to give the method a try. I will update this post every so often with my thoughts on the method so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-why-german&#34;&gt;So why German?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably the most relevant language for me to learn based on its similarities to English, my musical interests and the location of a lot of my friends. I would love to be able to travel there without being a &amp;ldquo;that guy&amp;rdquo; tourist that just speaks in English the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally I believe that learning German will give me reason to explore other related languages. I have always found languages interesting, who knows maybe one day I will be able to speak to people on every continent? I&amp;rsquo;d also like to put the theory that thinking in multiple languages can give you a better understanding of concepts to the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the tape format to be the best method of learning German that I have tried so far however with no native German speakers around me to put my practice to the test I am kinda stuck for the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Games Are Over</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/video-games-are-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/video-games-are-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern video games are an industrialised product that satisfies checklists at the cost of a unique identity and product. They are deceptively marketed and maliciously monetized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally a video game will come out that is just trying to be a fun video game. These are few and far between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a nostalgia post, modern video games are genuinely terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-they-suck&#34;&gt;Why do they suck?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simple answer and the correct one is: money. Video games have been watered down and industrialised into a checklist of what sells and what gets social media reactions. Many businesses have been led to believe that social media exposure is free advertising. Anyone with a basic understanding of social media algorithms can tell you why this isn&amp;rsquo;t true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally the rise of games as a service has effectively made every video game the same with some aesthetic differences. On top of that these service games are psychologically engineered to encourage you to spend as much time as possible playing their game over the competitor&amp;rsquo;s game as well as spending as much money as possible in their in-game store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;indie&amp;rdquo; title has become increasingly meaningless as industrial gaming corporations have co-opted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is clearly a desire for video games that are made &amp;ldquo;the old way&amp;rdquo;, games made this way are few and far between and as soon as a developer gets a reputation for making games like this they get acquired by a larger corporation and these types of video game disappear with that acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industrialised video games are produced with the budget of hollywood movies, with checklists (the developers cannot diverge from) of what marketing execs think will sell the product and they would rather divert resources to fighting criticism than taking it on board. All of this results in video games being designed for an &amp;ldquo;average gamer&amp;rdquo; that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally and most obviously, video games are no longer being developed by the same type of people. Designers, writes, artists, etc all have agenda&amp;rsquo;s and they intend to use their product to groom you to that agenda. You already knew this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;muh-nostalgia&#34;&gt;Muh nostalgia!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older games were designed differently, no one can dispute this. The way that they were designed respected the player&amp;rsquo;s intelligence and their time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally the technology to rinse your customers didn&amp;rsquo;t exist yet (at least at scale) so even if the idea did cross someone&amp;rsquo;s mind it wasn&amp;rsquo;t implementable in a meaningful or functional way. This led to video games being designed to be challenging, fun and replayable since they wanted you to come back and buy the sequel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gamers devised their own ways of competing with one another (the origin of speedruns) but most importantly gamers owned their games, they could loan them to friends, they could sell what they didn&amp;rsquo;t like, they could rent to try, some developers even made demos so you didn&amp;rsquo;t need to rent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that every old game was great, of course not. A lot of them probably sucked. In fact, most of them did. But the ones that didn&amp;rsquo;t suck are still talked about decades later, they are still played decades later, there are entire communities online dedicated to them that have been around almost as long as the games themselves. You won&amp;rsquo;t see this kind of community building effort for most modern games as they are replaced annually and are designed to be played by people that don&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply there are three solutions to the problem of modern games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a better hobby. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you can&amp;rsquo;t go back and play your video games occasionally but being realistic any &amp;ldquo;hobby&amp;rdquo; that isn&amp;rsquo;t productive isn&amp;rsquo;t healthy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just sit back, relax, enjoy your older video games and wait for this accursed industry to collapse in on itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only support developers that respect you as a customer, you can also download an emulator or get some classics from GOG.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important part is that you recognise that modern games are not designed to be fun, but to be addictive and profitable at your expense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
