<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>language on Dunkelheit Citizen</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in language on Dunkelheit Citizen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Path in Life</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from my Computer Science degree program. I did not enjoy my time on this degree as much as I had hoped when I started. Computers were my passion at one point in the past, but not so much any more. I still enjoy using the skills I developed and researching the industry out of curiousity. Ultimately though I pushed through to finish what I started and was glad when it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am a free man and I am going back into academia to study a completely different field that I am actually passionate for: Archaeology and History. Specifically Celtic and Anglo-Saxon history. Which is the field that I have always wanted to study but was misled by well-meaning and sincere concern over &amp;ldquo;employability&amp;rdquo; regarding such a subject. Personally I am not too concerned with the employability of such a degree. Afterall I was led to believe that CompSci would make me a millionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to write about my time on this degree as the subjects themselves are very fascinating but the way that they flow between each other by coincidence is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning German</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/learning-german/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/learning-german/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided to learn German. I have always had an interest in learning another language but due to the terrible methodology used by the education system and cringe meme apps like DuoLingo I was never motivated enough to stick them out. However I recently came to discover the Michel Thomas method after reading these articles by Luke Smith: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/notes-on-learning-languages&#34;&gt;Notes on Learning Languages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/learning-european-languages-michel-thomas&#34;&gt;Learning European Languages (Michel Thomas)&lt;/a&gt;. I won&amp;rsquo;t bother to summarize them here but you should definitely read them if you are interested in learning a language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading these articles I was convinced to give the method a try. I will update this post every so often with my thoughts on the method so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-why-german&#34;&gt;So why German?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably the most relevant language for me to learn based on its similarities to English, my musical interests and the location of a lot of my friends. I would love to be able to travel there without being a &amp;ldquo;that guy&amp;rdquo; tourist that just speaks in English the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally I believe that learning German will give me reason to explore other related languages. I have always found languages interesting, who knows maybe one day I will be able to speak to people on every continent? I&amp;rsquo;d also like to put the theory that thinking in multiple languages can give you a better understanding of concepts to the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;update&#34;&gt;Update:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the tape format to be the best method of learning German that I have tried so far however with no native German speakers around me to put my practice to the test I am kinda stuck for the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
