<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Language on Dunkelheit</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/language/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Language on Dunkelheit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Path in Life</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from my Computer Science degree program. I did not enjoy my time on this degree as much as I had hoped when I started. Computers were my passion at one point in the past, but not so much any more. I still enjoy using the skills I developed and researching the industry out of curiousity. Ultimately though I pushed through to finish what I started and was glad when it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am a free man and I am going back into academia to study a completely different field that I am actually passionate for: Archaeology and History. Specifically Celtic and Anglo-Saxon history. Which is the field that I have always wanted to study but was misled by well-meaning and sincere concern over &amp;ldquo;employability&amp;rdquo; regarding such a subject. Personally I am not too concerned with the employability of such a degree. Afterall I was led to believe that CompSci would make me a millionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to write about my time on this degree as the subjects themselves are very fascinating but the way that they flow between each other by coincidence is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
