<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Dunkelheit</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Dunkelheit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 12:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Apple Ecosystem Is Normie Coded</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/the-apple-ecosystem-is-normie-coded/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/the-apple-ecosystem-is-normie-coded/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a moment of minimalist induced madness I decided to try out the Apple ecosystem, this was a few years ago now and I have been using it long enough to have formed my opinions on it based on experience and observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, the Apple ecosystem is normie coded. This is not intended as an insult or a smug remark however, in fact it&amp;rsquo;s just a conclusion and one that I think Apple themselves are aiming for. These devices have nailed their intended function: be a device that does everything the user expects, do it in the simplest way possible to avoid user frustration and sell the user on the concept of &amp;ldquo;less is more&amp;rdquo;. Let&amp;rsquo;s get some things clear and dismiss a few myths: Apple devices are powerful hardware (this is obiviously the case),  they aare and aren&amp;rsquo;t walled gardens (this is complicated) and they are not designed exclusively for non-technical customers which is probably the most common and reddit coded take someone could have on Apple devices. Keep these observations in mind as I explore my experience with these devices and explain my thoughts regarding whether or not the Apple ecosystem is worthwhile for myself or for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I begin I will mention that this is written with my experience with the iPhone 15, Macbook Air M1 and AirPods Pro 2nd generation as my Apple experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardware&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the simplest part of the Apple package, the hardware. These devices are powerful, they have fantastic battery lives and they are extremely lightweight and clean in their construction. Can you get more powerful devices for the money? absolutely, better battery life? I assume so, just as lightweight? of course. But can you get a device that is just as clean? yeah that&amp;rsquo;s possible too. But from all my research I could not find devices that met all these requirements at once at the same price point. Now of course hardware is not the be all and end all of whether a device is good and in my expierence it&amp;rsquo;s the software that matters most to me. Which is where pretty much every single complaint I have about the Apple ecosystem finds itself levelled. Or put simply: if I could have Linux on my Macbook I would, if I could have Android on an iPhone would I? no, I&amp;rsquo;d rather have an Android phone than an &amp;ldquo;iDroid&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these devices I can honestly say that I was impressed by what I used but mostly by the battery life and the lightweight construction of the Macbook Air M1. I used this thing as my daily driver for a year, travelling to and from classes, the library and home and only needing to charge it at night before bed. I pretty much never turned the thing off except for updates and it would just open up to everything I had before instantly, everytime. I loved this, I still love this, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much my favourite part of this machine. This was the killer feature of this device for me and it still is. The battery life on this thing is phenomenal and since I only used it for the purpose of writing, note taking, programming and web browsing it did everything I needed and more, incredibly quickly and without any major effect on the battery life of the device. A stressfree experience with battery life and performance is what I want in a laptop and I can say that I got what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the hardware of the iPhone 15 I was also impressed, this phone is fast, has decent battery life (regardless of poor battery optimisation of App Store applications) and the camera takes the greatest video I have ever seen on a mobile device as well as excellent photographs. So in terms of the abstract hardware features I found the device to be pleasant to use and had no real issues related to it&amp;rsquo;s hardware performance. Pretty much every issue I had with this device was with it&amp;rsquo;s software and the ecosystem it is built around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireless earbuds are not really my thing, I prefer headphones and I&amp;rsquo;d prefer them to be wired if possible but every phone manufacturer has taken it upon themselves to make it their personal crusade to make sure that no device has an audio jack. So I got a pair of AirPods Pro 2 for the gym as inears are much more comfortable in this environment. I love these things for the gym and for walking, the noise cancellation in particular is incredibly useful is a busy gym that blasts the worst music they could possible choose for that environment and the battery life on these things is seemingly endless. But a lot of these features stop working the second you use them on a non-Apple device which is a major red flag for me and one of the reasons I plan to leave the Apple plantation. (Spoilers!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could rate Apple products on their hardware experience alone I&amp;rsquo;d say that it is fundamentally solid and whilst you pay a premium for the polish you do get what you pay for if you use these devices daily for their intended purposes. But that&amp;rsquo;s where the positives of Apple products are expected and unfortunately they start to become burdensome as we move on to looking at their software suite, also known as the Apple Ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s software suite is known as the Apple Ecosystem by most technologically concious internet users although I am unsure if it is a term that Apple themselves use or not, not that it matters as it is part of the zeitgeist whether they like it or not. I was unsure where to begin when talking about this ecosystem but I have come to the conclusion that there are a lot of positives to speak about that give more context to the negatives, so for the sake of not repeating myself to explain points I will start with the positives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the quality of Apple&amp;rsquo;s software engineering I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone could say with a straight face that it is aesthetically or functionally bad. Aesthetics are a personal preference but when there is a unified design standard for the user interface in a given software suite I am willing to put aside some animosity towards the things I don&amp;rsquo;t like because at least less of my time is being wasted. Fortunately however I don&amp;rsquo;t have many negative things to say regarding the user interface of Apple&amp;rsquo;s software suites. In fact I find it to be a bit too intuitive that I feel like I may be missing something in some cases. So the design isn&amp;rsquo;t bad in my experience, and as a long time Linux user I can see where a lot of desktop application design ideas got their inspiration from. Functionally speaking I found no real issue with Apple&amp;rsquo;s software other than their terminal and text editor being rather basic by my standards but considering you even get something with a decent featureset out of the box compared to what I recall from Windows I will let it slide. I am willing to let it slide even further as MacOS is a &amp;ldquo;Unix&amp;rdquo; system and is immediately familiar to me and the tools that I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The included office suite is not only functional and has seemingly zero bloat but I actually really enjoyed using it to the point of missing it when I revert to using LibreOffice on my Linux desktop. The mail client is also a shining example of a fantastic application that gets the job done, although it misses some features I would have liked. The desktop experience is serviceable, I don&amp;rsquo;t find myself using the desktop much as I open the device to my opened tasks and continue what I was doing anyway. Safari is a serviceable browser but I installed Brave and Firefox almost immediately anyway, unlike on the iPhone you can actually install software on the Mac from outside of the app store. Once I had Homebrew installed and setup I installed all of my go to software immediately, dropped my dotfiles where they needed to go and it was as if I was back on my Linux desktop, other than the Mac desktop it was pretty much the same experience. The issues of the walled garden are seemingly exclusive to the iPhone but this is not true. On a Mac the walled garden has a gate and you can come and go as you please for the most part. On iPhone this is absolutely not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On an iPhone you have to use what comes with the device or what you can find on the app store and you have to like it. In my case this didn&amp;rsquo;t bother me too much, in fact it was weirdly a selling point for me at the time as I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have a device on my person that would distract me and I don&amp;rsquo;t have much of a desire to use my phone for anything other than calls, email, messages, camera and music. All of these features  come with the device as they do pretty much all Android devices too, although there are issues with these on Android too that is outside the scope of what I plan to discuss here. My biggest issue with the Apple ecosystem is not the locked down nature of the device itself, although I oppose this on principle but rather the fact that to put my own music on the device requires a Windows or Mac computer. Which luckily I had a Mac but then the process of moving music to the device was a nightmare as well. This is where the tyrannical nature of the walled garden is most blatant, if you want to use your own music you will be inconvenienced. If you want to sync your files, upload your photographs, videos, etc to your computer instead of iCloud, you will be inconvenienced. There are more examples of this but I think I make the point most clear with these as they are the most basic and fundamental examples of things I should be able to do when and how I want yet there are so many loops to jump through to do so. This will be the reason I switch to Android with my next phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I tried to explain to someone that I was having these issues I know that I would be met with &amp;ldquo;just use iCloud then&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;pay for Apple music then&amp;rdquo; which not only would be completely ignoring the actual issue but creates an entirely new one. Why do I have to pay for an alternative when the standard option isn&amp;rsquo;t available in the first place? This is where the &amp;ldquo;normie coded&amp;rdquo; nature of the Apple ecosystem becomes obvious. These &amp;ldquo;solutions&amp;rdquo; to the problem are not solutions at all but the expected manner that you would use the device in. Apple Music, iCloud, Apple Fitness, etc everything is a subscription service. I don&amp;rsquo;t pay for any subscription services for reasons that should be obvious but in case it isn&amp;rsquo;t: why should I pay someone else to use my own stuff? Sure I can put my own music on the phone, sure I can get my photos and videos off the phone, but I have to jump through artificial hoops to do so when this was never the case on Android or in the age before the &amp;ldquo;smart phone&amp;rdquo;. Subscription services are a form of digital slavery and the way that the iPhone practically forces it upon their users is quite simply unacceptable. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to give in and pay for them but I surely will not be buying a new phone either and they can forget me jumping through their hoops. I have a Walkman A35 that I love and was using when I first got the iPhone, I had no idea of half these issues until I had owned the thing for almost a year I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep using my Walkman even when I switch to another platform for my mobile device which I will be doing out of principle. I will be decoupling myself from the iPhone and the Apple ecosystem entirely over this ridiculous and offensive push towards digital slavery. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be like this so I choose for it not to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a shame that devices with such great hardware and software quality have such a crippling and ridiculous model of user exploitation baked into the design of the software suite. The iPhone having less features but better implementation of them was one of it&amp;rsquo;s selling points to me originally but their approach to simplicity being built around the idea of outright blocking you from using alternatives is a counter to any benefit it has to not being a distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important observation to be made is that since it is designed this way on purpose, Apple knows that they can exploit their users this way and get away with it and they do get away with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;normie-coded&#34;&gt;Normie Coded&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s devices are great and their ecosystem is awful. Conceptually the idea of a &amp;ldquo;software ecosystem&amp;rdquo; is kinda gross. It is normie coded in that it is designed to turn a consumer into a dependant and that allows for a vampiric business model of selling expensive devices that &amp;ldquo;just work&amp;rdquo; to people that don&amp;rsquo;t know any better (this is not their fault) and then exploiting them with service fees for features that they have no alternative to. There is a demographic of users that will enjoy this business model, that don&amp;rsquo;t mind being ripped off because they would rather have convenience and these users would still opt into these services if alternatives were possible in fact they would likely see these services as an even greater convenience in that context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denying paying customers basic features and selling worse alternatives back to them at a monthly fee is disrespectful and outright exploitation. It is targeted to demographics that don&amp;rsquo;t know any better and will enjoy their exploitation because it is convenient to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got to try this experiment and see for myself just how bad it can be. It makes me appreciate just how good I have it and how much better it can be when I eventually switch to something better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Notes Management</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/simple-notes-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/simple-notes-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to start organising my notes more thoroughly and introduced a schema to my notes directory (demonstrated below). I found that this made it more likely for me to utilise my notes, which in turn has saved me a lot of time. I tend to use my notes throughout the day so I found myself needing a means to access them quickly. This is when I made a script. Utilising &lt;code&gt;fd&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;fzf&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;xargs&lt;/code&gt; I can now search my notes directory and start taking notes at any given time. It is working really well so far and combined with Neovim I am able to swap between notes files without leaving the comfort of the Neovim editor. If I had to put a number to it I would say that this has saved me at least half an hour a week, which is pretty good for a single line shell command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the schema:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$HOME/Documents/Notes/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 1/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TODO.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 2/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TODO.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 3/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject 3.1/
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notes.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;todo.md&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjects can be related to a given category of things such as music, food, hobbies, etc or used as a means of categorising further sub-categories of related notes. A lot of these notes files are checklists. I love checklists and while I could use the markdown format of a checklist, that isn&amp;rsquo;t really needed as I tend to delete entries from checklists when they have been met so I don&amp;rsquo;t have a giant list of stuff I no longer need to take note of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These notes can be synced between devices using &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;syncthing&lt;/code&gt; but I have had no need to implement this due to maintaining a paper notebook as my main means of notetaking. Anything important enough to need to access it on the go is already on paper and I take it with me everywhere anyway. I maintain and use a paper notebook for most of my note taking. I transfer my written notes to this system to index them. The way that I take notes in my paper notebooks is different and will maybe get it&amp;rsquo;s own post at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-it-simple-stupid&#34;&gt;Keep It Simple, Stupid!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While talking to a friend about this subject they mentioned that they use software specifically designed for this purpose, which I found odd since notes are just text files. They told me about Obsidian, a graphical markdown text editor that connects notes together with links and has plugin support and all kinds of bloated features that you do not need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a monolithic solution to something as simple as note taking is rather funny to think about. Especially when it offers nothing useful on top of its main feature i.e. being a notebook on your computer. A lot of these software applications have popped up over the years and yet none of them have offered anything unique or useful. I remember my university pushing Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s OneNote as the perfect note taking solution as if a text file or document file wouldn&amp;rsquo;t suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the one argument in favour of these tools that I see repeated most often. That being that they support some form of sync between devices. This is not a unique feature either, syncing files between devices is easily done. Cloud storage exists already for people that don&amp;rsquo;t want a DIY solution, sync tools exist for those that do. Including a file sync that is proprietary to the notes editor is a clear case of inventing problems to sell a solution. It is fundamentally worse in all regards than utilising tools that already exist for this purpose. Monolithic design for the sake of self-justification in a note taking program is insanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest solutions are always the best, which is why I find this whole world of note taking software redundant. Any notes worth taking don&amp;rsquo;t need an entire suite of software to handle. Just write it down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working on a few project recently and thought I would give an update to what they are and how they are coming along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;migrating-from-vim-to-neovim&#34;&gt;Migrating from Vim to Neovim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty self explanatory, Vim has served me well over the years but having to maintain my config in vimscript and trying to manage packages and plugins for it is too much work for what I get out of it. As such I have chosen to move to Neovim and start using it. My progress with this can be tracked on my dotfiles repo if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-platform-dotfile-management&#34;&gt;Cross platform dotfile management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use multiple systems for my computing needs, GNU+Linux for my desktops, servers, ThinkPads and MacOS for my Mac. There are differences between these two that require micro-management and changes when deploying dotfiles as such I have chosen to start modelling a new way of managing my dotfiles. For now this is in the planning stages and will be rolled out as I see fit and implement my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-website-design&#34;&gt;New website design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is my little space on the internet where I scream into the void. It&amp;rsquo;s great being able to post and publish things and share them around and get feedback, etc. One of my favourite parts of being in control of this website is that I can post and publish what I would like. However the issue of organising the content on the site has come to my attention recently. The cookbook section should be it&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;website&amp;rdquo; within the same domain for example. Categories and tags should be more distinct, sorting things by year on the index pages doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me either. As such I plan to make a few design changes to the website over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently these are the changes I plan to make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categorise content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookbook migrated to it&amp;rsquo;s own website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New content types (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimise image usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social&amp;rdquo; links 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-content&#34;&gt;New content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to expand the content that I write on this site to include things I would like to write about but didn&amp;rsquo;t think would suit the site in its current design. Now that I will be changing the design that excuse is no longer valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New content may include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More guides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to reviews, I came to the conclusion that writing about the music I listen to or the video games I play or the books I read could be useful to some people. After all I do seem to be asked quite frequently about what I think about a given product or band, etc. I would also like to review some of the camping gear I have acquired recently as this information is useful in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bots-are-fun&#34;&gt;Bots are fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been developing a bot that I intend to use as a means to bridge various platforms together that I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or patience to manually keep up to date with. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be great, it is a personal project intended to teach me how to interact with APIs and other tool sets. But it is a fun little project so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brewing&#34;&gt;Brewing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making my own wine, beer and cider has been a great hobby so far and I having been gaining a lot more experience with it. Learning the various ways that different ingredients interact, which yeast to use, how long to do things for and why. It is a great hobby and doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of time to do. Although the learning curve can be somewhat of an issue depending on what you plan to do. I plan to write about my experiences with brewing alcohol at some point but for now I just wanted to update that is an ongoing hobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;power-lifting&#34;&gt;Power lifting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have returned to the gym and have taken up a power lifting programming again. I have always enjoyed this sport and intend to last a lot longer at it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about everything. Thanks for reading and if you are interested in anything I have mentioned feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Against CDNs</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/against-cdns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content Delivery Networks or CDNs for short are a common means for sourcing libraries and frameworks into a web page without having to provide a local copy on the server. It helps cut down on bandwidth and resource usage when serving web content. Which sounds like a great deal for the webmaster. To be fair, it pretty much is a great deal but only for the webmaster and the CDN provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When clients connect to a website and pull JQuery or Bootstrap or some other framework from a CDN instead of the web server serving the page contents they are being tracked. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a very good deal for the user. CDN data can be used to track users around the web without the use of cookies, just by requesting the library from a CDN you are providing an awful lot of metadata without knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why it is important to minimize your exposure to sites and services that use these. Of course that means 90% of the web is probably no longer usable. It is important to be smart about it at the least. Should you use social media websites such as Facebook they already know who you are, the frameworks they use are served by them too. Your exposure to request tracking doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter in this scenario since you are already using Facebook. Which you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use if you value your privacy. Although it is possible to use Facebook without exposing your web usage to them, that is for another post, another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s say for example you like to read web blogs like mine. Hopefully they serve those frameworks, etc from their own server. You should check to be sure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blog is served entirely in static HTML and CSS documents so there is no frameworks being loaded at all. However I encourage that you check right now anyway. After all I could be lying (I&amp;rsquo;m not).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find that a blog you enjoy reading is using CDNs to serve frameworks, libraries, etc to your browser consider asking the admin to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Git Etiquette</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/an-introduction-to-git-etiquette/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/an-introduction-to-git-etiquette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git Etiquette is an interesting subject and one that I found myself having to teach my classmates often. Which I enjoyed because teaching is the greatest way to learn. (Apparently)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply it is the practice of standardising the way you manage your repo and how you communicate regarding things inside of the repo and generally for the purpose of making sure you don&amp;rsquo;t get conflicts, errors and other disasters that lead to development down time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I like to teach Git Etiquette is to introduce a schema and then give examples of how to operate within this schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;schema&#34;&gt;Schema&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical schema that was used on team projects at University was the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-diagram&#34; data-lang=&#34;diagram&#34;&gt;b-bug-name          |   Bug branches
doc-document-name   |   Documentation branches
f-feature-name      |   Feature branches
master              |   Master branch
t-test-name         |   Testing branches
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This allowed us to see at a glance what was going on in a branch without having to ask someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would then give examples of how to create branches, switch to them and back, give proper commit messages and other basic Git usage. The hour or so it takes to teach all of this at the start saves you immeasurable time later and keeps everyone happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;semi-automated-project-management&#34;&gt;Semi-Automated Project Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we made sure to use the GitHub issues tracker, personally I am not a fan of this but it was a reasonable compromise to make for the sake of the team&amp;rsquo;s comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merge and pull requests went through a two person verification stage to make sure we caught any issues before pulling them into the master branch. This was very effective. One developer would verify the contents of the commit and then escalate to the leader of his team or the project so that the users that could push to master was limited to those that were responsible for the project going smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an extremely effective means for us to keep everything flowing and smooth. With minor hiccups along the way when someone needed help with using Git as there are many people with zero experience of Git or similar software at University and not all Universities have classes on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-etiquette-and-you&#34;&gt;Git Etiquette and You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a good chance that only some, perhaps none of the above will be perfectly applicable to your project(s). That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, your schema and management rules must apply to the scope of your project after all. You may need more branch naming schemes than this, you may need more layers of verification. The important thing is to have a set of rules set out when you start so that events can flow into the desired workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPNs Are Not Private</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/vpns-are-not-private/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 07:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/vpns-are-not-private/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common misconception you will see repeated online is that VPNs make everything you do online &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo;. The people repeating this myth are unfortunate victims of advertising psyops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to VPNs having active advertising campaigns on television, they make outright claims in said advertisements that are simply untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be obvious that any product that can advertise itself on television doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually offer &amp;ldquo;privacy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; which of course they vaguely define and redefine as needed to sell you on their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPN services effectively have two main features and that&amp;rsquo;s it, anything beyond them is marketing. These are packet / protocol obfuscation and bypassing region locks or ISP blocking. Any claims to &amp;ldquo;privacy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; are poorly defined and assume that the user in question is an expert on internet protocols, fingerprinting, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can VPNs be used for privacy? Yes. Do VPNs offer privacy out of the box? No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, using a VPN service as is for all of your web traffic makes you easier to track as it is another piece of metadata that can be used to identify you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a VPN out of the box but then using it for everything tells every service you connect to that you are on a VPN, which VPN it is and that you use it for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some valid uses of a VPN service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bypassing your ISP / University network rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiding your IP address when using Peer To Peer services.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Such as torrents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bypassing a region lock for web content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide where you are if you decide to go abroad but continue to &amp;ldquo;work from home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are still valid uses for VPNs but for anything privacy or security related you need to know what you are doing. Otherwise you just make yourself a bigger target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPNs are useful tools and have valid uses, they can be used for privacy if you know what you are doing. Just be careful which one you pick and how you use it. Many VPN companies are owned by companies or in territories that are hostile to a free internet. Always research what you are buying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting an External Storage Device</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/encrypting-an-external-storage-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/encrypting-an-external-storage-device/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to keep backups of important data, it&amp;rsquo;s an even better idea to make sure only you can access them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a guide on how to encrypt an external storage device for use on a Linux system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-devices&#34;&gt;Storage Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide should be relatively universal for most external storage devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example I am assuming you know what kind of storage device is best for your use case and that you are using a NEW device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;color:red;&#34;&gt;Important Notice:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are using a device that you have used previously you may wish to securely wipe all data on it first. I do not have a guide for this at this time. I will update this post in the future if that changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need the following to follow this guide along:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer running a GNU/Linux operating system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An external storage device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;cryptsetup&lt;/code&gt; package installed.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name may vary based on distro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;encrypting-the-device&#34;&gt;Encrypting The Device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-find-your-devices-path&#34;&gt;1. Find your device&amp;rsquo;s path.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do so with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo fdisk -l
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The output of this command will list information about each storage device connected to your computer. Such as it&amp;rsquo;s total capacity in GiB units and the model number. You can use this information to determine which disk is the one you intend to write to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point forward I will be referring to this device as /dev/sdx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-set-up-partition-table&#34;&gt;2. Set up partition table.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most drives when purchased will come with the msdos partition table, you don&amp;rsquo;t need this for a Linux machine. The following command will change it to use the GPT partition table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo parted /dev/sdx mklabel gpt
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive now has the GPT partition table format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-creating-a-luks-device&#34;&gt;3. Creating a LUKS device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will now create the LUKS device. Using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksFormat /dev/sdx
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now it will ask you for a password and to confirm it. I assume you know how to choose a strong one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-mapping-the-device&#34;&gt;4. Mapping the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will now mount the device to the mapper. This allows us to use it like a normal storage device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will want to name the device at this stage, we will refer to your given name as DevName from here on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksOpen /dev/sdx DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The device is now available for usage as a normal storage device would be if it were unmounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-formatting-the-device&#34;&gt;5. Formatting the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage we will be formatting the device as the ext4 Linux format. To do that we run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo mkfs.ext4 /dev/mapper/DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The device now has the ext4 format and can be mounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mounting-the-device&#34;&gt;Mounting The Device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage you can mount the device the way you normally would an external device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your GUI file manager such as &lt;code&gt;pcmanfam&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;dolphin&lt;/code&gt; to open it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also do the following to open it using the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-repeat-step-4-above-mapping-the-device&#34;&gt;1. Repeat step 4 above. (Mapping the device)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can skip this if it is still mapped from earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-mount-the-drive&#34;&gt;2. Mount the drive.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now mount the device as you would normally do so for an external device via the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo mount /dev/mapper/DevName &amp;lt;/path/to/mount/point/&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;unmounting-the-device&#34;&gt;Unmounting the device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-unmounting-the-drive&#34;&gt;1. Unmounting the drive.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can unmount the drive using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo umount &amp;lt;/path/to/mount/point&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-unmapping-the-device&#34;&gt;2. Unmapping the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can unmap the device using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksClose DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now safely remove the device from the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you prefer to use a graphical file manager then you should use one.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact for external devices I recommend doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use other formats for the disk if you wish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating QR Codes for Crypto</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/generating-qr-codes-for-crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/generating-qr-codes-for-crypto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you run a blog or a website or have any kind of online presence then you should be accepting crypto donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not explain why you should accept crypto here because &lt;a href=&#34;https://landchad.net/crypto&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; exists. Please read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crypto-addresses&#34;&gt;Crypto Addresses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to use third party platforms to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you need is your address and you are good to go. In this example I will be assuming that you have custody of your crypto wallet(s) and don&amp;rsquo;t use fiat-crypto™️ platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example I will be using a Monero address but the same method will work for all cryptocurrencies that use a single-string address. Which &lt;a href=&#34;#tips&#34;&gt;all two&lt;/a&gt; of the important ones do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all you are going to want to know your Crypto receive address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should look like this for Monero: &lt;code&gt;87ukrCxsbK79rQbGwutzTmE4RDPiayn3xK5JT63iiSks5Q9TMCsXzUibXEea1q6x6ij6u2UDxzXpNBU5bP4u8Wz34esoLRG&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly you are going to want to install the &lt;code&gt;python-qrcode&lt;/code&gt; package. It is available under this name on Arch and Debian based distros. It can also be &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/qrcode/&#34;&gt;found here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have these two tools you are ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;generating-the-qr-code&#34;&gt;Generating the QR code.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Input the following into your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;qr &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;lt;your crypto address&amp;gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; xmr.png
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Replacing &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;your crypto address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with your actual address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me this would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;qr &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;87ukrCxsbK79rQbGwutzTmE4RDPiayn3xK5JT63iiSks5Q9TMCsXzUibXEea1q6x6ij6u2UDxzXpNBU5bP4u8Wz34esoLRG&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; xmr.png
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will now have a png image file in your current directory. You can now use this on your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an example of it in use see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/donate&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-use-this-program&#34;&gt;Why Use This Program?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may be considering using an online QR code generator. But any code running on someone else&amp;rsquo;s hardware cannot be trusted with something as sensitive as this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an advanced user you can use this tool with optimisation options or you can output your QR code to an SVG instead. You can use this in combination with other QR code optimisation tools to minimize the file size if that is a concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only two cryptocurrencies actually matter these are Bitcoin and Monero. All other cryptos are gambling or memes (or a dangerous combination of both). &lt;strong&gt;Not financial advice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should always give the user the option to donate with the address itself too. In fact its a good idea to provide the address with the QR code so that they can verify the QR resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be a good idea to create a minimalist solution to allow the user to expand the page with the given QR codes if you plan to include them on other pages on your site. This is only relevant if your site doesn&amp;rsquo;t accommodate for this in its design anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Bloating Your Shell</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/stop-bloating-your-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/stop-bloating-your-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably my favourite part of using Linux is that I can customise my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The customisation options for some of the fundamental tools I use are endless and they are customisable by design. I have probably spent more time customising, modifying and tweaking my shell configurations than any other piece of software on my system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this article I will be using &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; as the example shell unless stated otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-shell-is-a-tool-not-a-toy&#34;&gt;A shell is a tool, not a toy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put the shell is a tool. Whether you are using it interactively or you are scripting tasks, you must use your shell correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the shell is a tool you should be more concerned with what it is for than how it looks. You should also be aware of the dangers of using it incorrectly and the dangers of misunderstanding it while using it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most shells support a form of regex which allows you to be as explicit or implicit as you need when creating a command to be run. The use of the &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; on its own in shell scripts should be avoided for this reason. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to accidentally delete your entire home folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-dont-need-plugin-managers&#34;&gt;You Don&amp;rsquo;t Need Plugin Managers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of plugin managers for a shell is peak soydev and a completely ridiculous concept, so why do so many people fall for it? The answer is simple, they are soydevs and do not understand the shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular plugin manager seems to be &lt;code&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/code&gt; for the &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; shell. It is nothing more than an obfuscated fronted for features that are built into &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt;. You do not need it to install anything. You can &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; these plugins manually in your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using these managers makes your shell take longer to load, adds unneeded complexity and causes problems if you want to do something outside of its scope. Not only that but it turns your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file into a complete and utter mess for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop using them, you don&amp;rsquo;t need them. It&amp;rsquo;s lazy and encourages bad practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-your-own-plugins&#34;&gt;Make your own plugins!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have a ridiculous number of aliases? Would you prefer not to scroll through them? You can make these into their own plugin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above with how to load a plugin you simply need to source the plugin file. Plugin files for &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; are actually just &lt;code&gt;.zsh&lt;/code&gt; files and you can make your own. All you need to do is place your aliases in a new file, place the file somewhere appropriate, ensure that the file&amp;rsquo;s shebang is correct: &lt;code&gt;#!/bin/zsh&lt;/code&gt; and then source that file in the .zshrc file like so:
&lt;code&gt;source /path/to/new/alias/plugin.zsh 2&amp;gt;/dev/null&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally don&amp;rsquo;t do this with my aliases and would recommend not doing so but this is a good example of how plugins work, they are just &lt;code&gt;.zsh&lt;/code&gt; scripts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aliasing-correctly&#34;&gt;Aliasing correctly.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliases are probably my favourite part of using the shell for most of my needs. You can ensure that a command such as &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; always uses colours, you can create adjacently named commands such as &lt;code&gt;ll&lt;/code&gt; for example to run &lt;code&gt;ls -l&lt;/code&gt; when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally you can bind scripts and long and complicated single line commands to a single word for ease of use. For example I use &lt;code&gt;dotfiles&lt;/code&gt; for managing my dotfiles git repository, I have some scripts that I also like to invoke for things such as checking for updates from all programs on my system, checking crypto prices, etc that I can do with a single word instead of writing the full file path. Although I do I keep these scripts in my &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; I use a naming convention that makes it easier to tell what script it is but it is easier to just invoke them with an alias instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing you should not do with aliases however is use them to replace a program. It is bad practice to &amp;ldquo;rename&amp;rdquo; a core program such as &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; with an alternative you found online. You should instead be using this tool by its name so that you are aware of what you are doing. Using aliases to obfuscate what you are doing is dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shebang&#34;&gt;Shebang&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shebang (shell bang) is used to ensure that the correct shell language is used when a file is run. For example &lt;code&gt;#!/bin/sh&lt;/code&gt; would be used if a script is POSIX compliant only and uses no Non-POSIX commands. For example if you write a script in &lt;code&gt;BASH&lt;/code&gt; and it uses bashisms, then your shebang should be &lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/code&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting the shebang in your scripts correctly means that when you invoke them from another shell the correct shell program is used to interpret the script. There are tools for testing your shell scripts so that you know what shebang to use, what adjustments to make to use, etc. I personally quite like &lt;code&gt;shellcheck&lt;/code&gt; but there are other options out there. However you should not rely on these tools and should be familiar with the commands you are using and how they work before committing them to a script. You can always check their man pages or other documentation before you commit to their use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally all scripts should be POSIX compliant only, bashisms are very tempting to use as they do give you more options for your script but there is a good chance you just do not need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;remote-shells&#34;&gt;Remote Shells&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you connect to other devices using a tool like &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; then you should ensure that the remote user&amp;rsquo;s shell config is configured correctly for this. A few examples of what not to do are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invocation of programs with &lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt; returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard declaring terminal (and emulator) compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting background processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-recommendations&#34;&gt;Additional recommendations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When declaring your &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; variable you should do so explicitly, it may seem fun to use a script to do this but that is additional startup logic that you do not need and a script that you now need to maintain. Additionally you should not be declaring the &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; in your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file it should be declared in your &lt;code&gt;.zprofile&lt;/code&gt; file so that your application launcher (assuming dmenu) is &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of using a script that iterates through all the sub-directories of your &lt;code&gt;.local/bin/&lt;/code&gt; directory just declare them like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;export PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;$HOME&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;/.local/bin/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;export PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;$HOME&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;/.local/bin/go&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;export PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PATH&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;$HOME&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;/.local/bin/sh&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This example is from my &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; file, which you can find here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/wdunkelheit/dotfiles/-/blob/master/.config/zsh/.zshrc&#34;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-process&#34;&gt;Learning process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, using the shell is a learning process. The more you use it and tinker with it they more you will learn. Feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; about this subject if you would like help or would like to correct anything I have said.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emacs Rabbit Hole</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/the-emacs-rabbit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/the-emacs-rabbit-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using Emacs as my text editor for about a year now. I still have no idea what I am doing but at least I know why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cosy-and-powerful&#34;&gt;Cosy and Powerful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Emacs client is very lightweight and it can be self-extended whilst running by using Elisp. I am not quite sure how it works as Elisp is too far down the rabbit hole and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been there yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emacs is very modular to the point that you can use it as an entire operating system if you so choose. It can be used as a windowing manager, a web browser, an email client. Not bad for a text editor right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some believe that this makes Emacs monolithic but that is due to a misconception that Emacs itself is doing all of these things and not the independent Elisp and C programs running within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few days ago I learned that you can run Emacs as a server, I don&amp;rsquo;t even know what purpose this would have but it sounds cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vim-gang&#34;&gt;Vim gang&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to using Emacs I used Vim as my editor of choice. I still do for single file editing. I love the Vim keybindings, macros, instruction language, etc. So when I heard that you can use these in Emacs with Evil mode I decided to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-year-later&#34;&gt;One Year Later&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I have found to be the most impressive about Emacs after a year of use is how it just &amp;ldquo;works&amp;rdquo; in a minimalist way. There&amp;rsquo;s no bells and whistles, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to use my mouse for anything. Once it has been launched it is ready to go, my way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use Evil mode in Emacs and it is indistinguishable from using Vim in a terminal except I am no longer held back by any limitations built into a given terminal emulator. At first I missed being unable to use Alt key for quick normal mode instructions but I have since rebound my keyboard to be more Emacs compatible and find the Emacs way of doing things more intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have yet to try Emacs tools such as &lt;code&gt;magit&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;rmail&lt;/code&gt; but this is mostly due to wanting to wait until I learn Emacs properly. Speaking of which&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;taking-off-the-training-wheels&#34;&gt;Taking off the training wheels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to learn Emacs from scratch, as it stands for the last year I have not been using Emacs &amp;ldquo;correctly&amp;rdquo; in the sense that I haven&amp;rsquo;t been using it in a way that allows me to learn how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using an Emacs &amp;ldquo;rice&amp;rdquo; named &lt;code&gt;Doom Emacs&lt;/code&gt;. Which is effectively a glorified interface for package management that handles all of the initial setup of the packages that come with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is to learn the intricacies of Emacs configuration, how to correctly use Org mode for documentation and organisation and create an Emacs build that only has what I need and want in it. My hope is that by doing so I will learn more of the intricacies of Emacs and will be able to use it more effectively and maybe start writing my own Elisp extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-know&#34;&gt;In The Know&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that my experience of learning Emacs from scratch will be interesting enough to some people that I may blog about it a bit. I am not sure whether I will do so by updating this post or by making new posts regarding a specific topic, etc I want to talk about. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Dont Care If You Use Linux</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have seen my previous post about Free (as in freedom) software and came to the conclusion that I want to &amp;ldquo;convert&amp;rdquo; normies to using Linux. This is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not care if you use Linux or not, I do not care what distro you use either. Whatever works for you, works for you and that&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I recommend that you use a Linux based OS is not that I personally gain from you doing so but that you will gain from it. I have no attachment to what you use or how you use it. Linux fanboyism is a ridiculous concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-confusion&#34;&gt;Further Confusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the &amp;ldquo;What Does The Steam Deck mean?&amp;rdquo; post, someone read it and completely misunderstood it. They were under the impression that I wish to &amp;ldquo;convert&amp;rdquo; gamers to Linux. LOL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had intended to delete that post for being crap anyway, which I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point I was trying to make could be made in a sentence but I tried to give too much context. So I will make my point here and consider the issue resolved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Steam Deck will put more eyes on Linux as a gaming platform. It will not convert the masses to a new operating system that they have no apparent need for. This will not benefit me, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way let&amp;rsquo;s get to the main point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-dont-care-bro&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Care Bro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put if you don&amp;rsquo;t use Linux I don&amp;rsquo;t care and more importantly, if you do use Linux I don&amp;rsquo;t care either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have absolutely no need to know or care for what operating system you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-consumer-issue&#34;&gt;The Consumer Issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of Linux consumerism has reached its twilight, we now live in a world where people wear Tux t-shirts unironically and discuss their desktop environment of choice as if it is their favourite sportsball team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a Linux consumer? A Linux™️ consumer is someone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Linux because they want a Unix like free software operating system, they are just anti-Windows and use Linux as if it were Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I estimate that about 60-70% of people with a Linux based OS on their personal computer would fall under the category of a Linux consumer and as I stated above. I don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical example is someone that installs whatever meme distro they were shilled then goes on to use Google and Microsoft services, integrating them into every level of their workflow and consumption cycles. It really is an impressive example of cognitive dissonance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consuming Linux is a mindset that I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or patience to entertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put if you need to attach part of your identity to the operating system that you use, you need to get a life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;converting-normies&#34;&gt;Converting Normies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is simply not an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only benefit a normie will get from switching to Linux is that their 5 year old laptop won&amp;rsquo;t run to a halt and can still get security patches. The real normie operating system is Google Chrome after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t care about software, ethics, etc. They use their computer to write their homework, read their emails, watch cat videos and buy junk from Amazon. They are content and happy if they can do this, you won&amp;rsquo;t convince them to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youre-just-an-elitist&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re just an elitist!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/yeschad.webp&#34; style=&#34;height:120px; margin:auto; display:block&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; &#34;&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free As In Freedom</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Libre, not gratis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the specifics of Free Software in this article, if you would like to know more check the &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34;&gt;references&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;freedom-is-non-negotiable&#34;&gt;Freedom is non-negotiable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;memeright&#34; src=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/freedom.webp&#34; alt=&#34;GNU Pepe&#34; title=&#34;GNU Pepe&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your freedom as a user is the most important aspect of the software that you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common phrase found online regarding services such as search engines and email service providers goes something like &amp;ldquo;if it&amp;rsquo;s free then you are the product&amp;rdquo;. This is a fairly good summary as it implies (accurately) that these service providers see &lt;strong&gt;YOU&lt;/strong&gt; as an extension of their property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with this statement is the implication that software that is paid for will respect your rights. This is of course not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution to this problem is straightforward. Don&amp;rsquo;t use them. I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting a boycott (boycotts don&amp;rsquo;t work lol) I am actually just suggesting that you opt out and choose to use Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-a-change&#34;&gt;Make a change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant services you can change are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office Suite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also drop social media and streaming services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem daunting to have to switch all of your service providers but you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do it all at once. In fact if you do it slowly over time that is perfectly fine. You may find that you have to do so anyway if you keep on top of sanitising your email inbox, have ongoing projects or need access to a given social media platform to stay in contact with family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the latter case you may wish to get them onboard with switching to Free Software and Libre services too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every proprietary service you currently use likely has a Free Software equivalent. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t then you probably never needed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;regarding-video-games-and-drm&#34;&gt;Regarding Video Games and DRM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video games are almost always proprietary. If you want to play them there are ways to do so on Linux including native Linux binaries. However for those that don&amp;rsquo;t have native binaries you may experience issues with their &amp;ldquo;Anti-Cheat&amp;rdquo; or DRM. I recommend just not buying games that have intrusive layers like that in the first place, it is unacceptable for these companies to treat customers this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay away from streaming services like Netflix and Spotify. Buy an SD card instead, store your music on that and stick it in your phone. Streaming services take your money and give you nothing in return, you do not own what you &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo; they are ripping you off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-be-fooled&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Source and Free Software are not the same thing and whilst many Open Source programs would fit the definition of Free Software in practice this is not true of all Open Source programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the popular editing suite Visual Studio Code is not free software due to its inclusion of anti-features such as telemetry and centralisation of integrated services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is Telegram, the client software uses a modified GPL3 that makes it non-free and the server software is completely proprietary. Telegram is fundamentally no different from using WhatsApp in terms of user freedoms and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common misconception is that Android devices are &amp;ldquo;Free&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo; but this couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from the truth. Out of the box these devices do not run Free Software or Open Source software. They run proprietary builds of a semi-open source project but the closed source proprietary nature of the out of the box device makes it a non-free device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these devices can be modified with Free and Open Source Android forks such as LineageOS and GrapheneOS. With GrapheneOS being the superior choice if you own a Google Pixel device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;im-happy-to-help&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like advice or some pointers or if you would like to discuss the topics discussed here feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will likely publish articles on switching services in the future so make sure to subscribe to the RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html&#34;&gt;What is Free Software? | GNU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/why-i-use-the-gpl-and-not-cuck-licenses&#34;&gt;Why I Use the GPL and Not Cuck Licenses | Luke Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free As In Freedom: Richard Stallman&amp;rsquo;s Crusade For Free Software, Sam Williams - ISBN-13: 978-0-59-600287-4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS is Based!</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/rss-is-based/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 08:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/rss-is-based/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started using Newsboat for RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a proper RSS setup has been on my &amp;ldquo;cosy setup&amp;rdquo; checklist for a while. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take much time at all to get it working either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously just used browser plug-ins for this however this approach is terrible in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a proper setup using Newsboat I can truly appreciate RSS feeds and I would recommend using them to anyone that wants to keep up to date with things without engaging with social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-rss&#34;&gt;What is RSS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSS is an abbreviation of Really Simple Syndication, although this isn&amp;rsquo;t it&amp;rsquo;s original name. Put simply it is a way for you to download a feed from a website and keep up to date with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that instead of using intrusive and manipulated social media feeds to keep up to date with your favourite web feeds you can have it all in one place on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may in fact already be using RSS without realising it. Did you know that most podcast apps are just RSS readers with a media player?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using RSS you can completely replace the need for a Google account to keep up to date with your favourite YouTube channels. Although adding YouTube channels to an RSS feed isn&amp;rsquo;t as straightforward as blogs or podcasts it is doable and once you have done it once the process is quickly repeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One small caveat to this is that YouTube can choose to eliminate RSS feeds at any time so it may be worth keeping a separate list of channels you subscribe to for the inevitable third party solution that pops up (or perhaps already exists? 👀 Let me know please) if this situation were to arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-rss&#34;&gt;Why use RSS?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Censorship Resistant:&lt;/strong&gt; You get what you subscribed to, no manipulation by algorithms or loss of access based on social media account status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convenience:&lt;/strong&gt; Every feed you care for in one place, in whatever order you want, categorised, tagged, etc however you see fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalist:&lt;/strong&gt; No need for accounts or web services. Just a list, add or remove as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portable:&lt;/strong&gt; You can read the feeds using any client you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy:&lt;/strong&gt; RSS just loads an XML file from a web server, there is no tracking, JavaScript, middleman services, etc. You get the feed sent directly to you without the need to identify yourself (beyond IP requirements).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-i-get-started&#34;&gt;How do I get started?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get started by downloading an RSS client. I recommend the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;newsboat&lt;/code&gt; - CLI client, highly configurable and easy to configure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;liferea&lt;/code&gt; - GUI client, highly configurable graphical client, uses GTK+ theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These can be found in your distro&amp;rsquo;s package manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you have a client you can start adding your favourite feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add feeds as you go, doing it all at once can be an exhaustive exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a site doesn&amp;rsquo;t natively support RSS you will likely find a tool that can create a feed for you instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some sites provide feeds for specific topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the documentation for your chosen client if you need help configuring it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
