<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts on Dunkelheit</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Dunkelheit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>XMPP Available</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/xmpp-available.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/xmpp-available.html</guid>
      <description>XMPP chatting is now available.
You can contact me at w@dunkelheit.biz
Registration is not available at this time. I would recommend that you host your own XMPP service anyway.
You can learn how to host your own XMPP server at landchad.net or by watching this video by Mental Outlaw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free As In Freedom</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/free-as-in-freedom.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/free-as-in-freedom.html</guid>
      <description>Libre, not gratis.
I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the specifics of Free Software in this article, if you would like to know more check the references at the bottom of the page.
Freedom is non-negotiable Your freedom as a user is the most important aspect of the software that you use.
A common phrase found online regarding services such as search engines and email service providers goes something like &amp;ldquo;if it&amp;rsquo;s free then you are the product&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the Steam Deck mean?</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/what-does-the-steam-deck-mean.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/what-does-the-steam-deck-mean.html</guid>
      <description>Valve recently announced their latest hardware product, the Steam Deck. A handheld &amp;ldquo;gaming PC&amp;rdquo; similar in shape and function to a Nintendo Switch except it isn&amp;rsquo;t a locked down OS. In fact it will be running the new SteamOS which apparently is now based on Arch Linux as opposed to the previous Debian based attempts.
A lot of Linux users are showing interest in the device, which is understandable given it is a unique product in the Linux space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS is Based!</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/rss-is-based.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 08:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/rss-is-based.html</guid>
      <description>I recently started using Newsboat for RSS.
Getting a proper RSS setup has been on my &amp;ldquo;cozy setup&amp;rdquo; checklist for a while. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take much time at all to get it working either.
I previously just used browser plug-ins for this however this approach is terrible in practice.
Now that I have a proper setup using Newsboat I can truly appreciate RSS feeds and I would recommend using them to anyone that wants to keep up to date with things without engaging with social media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Markdown Format</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/switching-to-markdown-format.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/switching-to-markdown-format.html</guid>
      <description>I am starting to get comfortable with hugo as a static site generator, I know I haven&amp;rsquo;t made my theme the &amp;ldquo;correct way&amp;rdquo; but for now it works to an acceptable minimum and most importantly the pages it produces are formatted perfectly.
I had an issue in that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide if I wanted to use Markdown or HTML when writing blog posts. The issue may seem silly (it is) but my reasons for having it were pretty straight forward:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning German</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/learning-german.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/learning-german.html</guid>
      <description>I have decided to learn German. I have always had an interest in learning another language but due to the terrible methodology used by the education system and cringe meme apps like DuoLingo I was never motivated enough to stick them out. However I recently came to discover the Michel Thomas method after reading these articles by Luke Smith: Notes on Learning Languages and Learning European Languages (Michel Thomas). I won&amp;rsquo;t bother to sumamrize them here but you should definetely read them if you are interested in learning a language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Games Are Over</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/video-games-are-over.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.biz/blog/2021/video-games-are-over.html</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Modern video games are an industrialised product that satisfies checklists at the cost of a unique identity and product. They are deceptively marketted and maliciously monetized.
Occasionally a video game will come out that is just trying to be a fun video game. These are few and far between.
This is not a nostalgia post, modern video games are genuinely terrible.
Why do they suck? The simple answer and the correct one is: money.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
