<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>food on Dunkelheit Citizen</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in food on Dunkelheit Citizen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cookbook Now Live</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/cookbook-now-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is now live. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/recipes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a separate RSS feed from the one for blog posts. You may need to adjust your existing RSS link as I made some changes to that on the back end. You can find the most up to date versions of the RSS links at the bottom of this page and on the cookbook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cookbook is a bit barren right now but I figured it was better have it public than not at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy cooking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About My Meme Diet</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/all-about-my-meme-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 17:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/all-about-my-meme-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been rereading the Unaboomer archives again and came across this &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/my-diet-following-the-memes/&#34;&gt;interesting post&lt;/a&gt; titled &amp;ldquo;My diet following the memes&amp;rdquo; and thought it was an interesting read. I recommend reading it if you get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading that post I wanted to make my own post in the same vein, which is this one you are reading now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diet-or-dogma&#34;&gt;Diet or Dogma?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In industrial societies people tend to find themselves identifying with meaningless labels and manmade dogmatic practices to feel unique. You will even find people identifying with silly things like soap brands, whichever soy beverage they consume and even what video game they play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of dogmatic diets out there, some like Paleo are closer to the mark than others. There are other similar meme diets such as Keto too which get the fundamentals right by rejecting the ridiculous food pyramid standard but then fall for the direct consequences of the food pyramid such as so called &amp;ldquo;nutrition facts&amp;rdquo; labels and the promotion of factory farmed imported foodstuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of this is many people that have just been introduced to the Keto diet and lazy adherents to it will consider seed oils a perfectly healthy &amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo; to consume as it has the right macros according to the label. That label is lying of course there are no fats in there, only plant oils. These oils are produced using a highly industrialised and mechanical process involving petroleum byproducts and acetone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, at least they get the premise right and if they are coming from the standard Euro-American diet then they are still likely improving their health despite these mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for Keto adherents they do reject the food pyramid and are generally more willing to listen when you have advice to give and generally willing to do at least some research of their own, even if it is second hand research like watching a YouTube video explaining these concepts in normie friendly terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are &amp;ldquo;diets&amp;rdquo; that are more or less a suicidal death cult. You know which one it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-diet&#34;&gt;My Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried most of these meme diets: Keto, Paleo, Carnivore, etc. They all get the fundamentals right: high fat, high protein. But it isn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as that. Protein from a plant is not the same and is not comparable at all to protein from an animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the memes, what do I do now? I eat the natural human diet of course. Animal products, nose to tail, dairy, eggs. Raw, rare, cooked, stewed, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t eat bread or other slave foods unless I am eating out with friends or family and I really want to have a burger or something, which is still a meal that contains a lot of animal products. I enjoy fruits that are in season and native to the local soil, I avoid green vegetables and use carrots, potatoes, etc instead but in limited amounts as they are not sustainable for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-natural-human-diet&#34;&gt;On The Natural Human Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural human diet consisted of raw meat, fish, perennial fruits and mushrooms. If I was raised in an environment where this wasn&amp;rsquo;t presented as &amp;ldquo;disgusting&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;savage&amp;rdquo; then I would likely be able to adapt to doing it for the entirety of my diet. I would probably enjoy this kind of diet if I was able to break the mental barrier, which is why I include raw meats and organs, dairy and eggs in my diet where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I like my steak? Rare with butter and sauteed mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
