<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Dunkelheit</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Dunkelheit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun Is Trad</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/having-fun-is-trad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has come to my attention that e-trads have been crusading against fun. Interestingly they do so on the Internet, which is a curious choice of battleground for such a subject. I have absolutely no idea why they are doing this or what they think they will achieve. The most confusing detail of this trend is that having fun is in fact trad so what&amp;rsquo;s with the intentional friendly fire?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days people either treat fun as a part of everyday life (which it is), as an excuse to waste their time (addiction cope) or as an evil to be conquered (the cringe take). It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly strange to see the latter take from people that call themselves &amp;rsquo;traditionalists&amp;rsquo; as these are the very same people that strive to return to some kind of societal normality. In normal societies people had fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History is full of examples of people having fun, be it feasting with friends and neighbors or dancing around a fire or in a ballroom. One could argue that these traditional forms of fun don&amp;rsquo;t exist anymore, they would be wrong of course. Quite commonly you will find if you try hard to look in the first place that there are plenty of opportunities to do these things already and if that somehow yields zero results for you then the problem is that you aren&amp;rsquo;t organising it yourself. However this doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain the aversion to fun that a lot of trads seem to have developed recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the real problem that some of these people have isn&amp;rsquo;t people having fun, it&amp;rsquo;s the ways that people have fun. Particularly the habit forming excesses of it that lead to a loss of enjoyment but an addictive desire that compels participation when any joy to be found is already dead. So is the issue that fun is bad or that having fun is no longer fun? I&amp;rsquo;d wager it&amp;rsquo;s the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of habit forming fun is video games, they are formulaic in design, particularly to extract as much of your time as possible. Where is the fun to be found when these video games become a part time (or even a full time) job? If you have to commit yourself to something that used to be possible to just pick up and play you will find yourself drained of enjoyment very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major problem with people playing video games is excess. People play them way too much, they revolve their lives around them until they stop being fun and become a chore. They play these video games alone in their bedroom for hours or even days at a time in some cases and what do they get out of it? An ever decreasing dopamine rush when the shiny and sparkly effects flare off when you do the same chore (and that is what a lot of video game content is these days) for the thousandth time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with having some fun on your own of course, I find myself enjoying a book quite often. Books are trad right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not just video games that masquerade as fun whilst in actual fact being nothing more than addictive distraction. Television, YouTube, TikTok, etc all fulfill this role as well. Since consumption of these is entirely passive the victims of addiction don&amp;rsquo;t even need to think about anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s make a distinction between fun and distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is when you enjoy yourself. A distraction is when you occupy your time. To quote anti-gambling PSAs &amp;ldquo;when the fun stops STOP!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t owe distractions any of your time, that time belong to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally when someone had free time they spent it with other people, or learning a new skill, reading a book or just getting in some extra rest. Fun was enjoyable in the moment and benefited you in some way as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun is an ancient and primordial experience that has been twisted and turned into a control mechanism, you can reject it any time you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t have fun playing video games, or watching YouTube, etc but you have to be aware that they are built on algorithms and design standards to keep you engaged with them and not with something else. Time is money and they are draining you of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a bare minimum if you want to have fun find a hobby. Dedicate time to it every week, if after a while you don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it then find a new one. Repeat this until you are having fun. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for the trap of wasting time to pass time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your grandfathers went to the pub, the tavern and the mead hall on Thunorsday. You sit on a couch. Who do you think had more fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem isn&amp;rsquo;t fun, the problem is a lack of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Path in Life</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from my Computer Science degree program. I did not enjoy my time on this degree as much as I had hoped when I started. Computers were my passion at one point in the past, but not so much any more. I still enjoy using the skills I developed and researching the industry out of curiousity. Ultimately though I pushed through to finish what I started and was glad when it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am a free man and I am going back into academia to study a completely different field that I am actually passionate for: Archaeology and History. Specifically Celtic and Anglo-Saxon history. Which is the field that I have always wanted to study but was misled by well-meaning and sincere concern over &amp;ldquo;employability&amp;rdquo; regarding such a subject. Personally I am not too concerned with the employability of such a degree. Afterall I was led to believe that CompSci would make me a millionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to write about my time on this degree as the subjects themselves are very fascinating but the way that they flow between each other by coincidence is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Dont Care If You Use Linux</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have seen my previous post about Free (as in freedom) software and came to the conclusion that I want to &amp;ldquo;convert&amp;rdquo; normies to using Linux. This is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not care if you use Linux or not, I do not care what distro you use either. Whatever works for you, works for you and that&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I recommend that you use a Linux based OS is not that I personally gain from you doing so but that you will gain from it. I have no attachment to what you use or how you use it. Linux fanboyism is a ridiculous concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;further-confusion&#34;&gt;Further Confusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the &amp;ldquo;What Does The Steam Deck mean?&amp;rdquo; post, someone read it and completely misunderstood it. They were under the impression that I wish to &amp;ldquo;convert&amp;rdquo; gamers to Linux. LOL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had intended to delete that post for being crap anyway, which I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point I was trying to make could be made in a sentence but I tried to give too much context. So I will make my point here and consider the issue resolved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Steam Deck will put more eyes on Linux as a gaming platform. It will not convert the masses to a new operating system that they have no apparent need for. This will not benefit me, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way let&amp;rsquo;s get to the main point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-dont-care-bro&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Care Bro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put if you don&amp;rsquo;t use Linux I don&amp;rsquo;t care and more importantly, if you do use Linux I don&amp;rsquo;t care either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have absolutely no need to know or care for what operating system you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-consumer-issue&#34;&gt;The Consumer Issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of Linux consumerism has reached its twilight, we now live in a world where people wear Tux t-shirts unironically and discuss their desktop environment of choice as if it is their favourite sportsball team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a Linux consumer? A Linux™️ consumer is someone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use Linux because they want a Unix like free software operating system, they are just anti-Windows and use Linux as if it were Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I estimate that about 60-70% of people with a Linux based OS on their personal computer would fall under the category of a Linux consumer and as I stated above. I don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical example is someone that installs whatever meme distro they were shilled then goes on to use Google and Microsoft services, integrating them into every level of their workflow and consumption cycles. It really is an impressive example of cognitive dissonance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consuming Linux is a mindset that I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or patience to entertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put if you need to attach part of your identity to the operating system that you use, you need to get a life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;converting-normies&#34;&gt;Converting Normies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is simply not an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only benefit a normie will get from switching to Linux is that their 5 year old laptop won&amp;rsquo;t run to a halt and can still get security patches. The real normie operating system is Google Chrome after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They don&amp;rsquo;t care about software, ethics, etc. They use their computer to write their homework, read their emails, watch cat videos and buy junk from Amazon. They are content and happy if they can do this, you won&amp;rsquo;t convince them to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;youre-just-an-elitist&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re just an elitist!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/i-dont-care-if-you-use-linux/yeschad.webp&#34; style=&#34;height:120px; margin:auto; display:block&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center; &#34;&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free As In Freedom</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Libre, not gratis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the specifics of Free Software in this article, if you would like to know more check the &lt;a href=&#34;#references&#34;&gt;references&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;freedom-is-non-negotiable&#34;&gt;Freedom is non-negotiable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;memeright&#34; src=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/free-as-in-freedom/freedom.webp&#34; alt=&#34;GNU Pepe&#34; title=&#34;GNU Pepe&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your freedom as a user is the most important aspect of the software that you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common phrase found online regarding services such as search engines and email service providers goes something like &amp;ldquo;if it&amp;rsquo;s free then you are the product&amp;rdquo;. This is a fairly good summary as it implies (accurately) that these service providers see &lt;strong&gt;YOU&lt;/strong&gt; as an extension of their property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with this statement is the implication that software that is paid for will respect your rights. This is of course not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution to this problem is straightforward. Don&amp;rsquo;t use them. I&amp;rsquo;m not suggesting a boycott (boycotts don&amp;rsquo;t work lol) I am actually just suggesting that you opt out and choose to use Free Software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-a-change&#34;&gt;Make a change&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant services you can change are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office Suite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also drop social media and streaming services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem daunting to have to switch all of your service providers but you don&amp;rsquo;t need to do it all at once. In fact if you do it slowly over time that is perfectly fine. You may find that you have to do so anyway if you keep on top of sanitising your email inbox, have ongoing projects or need access to a given social media platform to stay in contact with family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the latter case you may wish to get them onboard with switching to Free Software and Libre services too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every proprietary service you currently use likely has a Free Software equivalent. If it doesn&amp;rsquo;t then you probably never needed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;regarding-video-games-and-drm&#34;&gt;Regarding Video Games and DRM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video games are almost always proprietary. If you want to play them there are ways to do so on Linux including native Linux binaries. However for those that don&amp;rsquo;t have native binaries you may experience issues with their &amp;ldquo;Anti-Cheat&amp;rdquo; or DRM. I recommend just not buying games that have intrusive layers like that in the first place, it is unacceptable for these companies to treat customers this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay away from streaming services like Netflix and Spotify. Buy an SD card instead, store your music on that and stick it in your phone. Streaming services take your money and give you nothing in return, you do not own what you &amp;ldquo;stream&amp;rdquo; they are ripping you off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-be-fooled&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open Source and Free Software are not the same thing and whilst many Open Source programs would fit the definition of Free Software in practice this is not true of all Open Source programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the popular editing suite Visual Studio Code is not free software due to its inclusion of anti-features such as telemetry and centralisation of integrated services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is Telegram, the client software uses a modified GPL3 that makes it non-free and the server software is completely proprietary. Telegram is fundamentally no different from using WhatsApp in terms of user freedoms and privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common misconception is that Android devices are &amp;ldquo;Free&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Open Source&amp;rdquo; but this couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from the truth. Out of the box these devices do not run Free Software or Open Source software. They run proprietary builds of a semi-open source project but the closed source proprietary nature of the out of the box device makes it a non-free device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of these devices can be modified with Free and Open Source Android forks such as LineageOS and GrapheneOS. With GrapheneOS being the superior choice if you own a Google Pixel device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;im-happy-to-help&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like advice or some pointers or if you would like to discuss the topics discussed here feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will likely publish articles on switching services in the future so make sure to subscribe to the RSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html&#34;&gt;What is Free Software? | GNU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/why-i-use-the-gpl-and-not-cuck-licenses&#34;&gt;Why I Use the GPL and Not Cuck Licenses | Luke Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free As In Freedom: Richard Stallman&amp;rsquo;s Crusade For Free Software, Sam Williams - ISBN-13: 978-0-59-600287-4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
