<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 Archive on Dunkelheit Citizen</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 Archive on Dunkelheit Citizen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A New Path in Life</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from my Computer Science degree program. I did not enjoy my time on this degree as much as I had hoped when I started. Computers were my passion at one point in the past, but not so much any more. I still enjoy using the skills I developed and researching the industry out of curiousity. Ultimately though I pushed through to finish what I started and was glad when it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am a free man and I am going back into academia to study a completely different field that I am actually passionate for: Archaeology and History. Specifically Celtic and Anglo-Saxon history. Which is the field that I have always wanted to study but was misled by well-meaning and sincere concern over &amp;ldquo;employability&amp;rdquo; regarding such a subject. Personally I am not too concerned with the employability of such a degree. Afterall I was led to believe that CompSci would make me a millionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to write about my time on this degree as the subjects themselves are very fascinating but the way that they flow between each other by coincidence is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About My Meme Diet</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/all-about-my-meme-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 17:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/all-about-my-meme-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been rereading the Unaboomer archives again and came across this &lt;a href=&#34;https://lukesmith.xyz/articles/my-diet-following-the-memes/&#34;&gt;interesting post&lt;/a&gt; titled &amp;ldquo;My diet following the memes&amp;rdquo; and thought it was an interesting read. I recommend reading it if you get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading that post I wanted to make my own post in the same vein, which is this one you are reading now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diet-or-dogma&#34;&gt;Diet or Dogma?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In industrial societies people tend to find themselves identifying with meaningless labels and manmade dogmatic practices to feel unique. You will even find people identifying with silly things like soap brands, whichever soy beverage they consume and even what video game they play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of dogmatic diets out there, some like Paleo are closer to the mark than others. There are other similar meme diets such as Keto too which get the fundamentals right by rejecting the ridiculous food pyramid standard but then fall for the direct consequences of the food pyramid such as so called &amp;ldquo;nutrition facts&amp;rdquo; labels and the promotion of factory farmed imported foodstuffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good example of this is many people that have just been introduced to the Keto diet and lazy adherents to it will consider seed oils a perfectly healthy &amp;ldquo;food&amp;rdquo; to consume as it has the right macros according to the label. That label is lying of course there are no fats in there, only plant oils. These oils are produced using a highly industrialised and mechanical process involving petroleum byproducts and acetone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, at least they get the premise right and if they are coming from the standard Euro-American diet then they are still likely improving their health despite these mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for Keto adherents they do reject the food pyramid and are generally more willing to listen when you have advice to give and generally willing to do at least some research of their own, even if it is second hand research like watching a YouTube video explaining these concepts in normie friendly terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are &amp;ldquo;diets&amp;rdquo; that are more or less a suicidal death cult. You know which one it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-diet&#34;&gt;My Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried most of these meme diets: Keto, Paleo, Carnivore, etc. They all get the fundamentals right: high fat, high protein. But it isn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as that. Protein from a plant is not the same and is not comparable at all to protein from an animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve tried the memes, what do I do now? I eat the natural human diet of course. Animal products, nose to tail, dairy, eggs. Raw, rare, cooked, stewed, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t eat bread or other slave foods unless I am eating out with friends or family and I really want to have a burger or something, which is still a meal that contains a lot of animal products. I enjoy fruits that are in season and native to the local soil, I avoid green vegetables and use carrots, potatoes, etc instead but in limited amounts as they are not sustainable for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-natural-human-diet&#34;&gt;On The Natural Human Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The natural human diet consisted of raw meat, fish, perennial fruits and mushrooms. If I was raised in an environment where this wasn&amp;rsquo;t presented as &amp;ldquo;disgusting&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;savage&amp;rdquo; then I would likely be able to adapt to doing it for the entirety of my diet. I would probably enjoy this kind of diet if I was able to break the mental barrier, which is why I include raw meats and organs, dairy and eggs in my diet where possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I like my steak? Rare with butter and sauteed mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Git Etiquette</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/an-introduction-to-git-etiquette/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/an-introduction-to-git-etiquette/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Git Etiquette is an interesting subject and one that I found myself having to teach my classmates often. Which I enjoyed because teaching is the greatest way to learn. (Apparently)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply it is the practice of standardising the way you manage your repo and how you communicate regarding things inside of the repo and generally for the purpose of making sure you don&amp;rsquo;t get conflicts, errors and other disasters that lead to development down time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I like to teach Git Etiquette is to introduce a schema and then give examples of how to operate within this schema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;schema&#34;&gt;Schema&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical schema that was used on team projects at University was the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-diagram&#34; data-lang=&#34;diagram&#34;&gt;b-bug-name          |   Bug branches
doc-document-name   |   Documentation branches
f-feature-name      |   Feature branches
master              |   Master branch
t-test-name         |   Testing branches
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This allowed us to see at a glance what was going on in a branch without having to ask someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would then give examples of how to create branches, switch to them and back, give proper commit messages and other basic Git usage. The hour or so it takes to teach all of this at the start saves you immeasurable time later and keeps everyone happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;semi-automated-project-management&#34;&gt;Semi-Automated Project Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we made sure to use the GitHub issues tracker, personally I am not a fan of this but it was a reasonable compromise to make for the sake of the team&amp;rsquo;s comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merge and pull requests went through a two person verification stage to make sure we caught any issues before pulling them into the master branch. This was very effective. One developer would verify the contents of the commit and then escalate to the leader of his team or the project so that the users that could push to master was limited to those that were responsible for the project going smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an extremely effective means for us to keep everything flowing and smooth. With minor hiccups along the way when someone needed help with using Git as there are many people with zero experience of Git or similar software at University and not all Universities have classes on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;git-etiquette-and-you&#34;&gt;Git Etiquette and You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a good chance that only some, perhaps none of the above will be perfectly applicable to your project(s). That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, your schema and management rules must apply to the scope of your project after all. You may need more branch naming schemes than this, you may need more layers of verification. The important thing is to have a set of rules set out when you start so that events can flow into the desired workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPNs Are Not Private</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/vpns-are-not-private/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 07:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/vpns-are-not-private/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common misconception you will see repeated online is that VPNs make everything you do online &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo;. The people repeating this myth are unfortunate victims of advertising psyops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to VPNs having active advertising campaigns on television, they make outright claims in said advertisements that are simply untrue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be obvious that any product that can advertise itself on television doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually offer &amp;ldquo;privacy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; which of course they vaguely define and redefine as needed to sell you on their product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPN services effectively have two main features and that&amp;rsquo;s it, anything beyond them is marketing. These are packet / protocol obfuscation and bypassing region locks or ISP blocking. Any claims to &amp;ldquo;privacy&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;security&amp;rdquo; are poorly defined and assume that the user in question is an expert on internet protocols, fingerprinting, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can VPNs be used for privacy? Yes. Do VPNs offer privacy out of the box? No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, using a VPN service as is for all of your web traffic makes you easier to track as it is another piece of metadata that can be used to identify you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a VPN out of the box but then using it for everything tells every service you connect to that you are on a VPN, which VPN it is and that you use it for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some valid uses of a VPN service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bypassing your ISP / University network rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hiding your IP address when using Peer To Peer services.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Such as torrents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bypassing a region lock for web content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide where you are if you decide to go abroad but continue to &amp;ldquo;work from home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there are still valid uses for VPNs but for anything privacy or security related you need to know what you are doing. Otherwise you just make yourself a bigger target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VPNs are useful tools and have valid uses, they can be used for privacy if you know what you are doing. Just be careful which one you pick and how you use it. Many VPN companies are owned by companies or in territories that are hostile to a free internet. Always research what you are buying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Cares About Twitter?</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/who-cares-about-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/who-cares-about-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s a big deal that Elon Musk bought Twitter. Everyone seems to be competing for the worst take regarding it. Which means it must be the Current Thing™️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true based and red pilled position is as always &amp;ldquo;who cares?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter sucks, it always sucked, it will continue to suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk wants to &amp;ldquo;verify all humans&amp;rdquo;, this effectively means KYCAML for Twitter. Apparently his reasoning for buying Twitter is to secure free speech online or something. A laughable statement when combined with his proposed human verification efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a more free (as in freedom) alternative to Twitter then maybe look into Fediverse services such as Mastodon and Pleroma. Do your research before you join an instance of course. Many of them are more censorious than Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want a truly free instance then run your own, create your own rules, block instances that you don&amp;rsquo;t like, etc. You can learn how to host your own Pleroma instance with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs-develop.pleroma.social/backend/installation/otp_en/&#34;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt; or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://landchad.net/pleroma.html&#34;&gt;LandChad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting an External Storage Device</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/encrypting-an-external-storage-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 09:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/encrypting-an-external-storage-device/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to keep backups of important data, it&amp;rsquo;s an even better idea to make sure only you can access them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a guide on how to encrypt an external storage device for use on a Linux system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storage-devices&#34;&gt;Storage Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide should be relatively universal for most external storage devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this example I am assuming you know what kind of storage device is best for your use case and that you are using a NEW device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;color:red;&#34;&gt;Important Notice:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are using a device that you have used previously you may wish to securely wipe all data on it first. I do not have a guide for this at this time. I will update this post in the future if that changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need the following to follow this guide along:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer running a GNU/Linux operating system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An external storage device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;cryptsetup&lt;/code&gt; package installed.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name may vary based on distro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;encrypting-the-device&#34;&gt;Encrypting The Device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-find-your-devices-path&#34;&gt;1. Find your device&amp;rsquo;s path.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do so with the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo fdisk -l
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The output of this command will list information about each storage device connected to your computer. Such as it&amp;rsquo;s total capacity in GiB units and the model number. You can use this information to determine which disk is the one you intend to write to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this point forward I will be referring to this device as /dev/sdx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-set-up-partition-table&#34;&gt;2. Set up partition table.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most drives when purchased will come with the msdos partition table, you don&amp;rsquo;t need this for a Linux machine. The following command will change it to use the GPT partition table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo parted /dev/sdx mklabel gpt
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive now has the GPT partition table format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-creating-a-luks-device&#34;&gt;3. Creating a LUKS device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will now create the LUKS device. Using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksFormat /dev/sdx
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now it will ask you for a password and to confirm it. I assume you know how to choose a strong one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-mapping-the-device&#34;&gt;4. Mapping the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will now mount the device to the mapper. This allows us to use it like a normal storage device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will want to name the device at this stage, we will refer to your given name as DevName from here on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksOpen /dev/sdx DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The device is now available for usage as a normal storage device would be if it were unmounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-formatting-the-device&#34;&gt;5. Formatting the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage we will be formatting the device as the ext4 Linux format. To do that we run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo mkfs.ext4 /dev/mapper/DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The device now has the ext4 format and can be mounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mounting-the-device&#34;&gt;Mounting The Device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage you can mount the device the way you normally would an external device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use your GUI file manager such as &lt;code&gt;pcmanfam&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;dolphin&lt;/code&gt; to open it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also do the following to open it using the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-repeat-step-4-above-mapping-the-device&#34;&gt;1. Repeat step 4 above. (Mapping the device)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can skip this if it is still mapped from earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-mount-the-drive&#34;&gt;2. Mount the drive.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now mount the device as you would normally do so for an external device via the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo mount /dev/mapper/DevName &amp;lt;/path/to/mount/point/&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;unmounting-the-device&#34;&gt;Unmounting the device&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-unmounting-the-drive&#34;&gt;1. Unmounting the drive.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can unmount the drive using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo umount &amp;lt;/path/to/mount/point&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-unmapping-the-device&#34;&gt;2. Unmapping the device.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can unmap the device using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo cryptsetup luksClose DevName
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can now safely remove the device from the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you prefer to use a graphical file manager then you should use one.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact for external devices I recommend doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use other formats for the disk if you wish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
