<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Dunkelheit Citizen</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Dunkelheit Citizen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Hunt Challenge 2023</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/wild-hunt-challenge-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/wild-hunt-challenge-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Golden One issued his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e53MzSk3Jlc&#34;&gt;Wild Hunt challenge for 2023&lt;/a&gt; a while back and I intend to take part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge(s) for this year (like all years) are to make positive changes in your life by getting more organised, being more well read and improving your health. Of course the Glorious Lion&amp;rsquo;s challenge includes going to the gym. I will go over each challenge, my thoughts on them and how I intended to approach them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-one---notebook&#34;&gt;Challenge One - Notebook&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the challenge is probably the most important as it will assist with the remainder of the challenges as well as being immensely useful for everyday organisiation in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge is simple, get a notebook and use it. Particular instruction on how to use it was given which is pretty straightforward. Write down what you plan to day on each given day and tick them off as you go. You get a feeling of accomplishment as you do this and get to see how you progress, where improvements can be made and you can keep on top of things such that you don&amp;rsquo;t forget anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great start to the challenge, a fairly reasonable introductory step that prepares you for the rest. Not much to say about it other than it being useful for the rest of the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-two---read-a-book&#34;&gt;Challenge Two - Read A Book&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part two of the challenge is to read a book, the recommended text is The Golden One&amp;rsquo;s own book Dauntless: Wild Hunt Edition, which I intend to read for this challenge as I have been meaning to get around to reading it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When presenting this part of the challenge the suggestion of reading a classic is also given and this is used to explain the purpose of the challenge. Reading a book doesn&amp;rsquo;t just teach you what its contents are, it also teaches you the world view of the author, the writing style used, why the book was written and you may even develop an idea as to why someone would want to read the book. A great intellectual exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned I plan to read Dauntless for this challenge. I already own a copy, as an additional challenge I plan to review the book and give my thoughts on it. I will consider this part of the challenge complete when I do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-three---the-temple-of-iron&#34;&gt;Challenge Three - The Temple of Iron&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we have a challenge relating to The Temple of Iron, which if you are unfamiliar is a term that Gigachads use to refer to the gym. In particular the challenge is to adopt a schedule for the gym and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty straightforward, the purpose of this challenge is to instill discipline as well as to get you in the gym and lifting. Which is glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Golden One gives Smolov Jr. as an example of a schedule / routine but I plan to use Starting Strength as it is what I prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-four---meditation&#34;&gt;Challenge Four - Meditation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth part of the challenge is to start meditating, every day. Starting at ten minutes with a guided meditation method. The recommended routine is the Wim Hof routine. I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about it yet but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to take the advice and at least look into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much else to say here, I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about meditation to really comment on it at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;challenge-five---fasting&#34;&gt;Challenge Five - Fasting&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final challenge is to do a twenty four hour fast. There are many advantages to fasting, from appetite control, developing your discipline, autophagy and weight loss. There are many others but these are the four most common and most directly useful to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is likely to be the easiest part of the challenge for me as I already practice rolling fasting as a means of weight loss. I will say that it is very effective and if there are other benefits (there most certainly is) they will creep their way in. You aren&amp;rsquo;t going to wake up after your first fast to find all the benefits occurred overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend fasting alongside a ketogenic diet. Or at the very least a ketogenic protocol prior to the fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-approach&#34;&gt;My Approach&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is my appraoch or how I intend to approach each challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchases a nice Oxford Touch notebook featuring 90gsm paper. Perfect for writing on both sides of.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is nothing fancy about it really, it&amp;rsquo;s a normal notebook with no thrills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t see much point in getting anything nicer than this for keeping checklists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As mentioned above I will be reading Dauntless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting Strength is a great routine for building strength, I switch between it and StrongLifts every so often.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also add in significant cardio work as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will start off with the recommended Wim Hof routine and see how it goes.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only challenge I see being somewhat of a change of pace / new experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I already have at least a twenty four hour fast every week.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes I throw in a forty eight or seventy two hour fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not consent to calories!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have given a breakdown of the challenge and my thoughts on each part I have a few comments on the overall challenge to make. First and foremost, the combination of these challenges will have obvious benefits to most people. I highly recommend taking part. Additionally you can modify it or add your own challenges if you&amp;rsquo;d like. The idea behind this is to make your New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution more meaningful without calling it a New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution. That&amp;rsquo;s a cringe name, we aren&amp;rsquo;t making &amp;ldquo;resolutions&amp;rdquo; we are COMPETING in the WILD HUNT with our leader THE GLORIOUS LION!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will update this post occasionally with my thoughts on the challenges so far. Glory to those competing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blog Without Blogging</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this blog it was purely as an exercise in staking my e-claim on my e-land as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=3dIVesHEAzc&#34;&gt;meme at the time&lt;/a&gt; suggested. It was a fun exercise that let me refresh my knowledge of HTML and CSS and it led me to learn Hugo too and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting to this site whenever I feel like something I&amp;rsquo;ve written is worth posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much blogging, in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve done basically none at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to change that. The idea of writing a blog is appealing I&amp;rsquo;ve just never felt like I had anything interesting going on. I blame doing a CompSci degree for this though. Now that I am doing a degree that I actually want to do I have probably too much that I want to write down about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When last semester ended I planned to blog about my experience, what I thought of the various classes, the campus, the environment of the university in general but I never got around to it. So I will cover both semesters at the same time when this one is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact there is a bunch of stuff I would like to start writing about that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to. Such as book reviews, travel logs and personal updates. The idea of &amp;ldquo;building your own platform&amp;rdquo; was supposed to give the opportunity to do these things and I never took advantage of it when I wanted to. I will be doing so more often starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Path in Life</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from my Computer Science degree program. I did not enjoy my time on this degree as much as I had hoped when I started. Computers were my passion at one point in the past, but not so much any more. I still enjoy using the skills I developed and researching the industry out of curiousity. Ultimately though I pushed through to finish what I started and was glad when it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am a free man and I am going back into academia to study a completely different field that I am actually passionate for: Archaeology and History. Specifically Celtic and Anglo-Saxon history. Which is the field that I have always wanted to study but was misled by well-meaning and sincere concern over &amp;ldquo;employability&amp;rdquo; regarding such a subject. Personally I am not too concerned with the employability of such a degree. Afterall I was led to believe that CompSci would make me a millionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to write about my time on this degree as the subjects themselves are very fascinating but the way that they flow between each other by coincidence is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
