<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Dunkelheit</title>
    <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Dunkelheit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dunkelheit.xyz/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects Update</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/projects-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working on a few project recently and thought I would give an update to what they are and how they are coming along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;migrating-from-vim-to-neovim&#34;&gt;Migrating from Vim to Neovim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty self explanatory, Vim has served me well over the years but having to maintain my config in vimscript and trying to manage packages and plugins for it is too much work for what I get out of it. As such I have chosen to move to Neovim and start using it. My progress with this can be tracked on my dotfiles repo if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-platform-dotfile-management&#34;&gt;Cross platform dotfile management&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use multiple systems for my computing needs, GNU+Linux for my desktops, servers, ThinkPads and MacOS for my Mac. There are differences between these two that require micro-management and changes when deploying dotfiles as such I have chosen to start modelling a new way of managing my dotfiles. For now this is in the planning stages and will be rolled out as I see fit and implement my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-website-design&#34;&gt;New website design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is my little space on the internet where I scream into the void. It&amp;rsquo;s great being able to post and publish things and share them around and get feedback, etc. One of my favourite parts of being in control of this website is that I can post and publish what I would like. However the issue of organising the content on the site has come to my attention recently. The cookbook section should be it&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;website&amp;rdquo; within the same domain for example. Categories and tags should be more distinct, sorting things by year on the index pages doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me either. As such I plan to make a few design changes to the website over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently these are the changes I plan to make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Categorise content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookbook migrated to it&amp;rsquo;s own website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New content types (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimise image usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Social&amp;rdquo; links 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-content&#34;&gt;New content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to expand the content that I write on this site to include things I would like to write about but didn&amp;rsquo;t think would suit the site in its current design. Now that I will be changing the design that excuse is no longer valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New content may include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More blogging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More guides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to reviews, I came to the conclusion that writing about the music I listen to or the video games I play or the books I read could be useful to some people. After all I do seem to be asked quite frequently about what I think about a given product or band, etc. I would also like to review some of the camping gear I have acquired recently as this information is useful in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bots-are-fun&#34;&gt;Bots are fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been developing a bot that I intend to use as a means to bridge various platforms together that I don&amp;rsquo;t have the time or patience to manually keep up to date with. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be great, it is a personal project intended to teach me how to interact with APIs and other tool sets. But it is a fun little project so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brewing&#34;&gt;Brewing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making my own wine, beer and cider has been a great hobby so far and I having been gaining a lot more experience with it. Learning the various ways that different ingredients interact, which yeast to use, how long to do things for and why. It is a great hobby and doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a lot of time to do. Although the learning curve can be somewhat of an issue depending on what you plan to do. I plan to write about my experiences with brewing alcohol at some point but for now I just wanted to update that is an ongoing hobby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;power-lifting&#34;&gt;Power lifting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have returned to the gym and have taken up a power lifting programming again. I have always enjoyed this sport and intend to last a lot longer at it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about everything. Thanks for reading and if you are interested in anything I have mentioned feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dunkelheit.xyz/contact&#34;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Still Sucks</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/twitter-still-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/twitter-still-sucks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently made a new Twitter account to follow some accounts while my usual manner of reading them via RSS feeds (thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://nitter.net&#34;&gt;Nitter&lt;/a&gt;) were unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprising no one, the website still sucks and has all the problems that it had before except now you can pay for a dunce cap on your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a waste of time that was!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blog Without Blogging</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-blog-without-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started this blog it was purely as an exercise in staking my e-claim on my e-land as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=3dIVesHEAzc&#34;&gt;meme at the time&lt;/a&gt; suggested. It was a fun exercise that let me refresh my knowledge of HTML and CSS and it led me to learn Hugo too and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting to this site whenever I feel like something I&amp;rsquo;ve written is worth posting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t do much blogging, in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve done basically none at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to change that. The idea of writing a blog is appealing I&amp;rsquo;ve just never felt like I had anything interesting going on. I blame doing a CompSci degree for this though. Now that I am doing a degree that I actually want to do I have probably too much that I want to write down about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When last semester ended I planned to blog about my experience, what I thought of the various classes, the campus, the environment of the university in general but I never got around to it. So I will cover both semesters at the same time when this one is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact there is a bunch of stuff I would like to start writing about that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the time to. Such as book reviews, travel logs and personal updates. The idea of &amp;ldquo;building your own platform&amp;rdquo; was supposed to give the opportunity to do these things and I never took advantage of it when I wanted to. I will be doing so more often starting now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Path in Life</title>
      <link>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dunkelheit.xyz/blog/a-new-path-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently graduated from my Computer Science degree program. I did not enjoy my time on this degree as much as I had hoped when I started. Computers were my passion at one point in the past, but not so much any more. I still enjoy using the skills I developed and researching the industry out of curiousity. Ultimately though I pushed through to finish what I started and was glad when it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I am a free man and I am going back into academia to study a completely different field that I am actually passionate for: Archaeology and History. Specifically Celtic and Anglo-Saxon history. Which is the field that I have always wanted to study but was misled by well-meaning and sincere concern over &amp;ldquo;employability&amp;rdquo; regarding such a subject. Personally I am not too concerned with the employability of such a degree. Afterall I was led to believe that CompSci would make me a millionaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to write about my time on this degree as the subjects themselves are very fascinating but the way that they flow between each other by coincidence is very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
